<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/14-7-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_7_3">
        <num>14-7-3</num>
        <content>
          <p>A person or a group of persons licensed to practice a profession in this state may elect to practice as a professional corporation by complying with this chapter, irrespective of any law which, on March 11, 1970, prohibited the practice of the profession by a corporation. The articles of incorporation of a professional corporation shall be filed, and the professional corporation shall be organized, under Chapter 2 of this title; and the professional corporation shall pay the fees and costs prescribed therein. The articles shall state that the purpose of the corporation is to practice the profession named in the articles and that the corporation elects to be governed by this chapter. Any corporation organized under the general corporation laws of this state or any professional association organized under Chapter 10 of this title may elect to be governed by this chapter by amending its articles of association so as to make such election and so as to comply with the other requirements of this chapter and with the laws applicable to corporations generally in this state which are not inconsistent with the express provisions of this chapter. A professional corporation and the shareholders of the corporation in their capacity as shareholders shall enjoy the rights, privileges, and immunities and shall be subject to the obligations and liabilities of other corporations organized for profit under Chapter 2 of this title and those of the shareholders of such corporations, except as changed, restricted, or enlarged by this chapter. Professional associations organized under Chapter 10 of this title are expressly authorized to continue to perform professional services pursuant to that Chapter 10 of this title without electing to comply with this chapter.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1970, p. 243, ยง 3.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
