<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_1_155">
        <num>7-1-155</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any financial institution of whose business or property the department has taken possession as receiver may, at any time within ten days after the department has become receiver, apply to the principal court for an order requiring the department to show cause why it should not be enjoined from continuing as receiver. Service may be made in such action by serving the commissioner personally or by leaving a copy with the deputy in charge of his or her office in the department or by serving the deputy receiver appointed by the department to manage the affairs of such financial institution. The court shall, after a hearing upon the merits, either dismiss the application or order the department to surrender to the financial institution possession of its business and property; but no such injunction shall issue where the department has been appointed receiver by action of a court of competent jurisdiction or by action of the financial institution itself, in accordance with this chapter. Such application for injunction may in the discretion of the court be heard at any time after service as provided in this Code section, with the right by either party to appeal, as in other cases of applications for temporary injunction.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1919, p. 135, art. 7, § 8; Code 1933, § 13-810; Code 1933, § 41A-706, enacted by Ga. L. 1974, p. 705, § 1; Ga. L. 2016, p. 883, § 3-3/HB 927.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
