<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/7-1-795/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_1_795">
        <num>7-1-795</num>
        <content>
          <p>The original record of deposits in savings and loan associations is the record on the books of the association, and the depositor shall be entitled to a savings account book or certificate which is a duplicate of such record. Those dealing with such savings account books and certificates shall be bound by the record on the books of the association. In the event of the loss or destruction of any such savings account book or certificate, any association may, upon receipt of an affidavit of such loss or destruction, issue a duplicate thereof and remain liable only to the holder or holders as shown on the records of the association. The only way an effective transfer or pledge may be accomplished so as to affect the rights of the association is by transfer on the books of the association in the case of transfer or written notice of a pledge entered on the books of the association and acknowledged in writing in the case of a pledge; and the association shall be protected in paying any part of a deposit to the holder thereof as shown on the books of the association unless it has received written notice of a pledge or transfer thereof.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 16-439, enacted by Ga. L. 1952, p. 305, § 4; Code 1933, § 41A-3527, enacted by Ga. L. 1974, p. 705, § 1; Ga. L. 2016, p. 390, § 7-4/HB 811.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
