<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-12-82/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_12_82">
        <num>45-12-82</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Governor, through the Office of Planning and Budget, shall require each budget unit, other than those of the legislative branch and the judicial branch, to file periodic work programs with the Office of Planning and Budget at such time as the Office of Planning and Budget shall direct. As provided in Code Section 45-12-83, no allotment of funds shall be approved for any budget unit until such budget unit has filed a periodic work program with the Office of Planning and Budget and the periodic work program has been approved by the Governor. The work program shall be presented on forms prescribed by the Office of Planning and Budget and shall contain such information as the Governor, through the Office of Planning and Budget, may require.The work program shall include the amount of the portion of the appropriation required for the period's expenditures based on the budget prepared as provided in this part. Periodic work programs may be amended from time to time in such manner as the Office of Planning and Budget may require.A duplicate copy of all of the periodic work programs and any amendments thereto shall be filed simultaneously with the Office of Planning and Budget, the state treasurer, the state auditor, the Senate Budget and Evaluation Office, and the House Budget and Research Office.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 40-414, enacted by Ga. L. 1962, p. 17, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 45; Ga. L. 1993, p. 1402, § 18; Ga. L. 1993, p. 1914, § 8; Ga. L. 2008, p. VO1, § 1-1/HB 529; Ga. L. 2010, p. 863, § 3/SB 296; Ga. L. 2014, p. 866, § 45/SB 340.)</p>
          <p>The 2014 amendment,
      effective April 29, 2014, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "Senate Budget and Evaluation Office, and the House Budget and Research Office" for "Senate Budget Office, and the House Budget Office" in the last sentence.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
