<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-11-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_11_4">
        <num>45-11-4</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Laws 1833, Cobb's 1851 Digest, pp. 644, 809; Code 1863, § 4391; Ga. L. 1865-66, p. 233, § 1; Code 1868, § 4432; Ga. L. 1873, p. 23, § 1; Code 1873, § 4504; Code 1882, § 4504; Ga. L. 1895, p. 63, § 1; Penal Code 1895, §§ 291, 292; Penal Code 1910, §§ 295, 296; Code 1933, §§ 89-9907, 89-9908; Ga. L. 1967, p. 858, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1325, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 884, § 3-33; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 45; Ga. L. 1988, p. 298, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1969, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 487, § 3; Ga. L. 2011, p. 59, § 1-67/HB 415; Ga. L. 2014, p. 866, § 45/SB 340; Ga. L. 2016, p. 186, § 8/HB 941.)</p>
          <p>The 2014 amendment,
      effective April 29, 2014, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "means" for "shall mean" in paragraphs (a)(1), (a)(2), and (a)(3).</p>
          <p>The 2016 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2016, substituted "misdemeanor, and upon" for "misdemeanor and, upon" in subsection (c); deleted former subsection (f), which read: "Any indictment brought pursuant to subsection (b) of this Code section shall specially set forth the merits of the complaint against the accused public officer. A copy of the proposed bill of indictment shall be served on the accused public officer at least 15 days before it is presented to the grand jury."; deleted former subsection (g), which read: "The accused shall have the right to appear before the grand jury to make such sworn statement as he or she shall desire at the conclusion of the presentation of the state's evidence. The accused shall not be subject to examination, either direct or cross, and shall not have the right individually or through his or her counsel to examine the state's witnesses. The accused and his or her counsel shall have the right to be present during the presentation of all evidence and alleged statements of the accused on the proposed indictment, presentment, or accusation, after which the accused and his or her counsel shall retire instanter from the grand jury room to permit the grand jury to deliberate upon the indictment."; deleted former subsection (h), which read: "At any time during the presentation of evidence or during deliberations, the grand jury may amend the indictment or instruct the district attorney to cause a new indictment to be drawn as in any other case. In such case, a copy of the amendment or new indictment, if it relates to the accused public official, shall be provided to the accused public official and his or her counsel."; and deleted former subsection (i), which read: "If a true bill is returned by the grand jury, the indictment shall, as in other cases, be published in open court and shall be placed on the superior court criminal docket of cases to be tried by a trial jury."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
