<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-17-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_17_4">
        <num>45-17-4</num>
        <content>
          <p>Before a certificate shall be issued to a notary public, he or she shall pay to the clerk of the superior court the sum prescribed by Code Section 15-6-77, relating to fees of clerks of the superior courts, from which amount the clerk shall be entitled to cover his or her services in issuing the certificate of appointment as notary public, administering the oath, and recording the same. The amount by which the sum prescribed by Code Section 15-6-77 exceeds the amount which the clerk is required by this Code section to forward to the Georgia Superior Court Clerks' Cooperative Authority is what the clerk shall use to cover his or her services. The clerk shall immediately send a copy of the certificate of appointment, under his or her seal of office, and $2.00 to the Georgia Superior Court Clerks' Cooperative Authority which shall keep a record showing the names of the notaries public appointed with their addresses, signatures, ages, sex, and the terms for which their commissions run; and such amount shall cover the cost of the Georgia Superior Court Clerks' Cooperative Authority in keeping such records. On reappointment as notaries public, the sum prescribed by Code Section 15-6-77 shall be paid to the clerk of the superior court and disbursed in the same manner as the fee for the original appointment is disbursed under this Code section.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1878-79, p. 80, § 1; Code 1882, § 1503a; Civil Code 1895, § 507; Civil Code 1910, § 625; Code 1933, § 71-105; Ga. L. 1947, p. 1108, § 1; Ga. L. 1970, p. 497, § 6; Ga. L. 1971, p. 699, § 4; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1105, § 1; Ga. L. 1997, p. 673, § 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
