<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/45-7-95/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_7_95">
        <num>45-7-95</num>
        <content>
          <p>The commission shall file a written report based upon its studies in which a recommended compensation shall be stated for each constitutional state officer, including members of the General Assembly and all full-time heads of state agencies, authorities, boards, bureaus, commissions, committees, and departments whose compensation is set by the Constitution of Georgia, by law, or by Act of the General Assembly. A copy of such report shall be filed with the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Speaker of the House of Representatives, Clerk of the House of Representatives, Secretary of the Senate, and legislative counsel. The commission shall file the written report at least 90 days prior to the convening of the General Assembly in regular session at which the general appropriations bill is first considered. The written report of the commission shall be filed, notwithstanding a determination by the commission that no compensation increase or decrease is recommended.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1971, p. 103, ยง 6; Ga. L. 2017, p. 579, ยง 3-1/HB 202.)</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective May 9, 2017, deleted the former subsection (a) designation; in the second sentence, substituted "such report" for "said report" near the beginning, inserted "and" preceding "legislative counsel", and deleted ", Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, and Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals" at the end; substituted "90 days" for "30 days" in the third sentence; and deleted former subsection (b), which read: "Whenever a written report of the commission's compensation plan is filed, a bill shall be prepared suitable for introduction in either the Senate or House of Representatives containing the compensation recommended by the commission; and such bill shall be introduced at the next session of the General Assembly convening after the filing of said written report. Such bill and the compensation contained therein, in order to become effective, shall receive the same number of readings and go through and be subject to the same procedure as required by the Constitution of Georgia for any other bill; provided, however, that the bill relative to the commission's compensation plan, whether introduced in the House or the Senate, or both, shall be automatically engrossed by both the House and the Senate, and any such bill shall not be changed in either the House or the Senate after its introduction.".</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
