<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-560/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_2_560">
        <num>20-2-560</num>
        <content>
          <p>The proceeds of bonds shall be used solely for the payment of the cost of the project or combined project and shall be disbursed upon requisition or order of the chairperson of the authority under such restrictions, if any, as the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or the trust indenture mentioned in Code Section 20-2-565 may provide. If the proceeds of such bonds, by error of calculation or otherwise, shall be less than the cost of the project or combined project, unless otherwise provided in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or in the trust indenture, additional bonds may in like manner be issued to provide the amount of such deficit. Unless otherwise provided in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or in the trust indenture, such additional bonds shall be deemed to be of the same issue and shall be entitled to payment from the same fund, without preference or priority, as the bonds first issued for the same purpose. If the proceeds of the bonds of any issue shall exceed the amount required for the purpose for which such bonds are issued, the surplus shall be paid into the fund provided in Code Section 20-2-567 for the payment of principal and interest, if any, of such bonds.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1951, p. 241, ยง 10; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1001, ยง 7/HB 936.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
