<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-572/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_2_572">
        <num>20-2-572</num>
        <content>
          <p>Bonds of the authority shall be confirmed and validated in accordance with the procedure of Article 3 of Chapter 82 of Title 36. The petition for validation shall make the authority party defendant and shall also make party defendant to such action any political subdivision or county, city, or independent school district or system which has contracted with the authority for the purchase or use of any building, structure, or facility for which bonds have been issued and sought to be validated; and such parties shall be required to show cause, if any, why the contract or contracts and the terms and conditions thereof should not be inquired into by the court, the validity of the terms thereof determined, the matters and conditions imposed on the contracting parties to be performed, and all such undertakings adjudicated as security for the payment of any such bonds of the authority. In the event no appeal is taken or if taken and the judgment is affirmed by the proper appellate court of this state, the judgment of the superior court so confirming and validating the issuance of the bonds shall be forever conclusive upon the validity of the bonds against the authority issuing them and against all parties to such proceedings.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1951, p. 241, ยง 23; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1001, ยง 14/HB 936.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
