<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-2-567/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_2_567">
        <num>20-2-567</num>
        <content>
          <p>The revenues, rents, and earnings derived from any particular project or combined projects; all sums allocated or paid by the State Board of Education or Department of Education to the authority for the benefit of and on behalf of any county, city, or independent school district or system or its governing body for the performance of any lease contract or agreement of sale or any and all funds from any sources received by the various county boards of education, city boards of education, or governing bodies of independent school districts or systems that have entered into lease contracts or agreements of sale with the authority and paid to it in the performance of such contract or contracts; any and all revenues, rents, and earnings received by the authority, regardless of whether or not such rents, earnings, and revenues were produced by a particular project for which bonds have been issued, unless otherwise pledged and allocated; and federal funds where applicable may be pledged and allocated by the authority to the payment of the principal and interest, if any, on revenue bonds of the authority as the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds or the trust instrument may provide. Such funds so pledged from whatever source received may include funds received from one or more or all sources and shall be set aside at regular intervals as may be provided in the resolution or trust indenture, into a sinking fund, which shall be pledged by the authority to and charged with the payment of:</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1951, p. 241, ยง 17; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1001, ยง 9/HB 936.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
