<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/20-3-265/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_3_265">
        <num>20-3-265</num>
        <content>
          <p>The executive director of the commission, or president, if designated by such title by the board of commissioners, shall serve as the executive director, or president, if designated by such title by the board of directors, and chief executive officer of the corporation. The executive director shall provide for maintenance of accurate and permanent minutes and records of all proceedings and activities of the board of directors and the corporation and have authority and responsibility to implement and carry out all administrative powers, duties, and functions of the corporation in accordance with governing state and federal laws and rules, regulations, and policies prescribed by the board of directors. The treasurer of the commission shall serve as treasurer of the corporation. The treasurer shall receive and disburse all funds made available to or for the use of the corporation by the General Assembly or otherwise in accordance with law and as may be directed by the board of directors. The secretary of the commission shall serve as secretary of the corporation. Other officers of the commission who are assigned duties and responsibilities relative to the purposes of the corporation may be designated as officers of the corporation. The foregoing officers and all other employees, professional personnel, agents, experts, consultants, and persons employed or retained by the commission who are assigned duties and responsibilities relative to the purposes of the corporation shall perform such assigned duties and responsibilities in accordance with the federal act and this part. Fidelity bond coverage of officers, employees, and members of the commission provided pursuant to paragraph (4) of Code Section 20-3-235 and covering such persons who are performing duties and responsibilities relative to the corporation pursuant to this part shall also be conditioned as to the insured and in such respects and for such sums as the board of directors determines necessary to protect the interests of the corporation.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 32-3306, enacted by Ga. L. 1980, p. 835, ยง 2; Ga. L. 2003, p. 158, ยง 3.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
