<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-4-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_4_8">
        <num>52-4-8</num>
        <content>
          <p>All companies incorporated under this chapter shall have power to bring or be the subject of actions; make contracts; lease, purchase, hold, and sell such property, real and personal, as may be necessary for the purposes of the corporation; and construct and maintain a canal and branch canals, dams, races, weirs, aqueducts, reservoirs, towpaths, and all other appliances necessary to divert, take, or use the waters of any stream or body of water. However, the canal companies shall not, by building any dam in or across or by diverting water from any navigable stream, destroy or obstruct the navigation of such stream. Such fishways shall be placed in any dams at the time of the construction of the dam as the commissioner of natural resources shall direct. Fishways shall be kept in good order and repair by the canal company, and the company shall notify the commissioner of natural resources of the proposed construction of any dam. Further, the canal companies shall pay reasonable compensation to such landholders as may have riparian rights in any stream or body of water taken, diverted, or obstructed for such taking, diversion, or obstruction or for any damage done them. The canal companies may also enter upon, take, and appropriate any lands and tenements necessary and appropriate for the purposes of the corporation upon first paying reasonable compensation therefor. No company incorporated as provided in this chapter shall have power to construct or use any canal within the corporate limits of any incorporated municipality without first obtaining the consent of the proper corporate authorities of such municipality.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1893, p. 81, ยง 3; Civil Code 1895, ยง 1989; Civil Code 1910, ยง 2370; Code 1933, ยง 17-106.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
