<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/52-6-38/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_6_38">
        <num>52-6-38</num>
        <content>
          <p>All matters concerning the assessment of fines or penalties against pilots or other persons, the suspension or revocation of pilot licenses, and any other matter relating to the use, business, or care of a pilot in any of the harbors shall be heard and determined by the commissioners, or a majority of them, appointed for the care of the pilotage where the violation, damage, or dispute may arise, upon reasonable notice to the pilot, pilots, or other persons concerned and an opportunity for the pilot, pilots, or other persons to be heard. The commissioners are authorized by their decree or order to decide and regulate every such matter, to assess fines and penalties, and to suspend or revoke licenses. They shall have the power to enforce the decree or order by execution or warrant of distress, under their hands and seals or under the hands and seals of any three of them, directed to any sheriff or constable of the county where the execution issues and commanding the sale of the offender's goods, or so much of them as may be necessary to satisfy the execution or warrant. All sales thereunder shall be made in conformity with the laws of the state in relating to sheriffs' sales. The sheriff and constable shall be liable to be ruled before the judge of the superior court as in other cases for default in duly executing such process.</p>
          <p>(Laws 1799, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 34; Code 1863, § 1472; Code 1868, § 1529; Code 1873, § 1523; Code 1882, § 1523; Civil Code 1895, § 1671; Civil Code 1910, § 1917; Code 1933, § 80-314; Ga. L. 1945, p. 279, § 15; Ga. L. 1995, p. 846, § 6.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
