<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act>
    <meta>
      <identification source="#cosilico">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-12-01" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1/eng@2018-12-01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1/eng@2018-12-01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-12-01" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1/eng@2018-12-01/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-1/eng@2018-12-01/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <publication date="2018-12-01" name="Official Code of Georgia Annotated" showAs="OCGA"/>
      <references>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_1-1">
        <num>Chapter 1</num>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-1">
          <num>1-1-1</num>
          <heading>Enactment of Code</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-1. Enactment of Code
The statutory portion of the codification of Georgia laws prepared by the Code Revision Commission and the Michie Company pursuant to a contract entered into on June 19, 1978, is enacted and shall have the effect of statutes enacted by the General Assembly of Georgia. The statutory portion of such codification shall be merged with annotations, captions, catchlines, history lines, editorial notes, cross-references, indices, title and chapter analyses, and other materials pursuant to the contract and shall be published by authority of the state pursuant to such contract and when so published shall be known and may be cited as the "Official Code of Georgia Annotated."

History Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-2">
          <num>1-1-2</num>
          <heading>Legislative intent</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-2. Legislative intent

The enactment of this Code is intended as a recodification, revision, modernization, and reenactment of the general laws of the State of Georgia which are currently of force and is intended, where possible, to resolve conflicts which exist in the law and to repeal those laws which are obsolete as a result of the passage of time or other causes, which have been declared unconstitutional or invalid, or which have been superseded by the enactment of later laws. Except as otherwise specifically provided by particular provisions of this Code, the enactment of this Code by the General Assembly is not intended to alter the substantive law in existence on the effective date of this Code.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-3">
          <num>1-1-3</num>
          <heading>Severability</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-3. Severability

Except as otherwise specifically provided in this Code or in an Act or resolution of the General Assembly, in the event any title, chapter, article, part, subpart, Code section, subsection, paragraph, subparagraph, item, sentence, clause, phrase, or word of this Code or of any Act or resolution of the General Assembly is declared or adjudged to be invalid or unconstitutional, such declaration or adjudication shall not affect the remaining portions of this Code or of such Act or resolution, which shall remain of full force and effect as if such portion so declared or adjudged invalid or unconstitutional were not originally a part of this Code or of such Act or resolution. The General Assembly declares that it would have enacted the remaining parts of this Code if it had known that such portion hereof would be declared or adjudged invalid or unconstitutional. The General Assembly further declares that it would have enacted the remaining parts of any other Act or resolution if it had known that such portion thereof would be declared or adjudged invalid or unconstitutional unless such Act or resolution contains an express provision to the contrary.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-4">
          <num>1-1-4</num>
          <heading>Validating Acts</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-4. Validating Acts

The omission from this Code of any Acts passed prior to the adoption of this Code which validated any bonds, notes, warrants, certificates, or other evidences of indebtedness issued by any political subdivision or instrumentality of the state shall in no way operate or be construed to repeal or destroy the effect of any and all of such validating Acts where such validating Acts have been otherwise lawfully passed and are not in conflict with the Constitution of the United States or the Constitution of Georgia.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-5">
          <num>1-1-5</num>
          <heading>Effect of adoption of Code upon rules or regulations</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-5. Effect of adoption of Code upon rules or regulations

Unless otherwise provided, the adoption of this Code shall not invalidate or affect any rules or regulations which were in effect on November 1, 1982, promulgated pursuant to authority given by law, and such rules and regulations shall remain in force until repealed, replaced, or invalidated.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-6">
          <num>1-1-6</num>
          <heading>Effect of adoption of Code upon terms of office and rights of officials or employees</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-1-6. Effect of adoption of Code upon terms of office and rights of officials or employees</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-6__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The adoption of this Code shall not affect the term of office or the right to hold office of any person who is in office on November 1, 1982, unless otherwise expressly provided or unless such office is abolished by the adoption of this Code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-6__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The adoption of this Code shall not affect the compensation, expenses, per diem, allowances, retirement, or other rights of any official or employee of the state or any county, municipal corporation, school system, political subdivision, authority, or other governmental entity within this state, unless otherwise provided in this Code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-7">
          <num>1-1-7</num>
          <heading>Notes and catchlines of Code sections not part of law</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-7. Notes and catchlines of Code sections not part of law
Unless otherwise provided in this Code, the descriptive headings or catchlines immediately preceding or within the text of the individual Code sections of this Code, except the Code section numbers included in the headings or catchlines immediately preceding the text of the Code sections, and title and chapter analyses do not constitute part of the law and shall in no manner limit or expand the construction of any Code section. All historical citations, title and chapter analyses, and notes set out in this Code are given for the purpose of convenient reference and do not constitute part of the law.

History Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-8">
          <num>1-1-8</num>
          <heading>References to state law or this Code</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-1-8. References to state law or this Code</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-8__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless otherwise indicated in the context, references in this Code to titles, chapters, articles, parts, subparts, or Code sections shall mean titles, chapters, articles, parts, subparts, or Code sections of this Code.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-8__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless there is an expressed intention to the contrary, any reference in this Code or in any law of this state to another provision of this Code or law of this state shall mean and be construed to refer to such other provision or law as it now or hereafter exists.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-8__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any reference in any local or special law of this state to any Act or resolution of the General Assembly or to any title, chapter, section, or other portion of any prior code of this state shall be construed to be a reference to the appropriate title, chapter, article, part, subpart, Code section, subsection, paragraph, subparagraph, division, or subdivision of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-8__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless otherwise indicated by the context in which it is used, any citation in any public or private document, writing, or other instrument to a law of the State of Georgia which has been codified in the Official Code of Georgia Annotated shall be construed to be a reference to such law as contained in the Official Code of Georgia Annotated.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-8__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any reference in any Act of the General Assembly or in any other public or private document, writing, or other instrument to "O.C.G.A." shall mean and refer to the Official Code of Georgia Annotated published under authority of the State of Georgia. The Official Code of Georgia Annotated published under authority of the State of Georgia may be cited or referred to as "O.C.G.A."

History Ga. L. 1981, Ex. Sess., p. 8, § 6; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 2.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1981, Ex. Sess., p. 8, § 6; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 2.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-9">
          <num>1-1-9</num>
          <heading>Effective date of Code</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-9. Effective date of Code

This Code shall become effective on November 1, 1982.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-10">
          <num>1-1-10</num>
          <heading>Specific repealer; provisions saved from repeal</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-1-10. Specific repealer; provisions saved from repeal</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following Codes, laws, and parts of laws are repealed, except as otherwise provided in this Code section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Code of Georgia of 1933, as amended;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All general laws enacted by the General Assembly of Georgia prior to June 1, 1981, except this Code and except as otherwise provided in this Code section; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All codes enacted or approved by the General Assembly prior to the Code of Georgia of 1933.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following laws and parts of laws are not repealed by the adoption of this Code and shall remain of full force and effect until otherwise repealed, amended, superseded, or declared invalid or unconstitutional:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions conveying, granting, leasing, encumbering, selling, exchanging, or authorizing easements in specific state-owned property or rights therein;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions providing for appropriations of state funds;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions granting compensation to persons, firms, partnerships, corporations, and private or governmental entities injured by the state or its officials, officers, employees, or agents;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Local Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly which are in effect on November 1, 1982, and which are not in conflict with this Code;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions which by their terms are applicable to a named superior court or judicial circuit, including but not limited to Acts fixing the terms of court and Acts providing for judges, district attorneys, or other personnel or their compensation, powers, or duties;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resolutions proposing amendments to the Constitution or proposing a new Constitution or portions thereof;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions ceding jurisdiction over territory within the state to the federal government;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions creating committees or commissions of the General Assembly or authorizing studies;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions providing for the furnishing of law books to various courts, governmental entities, libraries, and public officials;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions designating or naming highways, bridges, buildings, ferries, dams, structures, parks, natural resources, or other property or authorizing the placement of statues, plaques, memorials, portraits, or monuments;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_11">
              <num>(11)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resolutions relating to or providing for the internal operation of the General Assembly;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_12">
              <num>(12)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resolutions not intended to have the force and effect of law;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>General Acts of local application which are based on population and which have not been specifically repealed or declared invalid or unconstitutional;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_14">
              <num>(14)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions honoring, commending, or recognizing individuals, groups, principles, or ideas or urging that certain acts be done or refrained from by the federal, state, or local governments or by individuals, groups, or entities; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_b__para_15">
              <num>(15)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts and resolutions relieving sureties or bondsmen.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following specific laws and parts of laws are not repealed by the adoption of this Code and shall remain of full force and effect, pursuant to their terms, until otherwise repealed, amended, superseded, or declared invalid or unconstitutional:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act for reviving and enforcing certain laws therein mentioned and adopting the common laws of England as they existed on May 14, 1776, approved February 25, 1784. (For the adopting Act of 1784, see Prince's 1822 Digest, p. 570; Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 721; and Code of 1863, Section 1, paragraph 6.)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 10 of an Act amending an Act prohibiting certain practices in connection with real estate transactions, approved March 24, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 480).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 13 of an Act known as the "Georgia Marketing Act of 1981," approved April 13, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1354).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 1 and 67 of an Act to revise, modernize, codify, and update certain laws relating to alcoholic beverages, approved April 13, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1269).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 4 of an Act amending an Act known as the "Insurance Premium Finance Company Act," approved April 7, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 760).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 5 and 6 of an Act amending Code Title 56, known as the "Georgia Insurance Code," so as to provide additional qualifications for licensure of agents and counselors for life or accident and sickness insurance and for the making of annuity contracts, approved April 17, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1789).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 1 of an Act prohibiting discrimination in the employment of the handicapped and known as the "Georgia Equal Employment for the Handicapped Code," approved April 17, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1803).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act amending Code Section 56-3005, relating to optional policy provisions in accident and sickness policies, so as to remove the provisions relating to insurance with other insurers, approved April 9, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1009).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 4 of an Act amending Code Title 114, relating to workers' compensation, so as to redefine the term "employee," approved April 17, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1585).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act amending Code Title 56, known as the "Georgia Insurance Code," so as to require that certain accident and sickness policies and plans provide conversion privileges for insured surviving spouses or former spouses, approved April 7, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 640).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_11">
              <num>(11)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act amending Code Section 3-305, relating to suits against representatives of obligors, so as to reduce the period of exemption from suit for representatives of estates from 12 months to six months, approved April 9, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 852).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_12">
              <num>(12)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act providing that the State of Georgia shall be a party to the "Southern Interstate Nuclear Compact," approved March 3, 1962, (Ga. L. 1962, p. 505), as amended.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A resolution creating the Georgia Semiquincentenary Commission, approved April 14, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1472).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_14">
              <num>(14)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 1 of an Act authorizing the Supreme Court of Georgia to establish a uniform motion for review procedure, approved March 20, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 390).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_15">
              <num>(15)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing for distribution of certain moneys received or to be received as a result of the commission of a crime, approved April 17, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 1262).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_16">
              <num>(16)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 4 of an Act amending certain provisions relating to trial and accusation and waiver of indictment, approved March 20, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 452).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_17">
              <num>(17)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 4 of an Act providing for an additional credit to be given to criminal defendants who are confined in an institution or facility for treatment or examination of a physical or mental disability, approved April 3, 1972 (Ga. L. 1972, p. 742).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_18">
              <num>(18)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 14 and 15 of an Act providing for representation by counsel, services, and facilities for indigent persons in criminal proceedings, approved April 18, 1968 (Ga. L. 1968, p. 999).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_19">
              <num>(19)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 13 of an Act to provide defense services for indigent persons accused of crime, approved March 9, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 367).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_20">
              <num>(20)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A resolution approving the adoption of the rules of the Supreme Court, approved April 14, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1532).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_21">
              <num>(21)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 7 of an Act creating a new judicial circuit for this state to be known as the Douglas Judicial Circuit, approved March 20, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 563).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_22">
              <num>(22)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 38-612 of the Code of 1933, relating to Acts allowing papers improperly registered, and their copies, when lost, to be admitted in evidence.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_23">
              <num>(23)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act providing for the incorporation by reference of various fiduciary powers into wills, trusts, or other instruments in writing and providing that no exercise of any such power or authority by a fiduciary shall deprive the trust or estate involved of an otherwise available tax exemption, approved April 17, 1973 (Ga. L. 1973, p. 846).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_24">
              <num>(24)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act amending an Act providing for the incorporation by reference of various fiduciary powers into wills, trusts, and other instruments in writing, approved April 17, 1973 (Ga. L. 1973, p. 846), and providing that the Act shall not apply to any will, trust, or other instrument executed prior to April 7, 1976, approved April 7, 1976 (Ga. L. 1976, p. 1586).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_25">
              <num>(25)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing that mutual wills, other than mutual wills based on express contract, must contain an express statement that such wills are mutual wills, approved April 18, 1967 (Ga. L. 1967, p. 718).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_26">
              <num>(26)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 4 through 9 of an Act to provide for the number of witnesses required to attest wills and codicils and to provide for the execution and probate of wills and codicils, approved May 28, 1964 (Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 16).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_27">
              <num>(27)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing a residuary bequest or devise to a surviving widow in lieu of dower or years support shall be subject to debts, taxes, expenses of administration and similar charges, approved April 8, 1968 (Ga. L. 1968, p. 1070).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_28">
              <num>(28)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act changing from six months to nine months the time period within which a written instrument of renunciation must be filed, approved April 17, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 1292).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_29">
              <num>(29)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing additional procedures for taking the testimony of witnesses for wills, approved March 24, 1976 (Ga. L. 1976, p. 640).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_30">
              <num>(30)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing how guardians, administrators, executors, trustees, and other fiduciaries may sell stocks or bonds, approved March 2, 1953 (Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 378).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_31">
              <num>(31)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 15 of an Act providing for the supervision by the Attorney General of the administration of charitable trusts, approved March 21, 1974 (Ga. L. 1974, p. 440).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_32">
              <num>(32)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 6 of an Act prescribing procedure for appeals upon petition to the Supreme Court or Court of Appeals in certain specified cases shall not apply to appeals in certain habeas corpus cases, approved April 12, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 619).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_33">
              <num>(33)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 1 of an Act to be known as the "Georgia Public Revenue Code" and revising and modernizing certain revenue laws and to provide legislative intent, approved March 6, 1978 (Ga. L. 1978, p. 309).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_34">
              <num>(34)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 13 of an Act creating the Department of Offender Rehabilitation and the Board of Offender Rehabilitation and abolishing the State Board of Probation, approved April 6, 1972 (Ga. L. 1972, p. 1069).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_35">
              <num>(35)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act prohibiting any interference with the printing of the reports of the Supreme Court and the Court of Appeals, approved March 29, 1937 (Ga. L. 1937, p. 503).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_36">
              <num>(36)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 7 of an Act providing that the powers and duties of the Department of Administrative Services relative to contracts for supplies and services required by the state shall not be construed to affect, repeal, or limit an Act known as the "Unemployment Compensation Law," approved April 12, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 659).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_37">
              <num>(37)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing that the provisions regarding membership of certain metropolitan area planning and development commissions shall not be changed, approved April 6, 1978 (Ga. L. 1978, p. 2066).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_38">
              <num>(38)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing that certain additional authority granted to each area planning and development commission and the expiration of such authority shall not repeal, limit, or diminish any power heretofore possessed by any metropolitan area planning and development commission, approved March 23, 1977 (Ga. L. 1977, p. 782).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_39">
              <num>(39)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 5 of an Act providing that certain functions and authority granted to area planning and development commissions shall be cumulative of any authority provided to certain metropolitan area planning and development commissions and shall not diminish any authority heretofore granted to any such commission, approved April 11, 1978 (Ga. L. 1978, p. 2293).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_40">
              <num>(40)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act reestablishing the Georgia Council for the Arts and Humanities, approved March 13, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 388).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_41">
              <num>(41)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 9 of an Act substantially amending the duties, responsibilities and procedures of the Public Service Commission, approved April 14, 1975 (Ga. L. 1975, p. 404).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_42">
              <num>(42)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 7 of an Act amending the powers and duties of the State Depository Board and the regulation of deposits therein, approved March 23, 1960 (Ga. L. 1960, p. 1144).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_43">
              <num>(43)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 11 of the "Telecommunications Consolidation Act of 1973," approved April 18, 1973 (Ga. L. 1973, p. 1261).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_44">
              <num>(44)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 9 of the "Public Safety Radio Services Act of 1975," approved April 28, 1975 (Ga. L. 1975, p. 1642).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_45">
              <num>(45)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act amending an Act implementing the requirements of the Federal Intergovernmental Cooperation Act of 1968, approved March 20, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 736).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_46">
              <num>(46)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act providing that powers of sale and other powers in deeds of trust, mortgages, and other instruments may be exercised by transferees and other parties regardless of whether or not the transfer specifically includes such powers or conveys title to the property described, approved April 18, 1967 (Ga. L. 1967, p. 735).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_47">
              <num>(47)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 4 of an Act providing that a power of sale, unless limited in the instrument creating such power, authorizes a private sale by the donee of such power, except as to instruments given to secure a debt, approved March 4, 1955 (Ga. L. 1955, p. 430).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_48">
              <num>(48)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act requiring the conditional sales of personal property to be evidenced in writing, approved September 27, 1881 (Ga. L. 1880-81, p. 143), as amended.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_49">
              <num>(49)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to provide that the lien of mortgages on crops given to secure the payment of debts for supplies, money, and other articles of necessity shall be superior to judgments of older date than the mortgages, approved December 21, 1899 (Ga. L. 1899, p. 78).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_50">
              <num>(50)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to extend the lien of mortgages on crops, before the crops are planted or growing, approved July 15, 1924 (Ga. L. 1924, p. 125).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_51">
              <num>(51)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 2 and 3 of an Act declaring that growing crops shall be personalty and providing that mortgages or other liens thereof shall be attested and recorded as chattel mortgages, approved August 21, 1922 (Ga. L. 1922, p. 114).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_52">
              <num>(52)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act authorizing the securing of advances made for the purpose of planting, making, or gathering crops by giving a bill of sale, approved August 22, 1925 (Ga. L. 1925, p. 118), as amended.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_53">
              <num>(53)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act declaring the selling or encumbering of personal property held under a conditional purchase to be illegal, approved September 28, 1883 (Ga. L. 1882-83, p. 111).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_54">
              <num>(54)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to prevent the removal of personal property from this state held under a conditional purchase and sale, and by the terms of the purchase, the title is retained by the vendor until the purchase price is paid, without the consent of the vendor, and to prevent the vendee in such a purchase and sale from concealing the property, approved August 15, 1910 (Ga. L. 1910, p. 120).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_55">
              <num>(55)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to be known as the "Apartment Ownership Act," approved April 12, 1963 (Ga. L. 1963, p. 561), as amended.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_56">
              <num>(56)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to create the positions of associate public service commissioners, approved February 18, 1953 (Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 127).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_57">
              <num>(57)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to declare valid and legal the establishment and organization of housing authorities and all bonds, notes, contracts, agreements, obligations, and undertakings of such authorities, approved March 23, 1939 (Ga. L. 1939, p. 126).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_58">
              <num>(58)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to validate and declare legal all notes and bonds of housing authorities, and all civil proceedings, acts, and things heretofore undertaken, performed, or done with reference thereto, approved March 15, 1971 (Ga. L. 1971, p. 94).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_59">
              <num>(59)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to validate and declare legal the creation and establishment of housing authorities and all bonds, notes, contracts, agreements, obligations, and undertakings of such authorities, approved February 14, 1951 (Ga. L. 1951, p. 127).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_60">
              <num>(60)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to validate and declare legal the creation and establishment of housing authorities and all bonds, notes, contracts, agreements, obligations, and undertakings of such authorities, approved March 10, 1959 (Ga. L. 1959, p. 141).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_61">
              <num>(61)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to validate and declare legal the creation and establishment of housing authorities and all bonds, contracts, agreements, notes, obligations, and undertakings of such authorities, approved March 9, 1962 (Ga. L. 1962, p. 734).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_62">
              <num>(62)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 1 of an Act to provide for the number of directors of railroad corporations, and to provide for the ratification of prior actions of boards of directors thereof, approved April 23, 1969 (Ga. L. 1969, p. 589).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_63">
              <num>(63)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to provide that the seal of a notary need not be required to his attestation of deeds and to provide for the ratification of certain deeds, approved February 12, 1952 (Ga. L. 1952, p. 456).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_64">
              <num>(64)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to create certain emeritus offices of the state, to provide for appointment, compensation, and duties, as amended, approved March 7, 1957 (Ga. L. 1957, p. 206).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_65">
              <num>(65)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A resolution giving assent of this state to an act of Congress of the United States providing for cooperative agricultural extension work, approved August 14, 1914 (Ga. L. 1914, p. 1243).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_66">
              <num>(66)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to enlarge the powers of the Board of Trustees of Georgia Military College, approved March 24, 1939 (Ga. L. 1939, p. 410).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_67">
              <num>(67)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act to authorize the Toccoa Falls Institute to confer the degree of bachelor of arts in biblical education, approved March 24, 1939 (Ga. L. 1939, p. 412).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_68">
              <num>(68)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act designating Fort Valley State College as a land-grant college, approved February 25, 1949 (Ga. L. 1949, p. 1144).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_69">
              <num>(69)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act known as the "Georgia Professional Standards Act," approved March 25, 1976 (Ga. L. 1976, p. 966).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_70">
              <num>(70)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act known as the "State School Building Authority for the Deaf and Blind Act," approved February 21, 1951 (Ga. L. 1951, p. 637).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_71">
              <num>(71)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An Act known as the "Vocational Trade School Building Authority Act," approved February 16, 1951 (Ga. L. 1951, p. 132).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_72">
              <num>(72)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 2 of an Act to amend Code Title 49, relating to guardians and wards, as amended, so as to enact Chapter 9 of Title 49 and to provide that a guardian need not be appointed for a minor or an incompetent person in certain instances, approved April 18, 1967 (Ga. L. 1967, p. 720).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_73">
              <num>(73)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act to amend Code Title 49, relating to guardians and wards, as amended, so as to revise, modernize, and supersede Code Chapter 49-6, relating to guardians of insane persons or persons otherwise mentally incapable of managing their estates, approved April 8, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 1661).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_74">
              <num>(74)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 5 of an Act substantially revising the law relating to the joint-secretary of the state examining boards, as amended, in particular to provide an exception, approved April 22, 1981 (Ga. L. 1981, p. 1898).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_75">
              <num>(75)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 3 of an Act to amend Code Title 74, relating to parent and child, as amended, by enacting a new Code chapter relating to determination of paternity, approved April 1, 1980 (Ga. L. 1980, p. 1374).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_76">
              <num>(76)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Section 7 of the "Georgia Child Custody Intrastate Jurisdiction Act of 1978," approved April 5, 1978 (Ga. L. 1978, p. 1957).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_77">
              <num>(77)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 1 and 49 of an Act substantially revising and modernizing certain laws of this state relating to family, domestic relations, and interfamilial duties, approved April 4, 1979 (Ga. L. 1979, p. 466).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-1-10__subsec_c__para_78">
              <num>(78)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sections 29 and 30 of the "Uniform Reciprocal Enforcement of Support Act," approved February 20, 1958 (Ga. L. 1958, p. 34).

History Code 1981, § 1-1-10; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 1.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-1-10; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-1-11">
          <num>1-1-11</num>
          <heading>General repealer</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-1-11. General repealer

All laws and parts of laws in conflict with this Code are repealed.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_1-2">
        <num>Chapter 2</num>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-1">
          <num>1-2-1</num>
          <heading>Classes of persons generally; corporations deemed artificial persons; nature of corporations generally</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-2-1. Classes of persons generally; corporations deemed artificial persons; nature of corporations generally</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There are two classes of persons: natural and artificial.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Corporations are artificial persons. They are creatures of the law and, except insofar as the law forbids it, they are subject to be changed, modified, or destroyed at the will of their creator.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 1582; Code 1868, § 1645; Code 1873, § 1651; Code 1882, § 1651; Civil Code 1895, § 1802; Civil Code 1910, § 2159; Code 1933, § 79-101.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 1582; Code 1868, § 1645; Code 1873, § 1651; Code 1882, § 1651; Civil Code 1895, § 1802; Civil Code 1910, § 2159; Code 1933, § 79-101.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-2">
          <num>1-2-2</num>
          <heading>Categories of natural persons</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-2. Categories of natural personsNatural persons are categorized, according to their rights and status, as:
(1)  Citizens;

(2)  Citizens of the United States but not of this state; and

(3)  Aliens.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 1583; Code 1868, § 1646; Code 1873, § 1652; Code 1882, § 1652; Civil Code 1895, § 1803; Civil Code 1910, § 2160; Code 1933, § 79-102.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 1583; Code 1868, § 1646; Code 1873, § 1652; Code 1882, § 1652; Civil Code 1895, § 1803; Civil Code 1910, § 2160; Code 1933, § 79-102.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-3">
          <num>1-2-3</num>
          <heading>Duration of citizenship</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-3. Duration of citizenship
Until citizenship is acquired elsewhere, a citizen of this state continues to be a citizen of this state and of the United States.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 54; Code 1868, § 50; Code 1873, § 47; Code 1882, § 47; Civil Code 1895, § 1806; Civil Code 1910, § 2163; Code 1933, § 79-202.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 54; Code 1868, § 50; Code 1873, § 47; Code 1882, § 47; Civil Code 1895, § 1806; Civil Code 1910, § 2163; Code 1933, § 79-202.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-4">
          <num>1-2-4</num>
          <heading>Right of expatriation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-4. Right of expatriation
Except in time of war, every citizen of this state shall have the right of expatriation with a view to becoming a citizen of another country with which this state is at peace. Declaration or avowal of the intention to become a citizen of another country, accompanied by actual removal, shall be held to be a renunciation of all one's rights and duties as a citizen.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 53; Code 1868, § 49; Code 1873, § 46; Code 1882, § 46; Civil Code 1895, § 1805; Civil Code 1910, § 2162; Code 1933, § 79-203.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 53; Code 1868, § 49; Code 1873, § 46; Code 1882, § 46; Civil Code 1895, § 1805; Civil Code 1910, § 2162; Code 1933, § 79-203.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-5">
          <num>1-2-5</num>
          <heading>Reacquisition of citizenship by expatriated persons and descendants</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-5. Reacquisition of citizenship by expatriated persons and descendants
If a person expatriated under Code Section 1-2-4 acquires citizenship under some foreign power, he and his descendants who go with him for the purpose of residence may become citizens of this state again only after meeting the residence requirements and taking the oath of allegiance required of other foreigners as a condition to becoming a citizen of the United States by Section 1448 of Title 8 of the United States Code.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 55; Code 1868, § 51; Code 1873, § 48; Code 1882, § 48; Civil Code 1895, § 1807; Civil Code 1910, § 2164; Code 1933, § 79-204.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 55; Code 1868, § 51; Code 1873, § 48; Code 1882, § 48; Civil Code 1895, § 1807; Civil Code 1910, § 2164; Code 1933, § 79-204.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-6">
          <num>1-2-6</num>
          <heading>Rights of citizens generally</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-2-6. Rights of citizens generally</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The rights of citizens include, without limitation, the following:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right of personal security;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right of personal liberty;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right of private property and the disposition thereof;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right of the elective franchise;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to hold office, unless disqualified by the Constitution and laws of this state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to appeal to the courts;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to testify as a witness;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to perform any civil function; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_a__para_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The right to keep and bear arms.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-6__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All citizens are entitled to exercise all their rights as citizens, unless specially prohibited by law.

History Orig. Code 1863, §§ 1585, 1586; Code 1868, §§ 1648, 1649; Code 1873, §§ 1654, 1655; Code 1882, §§ 1654, 1655; Civil Code 1895, §§ 1808, 1809; Civil Code 1910, §§ 2165, 2166; Code 1933, §§ 79-205, 79-206.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, §§ 1585, 1586; Code 1868, §§ 1648, 1649; Code 1873, §§ 1654, 1655; Code 1882, §§ 1654, 1655; Civil Code 1895, §§ 1808, 1809; Civil Code 1910, §§ 2165, 2166; Code 1933, §§ 79-205, 79-206.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-7">
          <num>1-2-7</num>
          <heading>Rights of female citizens generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-7. Rights of female citizens generally
Female citizens are entitled to the privilege of the elective franchise and have the right to hold any civil office or perform any civil function as fully and completely as do male citizens.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 1587; Code 1868, § 1650; Code 1873, § 1656; Code 1882, § 1656; Civil Code 1895, § 1810; Ga. L. 1896, p. 40, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 2167; Ga. L. 1912, p. 62, § 1; Ga. L. 1916, p. 43, § 1; Ga. L. 1918, p. 118, § 1; Ga. L. 1921, p. 106, §§ 1, 2; Code 1933, § 79-207; Ga. L. 1975, p. 779, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 826, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 1587; Code 1868, § 1650; Code 1873, § 1656; Code 1882, § 1656; Civil Code 1895, § 1810; Ga. L. 1896, p. 40, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 2167; Ga. L. 1912, p. 62, § 1; Ga. L. 1916, p. 43, § 1; Ga. L. 1918, p. 118, § 1; Ga. L. 1921, p. 106, §§ 1, 2; Code 1933, § 79-207; Ga. L. 1975, p. 779, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 826, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-8">
          <num>1-2-8</num>
          <heading>Rights of minors</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-8. Rights of minors
The law prescribes certain ages at which persons shall be considered of sufficient maturity to discharge certain civil functions, to make contracts, and to dispose of property. Prior to those ages they are minors and are, on account of that disability, unable to exercise these rights as citizens unless such minor becomes emancipated by operation of law or pursuant to Article 10 of Chapter 11 of Title 15.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 1588; Code 1868, § 1651; Code 1873, § 1657; Code 1882, § 1657; Civil Code 1895, § 1811; Civil Code 1910, § 2168; Code 1933, § 79-208; Ga. L. 2006, p. 141, § 2/HB 847; Ga. L. 2013, p. 294, § 4-1/HB 242.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 1588; Code 1868, § 1651; Code 1873, § 1657; Code 1882, § 1657; Civil Code 1895, § 1811; Civil Code 1910, § 2168; Code 1933, § 79-208; Ga. L. 2006, p. 141, § 2/HB 847; Ga. L. 2013, p. 294, § 4-1/HB 242.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-9">
          <num>1-2-9</num>
          <heading>Rights of citizens of the United States while in this state generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-9. Rights of citizens of the United States while in this state generally
Such citizens of the other states of the Union as are recognized as citizens of the United States by the Constitution thereof shall be entitled, while temporarily within this state, to all the rights of citizens thereof, except the elective franchise, the right to hold office, and the right to perform such civil functions as are confined by law to citizens of this state.

History Laws 1785, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 364; Code 1863, § 1591; Code 1868, § 1654; Code 1873, § 1659; Code 1882, § 1659; Civil Code 1895, § 1813; Civil Code 1910, § 2170; Code 1933, § 79-301.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1785, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 364; Code 1863, § 1591; Code 1868, § 1654; Code 1873, § 1659; Code 1882, § 1659; Civil Code 1895, § 1813; Civil Code 1910, § 2170; Code 1933, § 79-301.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-10">
          <num>1-2-10</num>
          <heading>Rights of citizens of other states or nations to sue or give evidence</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-2-10. Rights of citizens of other states or nations to sue or give evidence
The citizens of other states of the United States or of foreign states at peace with this state shall, by comity, be allowed the privilege of suing in the courts of this state and of giving evidence therein, as long as the same comity is extended in the courts of the other states to the citizens of this state.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 1595; Code 1868, § 1657; Code 1873, § 1662; Code 1882, § 1662; Civil Code 1895, § 1817; Civil Code 1910, § 2174; Code 1933, § 79-305.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 1595; Code 1868, § 1657; Code 1873, § 1662; Code 1882, § 1662; Civil Code 1895, § 1817; Civil Code 1910, § 2174; Code 1933, § 79-305.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-2-11">
          <num>1-2-11</num>
          <heading>Rights of aliens generally; purchase, holding, and conveyance of realty</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-2-11. Rights of aliens generally; purchase, holding, and conveyance of realty</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-11__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aliens are the subjects of foreign governments who have not been naturalized under the laws of the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-2-11__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aliens who are subjects of governments at peace with the United States and this state, as long as their governments remain at peace with the United States and this state, shall be entitled to all the rights of citizens of other states who are temporarily in this state and shall have the privilege of purchasing, holding, and conveying real estate in this state.

History Laws 1785, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 364; Laws 1849, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 367; Code 1863, §§ 1592, 1593; Code 1868, §§ 1655, 1656; Code 1873, §§ 1660, 1661; Code 1882, §§ 1660, 1661; Civil Code 1895, §§ 1814, 1816; Civil Code 1910, §§ 2171, 2173; Code 1933, §§ 79-302, 79-303.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1785, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 364; Laws 1849, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 367; Code 1863, §§ 1592, 1593; Code 1868, §§ 1655, 1656; Code 1873, §§ 1660, 1661; Code 1882, §§ 1660, 1661; Civil Code 1895, §§ 1814, 1816; Civil Code 1910, §§ 2171, 2173; Code 1933, §§ 79-302, 79-303.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_1-3">
        <num>Chapter 3</num>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-1">
          <num>1-3-1</num>
          <heading>Construction of statutes generally</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-3-1. Construction of statutes generally</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all interpretations of statutes, the courts shall look diligently for the intention of the General Assembly, keeping in view at all times the old law, the evil, and the remedy. Grammatical errors shall not vitiate a law. A transposition of words and clauses may be resorted to when a sentence or clause is without meaning as it stands.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all interpretations of statutes, the ordinary signification shall be applied to all words, except words of art or words connected with a particular trade or subject matter, which shall have the signification attached to them by experts in such trade or with reference to such subject matter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A substantial compliance with any statutory requirement, especially on the part of public officers, shall be deemed and held sufficient, and no proceeding shall be declared void for want of such compliance, unless expressly so provided by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the rules for construction prescribed in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>through</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, the rules provided in this subsection shall govern the construction of all statutes with respect to the subjects enumerated.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Bonds.  When a bond is required by law, an undertaking in writing, without seal, is sufficient; and in all bonds where the names of the obligors do not appear in the bond but are subscribed thereto, they are bound thereby.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Census.  Whenever there is used in the statutory law of this state the term "federal census," "United States census," "decennial census," or similar words referring to the official census conducted every ten years by the United States of America or any agency thereof as required by Article I, Section II, Paragraph III of the Constitution of the United States, the effective date of such census for the purpose of making operative and of force any statutory law of this state shall be determined as follows:(A)  The effective date of the census shall be July 1 of the first year after the year in which the census is conducted, for the purpose of making operative and of force the following laws:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Code Section 15-16-20;

(ii)  Code Sections 15-6-88 through 15-6-91;

(iii)  Code Section 48-5-183;

(iv)  Code Sections 15-9-63 through 15-9-66;</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v">
            <num>(v)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Code Section 36-5-25;

(vi)  Code Section 15-10-23; and(vii)  Code Section 45-16-11;
provided, however, that if a county's population decreases according to a more recent census below its population according to an earlier census, then, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any officer who is compensated under a law specified in this subparagraph and who is in office on the date specified in this subparagraph shall continue during his entire tenure in such office (including any future terms of office in such office) to be compensated on the basis of the county's population according to such earlier census;

(B)  For purposes of any program of grants of state funds to local governments, the effective date of the census shall be July 1 of the first year after the year in which the census is conducted;

(C)  For the purpose of reconstituting the membership of any constitutional or statutory board, commission, or body whose members are appointed from congressional districts, the effective date of the census shall be January 1 of the third year after the year in which the census is conducted;

(D)  The effective date of the census shall be July 1 of the second year after the year in which the census is conducted for the purpose of making operative and of force all other statutory laws which do not expressly provide otherwise.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Computation of time.  Except as otherwise provided by time period computations specifically applying to other laws, when a period of time measured in days, weeks, months, years, or other measurements of time except hours is prescribed for the exercise of any privilege or the discharge of any duty, the first day shall not be counted but the last day shall be counted; and, if the last day falls on Saturday or Sunday, the party having such privilege or duty shall have through the following Monday to exercise the privilege or to discharge the duty. When the last day prescribed for such action falls on a public and legal holiday as set forth in Code Section 1-4-1, the party having the privilege or duty shall have through the next business day to exercise the privilege or to discharge the duty. When the period of time prescribed is less than seven days, intermediate Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays shall be excluded in the computation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gender.  The masculine gender includes the feminine and the neuter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Joint authority.  A joint authority given to any number of persons or officers may be executed by a majority of them, unless it is otherwise declared.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Number.  The singular or plural number each includes the other, unless the other is expressly excluded.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-1__subsec_v__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Tense.  The present or past tense includes the future.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 5; Code 1868, § 4; Code 1873, § 4; Code 1882, § 4; Civil Code 1895, § 4; Penal Code 1895, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 4; Penal Code 1910, § 1; Code 1933, § 102-102; Ga. L. 1958, p. 388, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 608, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 579, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 951, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 648, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1903, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 902, § 22; Ga. L. 2012, p. 173, § 2-1/HB 665; Ga. L. 2018, p. 356, § 2-1/SB 436.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 5; Code 1868, § 4; Code 1873, § 4; Code 1882, § 4; Civil Code 1895, § 4; Penal Code 1895, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 4; Penal Code 1910, § 1; Code 1933, § 102-102; Ga. L. 1958, p. 388, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 608, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 579, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 951, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 648, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1903, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 902, § 22; Ga. L. 2012, p. 173, § 2-1/HB 665; Ga. L. 2018, p. 356, § 2-1/SB 436.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-2">
          <num>1-3-2</num>
          <heading>Construction of definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-2. Construction of definitions

As used in this Code or in any other law of this state, defined words shall have the meanings specified, unless the context in which the word or term is used clearly requires that a different meaning be used.</p>
          </content>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-3">
          <num>1-3-3</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-3-3. DefinitionsAs used in this Code or in any other law of this state, the term:
(1)  "Abode" ordinarily means domicile.

(2)  "Accident" means an event which takes place without one's foresight or expectation or design.

(3)  "Act of God" means an accident produced by physical causes which are irresistible or inevitable, such as lightning, storms, perils of the sea, earthquakes, inundations, sudden death, or illness. This expression excludes all idea of human agency.

(4)  "Aforesaid" mean</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Code Section 9-10-12.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b__para_20">
              <num>(20)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Trespass" means any misfeasance, transgression, or offense which damages another's health, reputation, or property.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b__para_21">
              <num>(21)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Until," when used with reference to a certain day, includes all of such day.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b__para_22">
              <num>(22)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Whereas" means considering that.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b__para_23">
              <num>(23)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Writing" includes printing and all numerals.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-3__subsec_b__para_24">
              <num>(24)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Year" means a calendar year.

History Laws 1838, Cobb's 1851 Digest, pp. 274, 536; Laws 1833, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 780; Code 1863, § 6; Code 1868, § 5; Code 1873, § 5; Code 1882, § 5; Civil Code 1895, § 5; Penal Code 1895, § 2; Ga. L. 1896, p. 82, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5; Penal Code 1910, § 2; Code 1933, § 102-103; Ga. L. 1957, p. 477, § 6; Ga. L. 1987, p. 1482, § 1; Ga. L. 1991, p. 1849, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2398, § 1; Ga. L. 1995, p. 347, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 362, § 23; Ga. L. 2008, p. 458, § 1/SB 364.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1838, Cobb's 1851 Digest, pp. 274, 536; Laws 1833, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 780; Code 1863, § 6; Code 1868, § 5; Code 1873, § 5; Code 1882, § 5; Civil Code 1895, § 5; Penal Code 1895, § 2; Ga. L. 1896, p. 82, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5; Penal Code 1910, § 2; Code 1933, § 102-103; Ga. L. 1957, p. 477, § 6; Ga. L. 1987, p. 1482, § 1; Ga. L. 1991, p. 1849, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2398, § 1; Ga. L. 1995, p. 347, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 362, § 23; Ga. L. 2008, p. 458, § 1/SB 364.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-4">
          <num>1-3-4</num>
          <heading>Effective date of legislative Acts</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-3-4. Effective date of legislative Acts</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-4__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless a different effective date is specified in an Act:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-4__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any Act which is approved by the Governor or which becomes law without his approval on or after the first day of January and prior to the first day of July of a calendar year shall become effective on the first day of July; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-3-4__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any Act which is approved by the Governor or which becomes law without his approval on or after the first day of July and prior to the first day of January of the immediately succeeding calendar year shall become effective on the first day of January.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-4__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-3-4__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section shall not apply to local legislation or to resolutions intended to have the effect of law. Such local legislation and resolutions intended to have the effect of law become effective immediately upon approval by the Governor or upon their becoming law without his approval, unless a different effective date is specified in the Act or resolution.

History Ga. L. 1968, p. 1364, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 7, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 984, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 985, § 2.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1968, p. 1364, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 7, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 984, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 985, § 2.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-4.1">
          <num>1-3-4.1</num>
          <heading>Effective date for general Acts requiring increases in compensation of certain county officials</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-4.1. Effective date for general Acts requiring increases in compensation of certain county officials
Notwithstanding the provisions of Code Section 1-3-4, no general Act which provides for an increase in compensation to one or more of the county officials listed in Article IX, Section I, Paragraph III of the Constitution or Chapter 10 of Title 15 shall be effective until the first day of January following passage of the Act.

History Code 1981, § 1-3-4.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1985, p. 984, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1397, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 1197, § 1; Ga. L. 1997, p. 11, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 985, § 2; Ga. L. 2003, p. 140, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-3-4.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1985, p. 984, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1397, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 1197, § 1; Ga. L. 1997, p. 11, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 985, § 2; Ga. L. 2003, p. 140, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-5">
          <num>1-3-5</num>
          <heading>Operation of laws generally; retrospective operation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-5. Operation of laws generally; retrospective operation
Laws prescribe only for the future; they cannot impair the obligation of contracts nor, ordinarily, have a retrospective operation. Laws looking only to the remedy or mode of trial may apply to contracts, rights, and offenses entered into, accrued, or committed prior to their passage; but in every case a reasonable time subsequent to the passage of the law should be allowed for the citizen to enforce his contract or to protect his right.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 7; Code 1868, § 6; Code 1873, § 6; Code 1882, § 6; Civil Code 1895, § 6; Penal Code 1895, § 3; Civil Code 1910, § 6; Penal Code 1910, § 3; Code 1933, § 102-104.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 7; Code 1868, § 6; Code 1873, § 6; Code 1882, § 6; Civil Code 1895, § 6; Penal Code 1895, § 3; Civil Code 1910, § 6; Penal Code 1910, § 3; Code 1933, § 102-104.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-6">
          <num>1-3-6</num>
          <heading>When laws become obligatory; effect of ignorance</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-6. When laws become obligatory; effect of ignorance
After they take effect, the laws of this state are obligatory upon all the inhabitants thereof. Ignorance of the law excuses no one.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 8; Code 1868, § 7; Code 1873, § 7; Code 1882, § 7; Civil Code 1895, § 7; Penal Code 1895, § 4; Civil Code 1910, § 7; Penal Code 1910, § 4; Code 1933, § 102-105.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 8; Code 1868, § 7; Code 1873, § 7; Code 1882, § 7; Civil Code 1895, § 7; Penal Code 1895, § 4; Civil Code 1910, § 7; Penal Code 1910, § 4; Code 1933, § 102-105.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-7">
          <num>1-3-7</num>
          <heading>Abrogation of laws by agreement; waiver or renunciation of benefits established by law</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-7. Abrogation of laws by agreement; waiver or renunciation of benefits established by law
Laws made for the preservation of public order or good morals may not be dispensed with or abrogated by any agreement. However, a person may waive or renounce what the law has established in his favor when he does not thereby injure others or affect the public interest.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 11; Code 1868, § 10; Code 1873, § 10; Code 1882, § 10; Civil Code 1895, § 10; Penal Code 1895, § 5; Civil Code 1910, § 10; Penal Code 1910, § 5; Code 1933, § 102-106.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 11; Code 1868, § 10; Code 1873, § 10; Code 1882, § 10; Civil Code 1895, § 10; Penal Code 1895, § 5; Civil Code 1910, § 10; Penal Code 1910, § 5; Code 1933, § 102-106.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-8">
          <num>1-3-8</num>
          <heading>Binding effect of legislation upon state</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-8. Binding effect of legislation upon state
The state is not bound by the passage of a law unless it is named therein or unless the words of the law are so plain, clear, and unmistakable as to leave no doubt as to the intention of the General Assembly.

History Civil Code 1895, § 3; Civil Code 1910, § 3; Code 1933, § 102-109.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Civil Code 1895, § 3; Civil Code 1910, § 3; Code 1933, § 102-109.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-9">
          <num>1-3-9</num>
          <heading>Effect and enforcement of foreign laws</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-9. Effect and enforcement of foreign laws
The laws of other states and foreign nations shall have no force and effect of themselves within this state further than is provided by the Constitution of the United States and is recognized by the comity of states. The courts shall enforce this comity, unless restrained by the General Assembly, so long as its enforcement is not contrary to the policy or prejudicial to the interests of this state.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 10; Code 1868, § 9; Code 1873, § 9; Code 1882, § 9; Civil Code 1895, § 9; Civil Code 1910, § 9; Code 1933, § 102-110.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 10; Code 1868, § 9; Code 1873, § 9; Code 1882, § 9; Civil Code 1895, § 9; Civil Code 1910, § 9; Code 1933, § 102-110.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-10">
          <num>1-3-10</num>
          <heading>Execution of writings and contracts</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-10. Execution of writings and contracts
Except for wills of personalty of persons domiciled in another state or country, when writings or contracts are intended to have effect in this state they must be executed in conformity to the laws of this state.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 9; Code 1868, § 8; Code 1873, § 8; Code 1882, § 8; Civil Code 1895, § 8; Civil Code 1910, § 8; Code 1933, § 102-108; Ga. L. 1962, p. 156, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 188, § 38.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 9; Code 1868, § 8; Code 1873, § 8; Code 1882, § 8; Civil Code 1895, § 8; Civil Code 1910, § 8; Code 1933, § 102-108; Ga. L. 1962, p. 156, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 188, § 38.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-3-11">
          <num>1-3-11</num>
          <heading>Local referenda on abolishing offices or shortening or lengthening term</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-3-11. Local referenda on abolishing offices or shortening or lengthening term
No office to which a person has been elected shall be abolished nor the term of the office shortened or lengthened by local or special Act during the term for which such person was elected unless the same shall be approved by the people of the jurisdiction affected in a referendum on the question.

History Code 1981, § 1-3-11, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 685, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-3-11, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 685, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_1-4">
        <num>Chapter 4</num>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-1">
          <num>1-4-1</num>
          <heading>Public and legal holidays; leave for observance of religious holidays not specifically provided for</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-1. Public and legal holidays; leave for observance of religious holidays not specifically provided for</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State of Georgia shall recognize and observe as public and legal holidays:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All days which have been designated as of January 1, 1984, as public and legal holidays by the federal government; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All other days designated and proclaimed by the Governor as public and legal holidays or as days of fasting and prayer or other religious observance. In such designation, the Governor shall include at least one of the following dates: January 19, April 26, or June 3, or a suitable date in lieu thereof to commemorate the event or events now observed by such dates.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor shall close all state offices and facilities a minimum of 12 days throughout the year and not more than 12 days in observance of the public and legal holidays and other days set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section and shall specify the days state offices and facilities shall be closed for such observances.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Employees of any state department or agency shall, upon request to their appointing authority or his or her designee at least seven days in advance, be given priority consideration for time away from work for observance of religious holy days not otherwise provided for in this Code section. Any paid leave time for such religious holy day observance shall be charged to accrued compensatory leave or accrued annual leave credits available to the employee at the time of the holy day observance. No employee may claim priority consideration for more than three work days each calendar year. A request by an employee for time away from work to observe a religious holy day shall not be denied unless the employee has inadequate accrued compensatory or annual leave credits to cover such period of absence or the duties performed by the employee are urgently required and the employee is the only person available who can perform the duties as determined by the appointing authority or his or her designee. The State Personnel Board shall provide by rule and regulation a procedure to be followed by agencies and departments in the granting of such holy days.

History Laws 1850, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 522; Code 1863, § 2733; Code 1868, § 2741; Ga. L. 1870, p. 69, § 1; Ga. L. 1871-72, p. 23, § 1; Code 1873, § 2783; Ga. L. 1874, p. 19, § 1; Code 1882, § 2783; Ga. L. 1889, p. 72, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1893, p. 115, § 1; Ga. L. 1894, p. 47, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 3692; Ga. L. 1897, p. 119, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 4284; Ga. L. 1929, p. 211, § 1; Code 1933, § 14-1808; Ga. L. 1935, p. 350, § 1; Ga. L. 1943, p. 331, § 1; Ga. L. 1945, p. 123, § 1; Ga. L. 1968, p. 986, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 9, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 363, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 368, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 986, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1274, § 1; Ga. L. 2009, p. 745, § 1/SB 97; Ga. L. 2012, p. 446, § 2-1/HB 642; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 1/HB 737.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1850, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 522; Code 1863, § 2733; Code 1868, § 2741; Ga. L. 1870, p. 69, § 1; Ga. L. 1871-72, p. 23, § 1; Code 1873, § 2783; Ga. L. 1874, p. 19, § 1; Code 1882, § 2783; Ga. L. 1889, p. 72, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1893, p. 115, § 1; Ga. L. 1894, p. 47, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 3692; Ga. L. 1897, p. 119, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 4284; Ga. L. 1929, p. 211, § 1; Code 1933, § 14-1808; Ga. L. 1935, p. 350, § 1; Ga. L. 1943, p. 331, § 1; Ga. L. 1945, p. 123, § 1; Ga. L. 1968, p. 986, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 9, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 363, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 368, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 986, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1274, § 1; Ga. L. 2009, p. 745, § 1/SB 97; Ga. L. 2012, p. 446, § 2-1/HB 642; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 1/HB 737.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-2">
          <num>1-4-2</num>
          <heading>Religious holidays</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-2. Religious holidays
The only days to be declared, treated, and considered as religious holidays shall be the first day of each week, called Sunday.

History Ga. L. 1943, p. 331, § 2.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1943, p. 331, § 2.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-3">
          <num>1-4-3</num>
          <heading>American History Month</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-3. American History Month</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-3__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State of Georgia recognizes the importance to the citizens of this state of the principles upon which the United States of America was founded and of an understanding of the history of our nation. To encourage the study of American history by the citizens of this state, the month of February of each year is designated as "American History Month" in Georgia. The citizens of this state are encouraged to observe "American History Month" with appropriate observances and programs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-3__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The month of February of each year is also designated as Georgia History Month in special tribute to the founders, builders, and preservers of this state.

History Ga. L. 1963, p. 386, § 1; Ga. L. 1974, p. 329, § 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1963, p. 386, § 1; Ga. L. 1974, p. 329, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-4">
          <num>1-4-4</num>
          <heading>Wildflower Week</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-4. Wildflower Week
The fourth week in the month of March of each year is declared to be "Wildflower Week" in Georgia.

History Ga. L. 1981, p. 1849.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1981, p. 1849.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-5">
          <num>1-4-5</num>
          <heading>Bird Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-5. Bird Day
The second Thursday in October of each year is declared to be "Bird Day" in Georgia.

History Ga. L. 1981, p. 1849.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1981, p. 1849.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-6">
          <num>1-4-6</num>
          <heading>Law Enforcement Officer Appreciation Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-6. Law Enforcement Officer Appreciation Day
The second Monday in February of each year is declared to be "Law Enforcement Officer Appreciation Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-6, enacted by Ga. L. 1985, p. 658, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-6, enacted by Ga. L. 1985, p. 658, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-7">
          <num>1-4-7</num>
          <heading>Peace Officer Memorial Day; Police Week</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-7. Peace Officer Memorial Day; Police Week
May 15 of each year is declared to be "Peace Officer Memorial Day" and the calendar week in which it falls is declared as "Police Week."

History Code 1981, § 1-4-7, enacted by Ga. L. 1987, p. 869, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-7, enacted by Ga. L. 1987, p. 869, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-8">
          <num>1-4-8</num>
          <heading>Children's Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-8. Children's Day
The first Sunday in October of each year, beginning in 1990, is declared to be "Children's Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-8, enacted by Ga. L. 1990, p. 175, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-8, enacted by Ga. L. 1990, p. 175, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-9">
          <num>1-4-9</num>
          <heading>Former Prisoners of War Recognition Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-9. Former Prisoners of War Recognition Day
The day of April 9 of each year is designated as "Former Prisoners of War Recognition Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-9, enacted by Ga. L. 1990, p. 1061, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-9, enacted by Ga. L. 1990, p. 1061, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-10">
          <num>1-4-10</num>
          <heading>Girls and Women in Sports Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-10. Girls and Women in Sports Day
The first Thursday in February of each year is designated as "Girls and Women in Sports Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-10, enacted by Ga. L. 1991, p. 788, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-10, enacted by Ga. L. 1991, p. 788, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-11">
          <num>1-4-11</num>
          <heading>Clean Water Week</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-11. Clean Water Week
The third week in October of each year is designated and shall be observed as "Clean Water Week" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-11, enacted by Ga. L. 1994, p. 1403, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-11, enacted by Ga. L. 1994, p. 1403, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-12">
          <num>1-4-12</num>
          <heading>Firefighter Appreciation Day</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-12. Firefighter Appreciation Day
The first Tuesday in February of each year is designated as "Firefighter Appreciation Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-12, enacted by Ga. L. 1996, p. 836, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-12, enacted by Ga. L. 1996, p. 836, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-13">
          <num>1-4-13</num>
          <heading>Bill of Rights Day</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-13. Bill of Rights Day</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-13__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State of Georgia recognizes the first ten amendments to the Constitution of the United States as vitally important in articulating and ensuring fundamental human rights. These first ten amendments, known collectively as the Bill of Rights, were ratified on December 15, 1791.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-13__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To affirm the fundamental freedoms embodied in the Bill of Rights, celebrate the anniversary of ratification, and commemorate the sacrifices made to preserve these essential rights, December 15 of each year is designated "Bill of Rights Day" in Georgia. The citizens of this state are encouraged to observe the day by reflecting upon the meaning and importance of the Bill of Rights.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-13, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 743, § 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-13, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 743, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-14">
          <num>1-4-14</num>
          <heading>Home Education Week</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-14. Home Education Week
The first week in February of each year is declared to be "Home Education Week" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-14, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 1014, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-14, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 1014, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-15">
          <num>1-4-15</num>
          <heading>Designation of "Bill Elliott Day."</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-15. Designation of "Bill Elliott Day."</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-15__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The General Assembly finds that a Georgia family's proud tradition of racing began in Dawsonville, Georgia, under the tutelage and guiding hand of George Elliott.  George's young son Bill began to demonstrate at an early age a natural skill and competitive racing instinct at Dixie Speedway in Woodstock, and in 1976, at the tender age of 20, Bill Elliott entered his first Winston Cup race and launched a career that would span decades. Awesome Bill from Dawsonville, a modest, unassuming, and unpretentious man, has become a household name in NASCAR racing and has been selected Most Popular Driver an unprecedented 16 times, Georgia Professional Athlete of the Year twice, National Motorsports Driver of the Year 14 times, and in 1998, was inducted into the Georgia Sports Hall of Fame. It is virtually impossible to list all of the honors and awards Million Dollar Bill has garnered over his incandescent career, but perhaps his most acclaimed accomplishment is his support, love, and respect from racing fans.  He has given unstintingly of his time, talents, energy, and financial resources to numerous charities including the Special Olympics, the M.D. Anderson Cancer Center, and the Make-A-Wish Foundation and it is abundantly fitting and proper that this extraordinary Georgian be recognized in a special and lasting manner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-15__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The members of the General Assembly commend Bill Elliott for his over 30 years of outstanding contributions to the sport of racing and designate October 8 of each year as "Bill Elliott Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-15, enacted by Ga. L. 2005, p. 1159, § .1/SB 168; Ga. L. 2006, p. 72, § 1/SB 465.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-15, enacted by Ga. L. 2005, p. 1159, § .1/SB 168; Ga. L. 2006, p. 72, § 1/SB 465.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-15.1">
          <num>1-4-15.1</num>
          <heading>Designation of "Ronald Reagan Day."</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-15.1. Designation of "Ronald Reagan Day."</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The General Assembly recognizes that:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>President Ronald Wilson Reagan, a man of humble background, worked throughout his life serving freedom and advancing the public good, having been employed as an entertainer, Union leader, corporate spokesman, Governor of California, and President of the United States;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ronald Reagan served with honor and distinction for two terms as the fortieth President of the United States of America, and in his reelection he earned the confidence of three-fifths of the electorate and was victorious in 49 of the 50 states in the general election, a record unsurpassed in the history of American presidential elections;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>During Mr. Reagan's presidency he worked in a bipartisan manner to enact his bold agenda of restoring accountability and common sense to government which led to an unprecedented economic expansion and opportunity for millions of Americans;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Mr. Reagan's commitment to an active social policy agenda for the nation's children helped lower crime rates and drug use in our neighborhoods;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>President Reagan's commitment to our armed forces contributed to the restoration of pride in America, her values and those cherished by the free world, and prepared America's armed forces to meet twenty-first century challenges;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>President Reagan's vision of "peace through strength" led to the end of the Cold War and the ultimate demise of the Soviet Union, guaranteeing basic human rights for millions of people; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_a__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>February 6, 2005, will be the ninety-fourth anniversary of Ronald Reagan's birth, and the first since his passing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-15.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>February 6 of each year is designated "Ronald Reagan Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-15.1, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 139, § 1/HB 713; Ga. L. 2007, p. 47, § 1/SB 103.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-15.1, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 139, § 1/HB 713; Ga. L. 2007, p. 47, § 1/SB 103.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-16">
          <num>1-4-16</num>
          <heading>Designation of "Prison Chaplains Appreciation Day."</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-16. Designation of "Prison Chaplains Appreciation Day."
The fourth Monday in March of each year is designated and shall be observed as "Prison Chaplains Appreciation Day" in all state and private correctional institutions in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-16, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 484, § 1/HB 1292.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-16, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 484, § 1/HB 1292.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-17">
          <num>1-4-17</num>
          <heading>Declaration of "Georgia Day."</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-17. Declaration of "Georgia Day."
The twelfth day of February in each year is declared to be "Georgia Day," as the anniversary of the landing of the first colonists in Georgia under Oglethorpe.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-17, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 2, § 1/HB 387.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-17, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 2, § 1/HB 387.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-18">
          <num>1-4-18</num>
          <heading>Designation of "School Bus Drivers Appreciation Day."</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-18. Designation of "School Bus Drivers Appreciation Day."
The third Monday in October of every year is designated "School Bus Drivers Appreciation Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-18, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 563, § 2/HB 791.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-18, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 563, § 2/HB 791.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-19">
          <num>1-4-19</num>
          <heading>Designation of "School Bus Safety Week."</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-19. Designation of "School Bus Safety Week."
The third week in October of every year is designated "School Bus Safety Week" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-19, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 566, § 2/HB 790.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-19, enacted by Ga. L. 2008, p. 566, § 2/HB 790.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-20">
          <num>1-4-20</num>
          <heading>Designation of Confederate History and Heritage Month</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-20. Designation of Confederate History and Heritage Month</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-20__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The General Assembly hereby finds and determines that tourism is a great economic resource in Georgia; and historical, heritage, and cultural inheritance are among the tourism industry's most popular attractions. Georgia's Confederate heritage, physical artifacts and battle sites, and historic events and persons not only attract visitors, they are potentially of even greater importance and benefit to our state's economy. Increased development of our state's Confederate history and heritage as part of the tourism industry will be enhanced through recognizing, celebrating, and advertising that heritage and history.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-20__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The month of April of each year is hereby designated as Confederate History and Heritage Month and shall be set aside to honor, observe, and celebrate the Confederate States of America, its history, those who served in its armed forces and government, and all those millions of its citizens of various races and ethnic groups and religions who contributed in sundry and myriad ways to the cause which they held so dear from its founding on February 4, 1861, in Montgomery, Alabama, until the Confederate ship CSS Shenandoah sailed into Liverpool Harbor and surrendered to British authorities on November 6, 1865.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-20__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Officials and departments of state, county, and municipal governments, boards of education, elementary and secondary schools, colleges and universities, businesses, and all citizens are encouraged to participate in programs, displays, and activities that commemorate and honor our shared history and cultural inheritance throughout each April during Confederate History and Heritage Month.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-20, enacted by Ga. L. 2009, p. 207, § 2/SB 27.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-20, enacted by Ga. L. 2009, p. 207, § 2/SB 27.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-21">
          <num>1-4-21</num>
          <heading>Designation of "Purple Heart Day."</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-4-21. Designation of "Purple Heart Day."</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-21__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>August 7 of every year is designated as "Purple Heart Day."</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-4-21__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor may annually issue a proclamation designating August 7 as "Purple Heart Day." Public officials, schools, private organizations, and all residents of this state are encouraged to commemorate Purple Heart Day and honor those wounded or killed while serving in any branch of the United States Armed Services.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-21, enacted by Ga. L. 2014, p. 758, § 1/SB 276.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-21, enacted by Ga. L. 2014, p. 758, § 1/SB 276.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_1-4-22">
          <num>1-4-22</num>
          <heading>Designation of "Water Professionals Appreciation Day."</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 1-4-22. Designation of "Water Professionals Appreciation Day."
The first Monday in May of each year is designated as "Water Professionals Appreciation Day" in Georgia.

History Code 1981, § 1-4-22, enacted by Ga. L. 2015, p. 108, § 2/SB 119.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-4-22, enacted by Ga. L. 2015, p. 108, § 2/SB 119.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_1-5">
        <num>Chapter 5</num>
        <section eId="sec_1-5-1">
          <num>1-5-1</num>
          <heading>Power of board of directors to change name and style under which an authority operates</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 1-5-1. Power of board of directors to change name and style under which an authority operates
The board of directors of any public authority created by a constitutional amendment, which amendment was continued in force as a part of the 1983 Constitution pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_1-5-1__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Article XI, Section I, Paragraph IV, shall be empowered to change the name and style under which the authority operates by adopting an appropriate resolution by a majority vote at any regular or special meeting of the authority. If the board of directors changes the name and style under which an authority operates in accordance with the provisions of this Code section, such action shall in no way alter or restrict the character or nature of the authority and the authority shall be recognized and declared to be one and the same continuing body corporate and politic with all the powers heretofore or hereafter granted to said authority; and any acts done under the new name and style so adopted shall be for all intents and purposes equally as valid and effective as if done under the original name and style of the authority.

History Code 1981, § 1-5-1, enacted by Ga. L. 1989, p. 47, § 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 1-5-1, enacted by Ga. L. 1989, p. 47, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
