<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act>
    <meta>
      <identification source="#cosilico">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-12-01" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="22"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22/eng@2018-12-01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22/eng@2018-12-01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-12-01" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22/eng@2018-12-01/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ga/act/ocga/title-22/eng@2018-12-01/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <publication date="2018-12-01" name="Official Code of Georgia Annotated" showAs="OCGA"/>
      <references>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_22-1">
        <num>Chapter 1</num>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-1">
          <num>22-1-1</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-1. DefinitionsAs used in this title, the term:(1)  "Blighted property," "blighted," or "blight" means any urbanized or developed property which:(A)  Presents two or more of the following conditions:</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Uninhabitable, unsafe, or abandoned structures;

(ii)  Inadequate provisions for ventilation, light, air, or sanitation;

(iii)  An imminent harm to life or other property caused by fire, flood, hurricane, tornado, earthquake, storm, or other natural catastrophe respecting which the Governor has declared a state of emergency under state law or has certified the need for disaster assistance under federal law; provided, however, that this division shall not apply to property unless the relevant public agency has given notice in writing to the property owner regarding specific harm caused by the property and the owner has failed to take reasonable measures to remedy the harm;

(iv)  A site identified by the federal Environmental Protection Agency as a Superfund site pursuant to 42 U.S.C. Section 9601, et seq., or environmental contamination to an extent that requires remedial investigation or a feasability study;</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v">
            <num>(v)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Repeated illegal activity on the individual property of which the property owner knew or should have known; or

(vi)  The maintenance of the property is below state, county, or municipal codes for at least one year after notice of the code violation; and(B)  Is conducive to ill health, transmission of disease, infant mortality, or crime in the immediate proximity of the property.
Property shall not be deemed blighted because of esthetic conditions.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Common carrier" means any carrier required by law to convey passengers or freight without refusal if the approved fare or charge is paid.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Condemnor" or "condemning authority" means:
(A)  The State of Georgia or any branch or any department, board, commission, agency, or authority of the executive branch of the government of the State of Georgia;

(B)  Any county or municipality of the State of Georgia;

(C)  Any housing authority with approval of the governing authority of the city or county as provided in Code Section 8-3-31.1;

(D)  Any other political subdivision of the State of Georgia which possesses the power of eminent domain; and

(E)  All public utilities that possess the right or power of eminent domain.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Economic development" means any economic activity to increase tax revenue, tax base, or employment or improve general economic health, when the activity does not result in:
(A)  Transfer of land to public ownership;

(B)  Transfer of property to a private entity that is a public utility;

(C)  Lease of property to private entities that occupy an incidental area within a public project; or

(D)  The remedy of blight.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Each person with a legal claim" means the owner of the property or of any remainder, reversion, mortgage, lease, security deed, or other claim in the property.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Interest" means any title or nontitle interest other than fee simple title.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Persons" means individuals, partnerships, associations, and corporations, domestic or foreign.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Property" means fee simple title.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) "Public use" means:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The possession, occupation, or use of the land by the general public or by state or local governmental entities;

(ii)  The use of land for the creation or functioning of public utilities;

(iii)  The opening of roads, the construction of defenses, or the providing of channels of trade or travel;

(iv)  The acquisition of property where title is clouded due to the inability to identify or locate all owners of the property;</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v">
            <num>(v)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The acquisition of property where unanimous consent is received from each person with a legal claim that has been identified and found; or(vi)  The remedy of blight.
(B)  The public benefit of economic development shall not constitute a public use.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-1__subsec_v__para_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Public utility" means any publicly, privately, or cooperatively owned line, facility, or system for producing, transmitting, or distributing communications, power, electricity, light, heat, gas, oil products, water, steam, clay, waste, storm water not connected with highway drainage, and other similar services and commodities, including publicly owned fire and police and traffic signals and street lighting systems, which directly or indirectly serve the public. This term also means a person, municipal corporation, county, state agency, or public authority which owns or manages a utility as defined in this paragraph. This term shall also include common carriers and railroads.

History Ga. L. 1929, p. 219, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-201; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 3/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1929, p. 219, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-201; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 3/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-2">
          <num>22-1-2</num>
          <heading>Nature of right of eminent domain; property to be put to public use</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-2. Nature of right of eminent domain; property to be put to public use</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The right of eminent domain is the right of this state, through its regular organization, to reassert, either temporarily or permanently, its dominion over any portion of the soil of this state on account of public exigency and for the public good. Thus, in time of war or insurrection the proper authorities may possess and hold any part of the territory of this state for the common safety. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, except as provided in Code Section 22-1-15, neither this state nor any political subdivision thereof nor any other condemning authority shall use eminent domain unless it is for public use. Public use is a matter of law to be determined by the court and the condemnor bears the burden of proof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in Code Section 22-1-15, no condemnation shall be converted to any use other than a public use for 20 years from the initial condemnation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p/>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Code Section 22-1-15, if property acquired through the power of eminent domain from an owner fails to be put to a public use within five years, the former property owner may apply to the condemnor or its successor or assign for reconveyance or quitclaim of the property to the former property owner or for additional compensation for such property. For purposes of this subsection, property shall be considered to have been put to a public use at the point in time when substantial good faith effort has been expended on a project to put the property to public use, notwithstanding the fact that the project may not have been completed. The application shall be in writing, and the condemnor or its successor or assign shall act on the application within 60 days by:
(A)  Executing a reconveyance or quitclaim of the property upon receipt of compensation not to exceed the amount of the compensation paid by the condemnor at the time of acquisition; or(B)  Paying additional compensation to the former owner of the property, such compensation to be calculated by subtracting the price paid by the condemnor for the property at the time of acquisition from the fair market value of the property at the time the application is filed.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the condemnor fails to take either action within 60 days, the former property owner may, within the next 90 days following, initiate an action in the superior court in the county in which the property is located to reacquire the property or receive additional compensation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_c__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The condemnor shall provide notice to each former owner of the property prior to acquisition if the condemnor fails to put such property to a public use within five years. The condemnee shall have one year from the date notice is received to bring an application under this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When property is acquired from more than one owner for the same public use and reconveyance or additional compensation to a single owner is impracticable, any party to the original condemnation or each person with a legal claim in such condemnation may file an action in the superior court in the county in which the property is located for an equitable resolution.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-2__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Code section shall not apply to condemnations subject to Code Section 22-3-162 or Title 32.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 2201; Code 1868, § 2196; Code 1873, § 2222; Code 1882, § 2222; Civil Code 1895, § 3052; Civil Code 1910, § 3624; Code 1933, § 36-101; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 4/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2017, p. 754, § 1/HB 434.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 2201; Code 1868, § 2196; Code 1873, § 2222; Code 1882, § 2222; Civil Code 1895, § 3052; Civil Code 1910, § 3624; Code 1933, § 36-101; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 4/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2017, p. 754, § 1/HB 434.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-3">
          <num>22-1-3</num>
          <heading>Power of General Assembly to determine when right of eminent domain may be exercised; duty of courts as to laws authorizing the condemnation of private property for private uses</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-3. Power of General Assembly to determine when right of eminent domain may be exercised; duty of courts as to laws authorizing the condemnation of private property for private uses
It is the province of the General Assembly to determine when the right of eminent domain may be exercised. If, however, under pretext of such necessity the General Assembly should pass a law authorizing the taking of property for private use rather than for public use, the courts should declare the law inoperative.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 2202; Code 1868, § 2197; Code 1873, § 2223; Code 1882, § 2223; Civil Code 1895, § 3053; Civil Code 1910, § 3625; Code 1933, § 36-102.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 2202; Code 1868, § 2197; Code 1873, § 2223; Code 1882, § 2223; Civil Code 1895, § 3053; Civil Code 1910, § 3625; Code 1933, § 36-102.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-4">
          <num>22-1-4</num>
          <heading>Manner in which General Assembly may exercise right of eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-4. Manner in which General Assembly may exercise right of eminent domain
The General Assembly may exercise the right of eminent domain directly through the officers of the state, through the medium of corporate bodies, or by means of individual enterprise.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 2203; Code 1868, § 2198; Code 1873, § 2224; Code 1882, § 2224; Civil Code 1895, § 3054; Civil Code 1910, § 3626; Code 1933, § 36-103.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 2203; Code 1868, § 2198; Code 1873, § 2224; Code 1882, § 2224; Civil Code 1895, § 3054; Civil Code 1910, § 3626; Code 1933, § 36-103.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-5">
          <num>22-1-5</num>
          <heading>Requirement of just compensation as a limitation on exercise of power of eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-5. Requirement of just compensation as a limitation on exercise of power of eminent domain
Except in cases of extreme necessity and great urgency, the right of eminent domain cannot be exercised without first providing for just compensation to the owner for the interference with his exclusive rights.

History Orig. Code 1863, § 2204; Code 1868, § 2199; Code 1873, § 2225; Code 1882, § 2225; Civil Code 1895, § 3055; Civil Code 1910, § 3627; Code 1933, § 36-104.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Orig. Code 1863, § 2204; Code 1868, § 2199; Code 1873, § 2225; Code 1882, § 2225; Civil Code 1895, § 3055; Civil Code 1910, § 3627; Code 1933, § 36-104.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-6">
          <num>22-1-6</num>
          <heading>Right of persons to take or damage private property upon payment of just and adequate compensation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-6. Right of persons to take or damage private property upon payment of just and adequate compensation
If a person who is authorized to exercise the power of eminent domain cannot by contract procure the property or the easement, right of way, waterway, franchise, or other interest sought to be condemned, the person may take or damage the property or interest upon paying or tendering to the owner thereof just and adequate compensation.

History Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 2; Civil Code 1895, § 4658; Civil Code 1910, § 5207; Code 1933, § 36-302.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 2; Civil Code 1895, § 4658; Civil Code 1910, § 5207; Code 1933, § 36-302.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-7">
          <num>22-1-7</num>
          <heading>Effect of failure to agree on compensation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-7. Effect of failure to agree on compensation
If the parties cannot agree upon the compensation to be paid, the same shall be assessed and determined as provided in Article 1 of Chapter 2 of this title.

History Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 3; Civil Code 1895, § 4659; Civil Code 1910, § 5208; Code 1933, § 36-303.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 3; Civil Code 1895, § 4659; Civil Code 1910, § 5208; Code 1933, § 36-303.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-8">
          <num>22-1-8</num>
          <heading>Exclusive nature of title</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-8. Exclusive nature of title
All persons authorized to take or damage private property for public purposes shall proceed as set forth in this title.

History Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 4657; Civil Code 1910, § 5206; Code 1933, § 36-301.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1894, p. 95, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 4657; Civil Code 1910, § 5206; Code 1933, § 36-301.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-9">
          <num>22-1-9</num>
          <heading>Policies and practices guiding exercise of eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-9. Policies and practices guiding exercise of eminent domainIn order to encourage and expedite the acquisition of real property by agreements with owners, to avoid litigation and relieve congestion in the courts, to assure consistent treatment for property owners, and to promote public confidence in land acquisition practices, all condemnations and potential condemnations shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be guided by the following policies and practices:
(1)  The condemning authority shall make every reasonable effort to acquire expeditiously real property by negotiation;

(2)  Where the condemning authority seeks to obtain a fee simple interest in real property, real property shall be appraised before the initiation of negotiations, and the owner or his or her designated representatives shall be given an opportunity to accompany the appraiser during his or her inspection of the property, except that the condemning authority may, by law, rule, regulation, or ordinance, prescribe a procedure to waive the appraisal in cases involving the acquisition by sale or donation of property with a low fair market value;

(3)  Before the initiation of negotiations for fee simple interest for real property, the condemning authority shall establish an amount which it believes to be just compensation and shall make a prompt offer to acquire the property for the full amount so established. In no event shall such amount be less than the condemning authority's independent appraisal of the fair market value of such property. The condemning authority shall provide the owner of real property to be acquired with a written statement of, and summary of the basis for, the amount it established as just compensation. Where appropriate, the just compensation for the real property acquired and for damages to remaining real property shall be separately stated. The condemning authority shall consider alternative sites suggested by the owner of the property as part of the compensation offered;

(4)  No owner shall be required to surrender possession of real property before the condemning authority pays the agreed purchase price or deposits with the court in accordance with this title, for the benefit of the owner, an amount not less than the condemning authority's appraisal of the fair market value of such property or the amount of the award of compensation in the condemnation proceeding for such property;

(5)  The construction or development of a project for public use shall be so scheduled that, to the greatest extent practicable, no person lawfully occupying real property shall be required to move from a dwelling or to move his or her business or farm operation without at least 90 days' written notice from the condemning authority of the date by which such move is required;

(6)  If the condemning authority permits an owner or tenant to occupy the real property acquired on a rental basis for a short term or for a period subject to termination by the condemning authority on short notice, the amount of rent required shall not exceed the fair rental value of the property to a short-term occupier;

(7)  In no event shall the condemnor act in bad faith in order to compel an agreement on the price to be paid for the property;

(8)  If any legal interest in real property is to be acquired by exercise of the power of eminent domain, the condemning authority shall institute formal condemnation proceedings. No condemnor shall intentionally make it necessary for an owner to institute legal proceedings to prove the fact of the taking of his or her real property; and

(9)  A person whose real property is being acquired in accordance with this title may, after the person has been fully informed of his or her right to receive just compensation for such property, donate such property, any part thereof, any legal interest therein, or any compensation paid to a condemning authority, as such person shall determine.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-9, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2013, p. 141, § 22/HB 79; Ga. L. 2018, p. 1112, § 22/SB 365.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-9, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2013, p. 141, § 22/HB 79; Ga. L. 2018, p. 1112, § 22/SB 365.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-10">
          <num>22-1-10</num>
          <heading>Duties of condemnor prior to exercise of eminent domain; rights of condemnee; exceptions</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-10. Duties of condemnor prior to exercise of eminent domain; rights of condemnee; exceptions</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior to exercising the power of eminent domain, a governmental condemnor shall:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not less than 15 days before any meeting at which a resolution approving the exercise of eminent domain is to be considered, post a sign, if possible, in the right of way adjacent to each property that is subject to the proposed use of the eminent domain power stating the time, date, and place of such meeting;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Attempt to serve the condemnee personally with notice of the meeting not less than 15 days before any meeting at which such resolution is to be considered, unless service is acknowledged or waived by the condemnee. If the attempted service is unsuccessful, service of notice may be satisfied by mail or statutory overnight delivery to the property owner at the address of record and, if different from the property owner, to the parties in possession of the property, return receipt requested;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ensure that any notice that is required by law to be published be placed in the county legal organ, but such notice shall not be published in the legal notices section of such newspaper; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_a__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ensure that any meeting at which such resolution is to be considered and voted on shall commence after 6:00 P.M.
Any such resolution shall specifically and conspicuously delineate each parcel to be affected.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A nongovernmental condemnor shall, with respect to its exercise of the power of eminent domain in general, by action of the governing body or chief executive officer of the condemnor designate who is authorized to approve the exercise of the power of eminent domain by the condemnor and provide a method for documenting the time of the exercise of final approval of a particular exercise of the power of eminent domain by that individual or group of individuals. Such a condemning authority shall with respect to any particular exercise of the power of eminent domain:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not less than 15 days before the documented time of approval of the exercise of eminent domain, post a sign, if possible, in the right of way adjacent to each property that is subject to the proposed use of the eminent domain power stating: (A) that the property is subject to a proposed condemnation which may be initiated after 15 days from the date of posting; (B) the date of posting; and (C) the name, business address, and telephone number of the condemnor;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not less than 15 days before the documented time of approval of the exercise of eminent domain serve the condemnee personally with notice of the proposed condemnation stating: (A) that the property is subject to a proposed condemnation which may be initiated after 15 days from the date of service; (B) the date of service; and (C) the name, business address, and telephone number of the condemnor. If the attempted service is unsuccessful, service of notice may be satisfied by mail or statutory overnight delivery to the property owner at the address of record and, if different from the property owner, to the parties in possession of the property, return receipt requested; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_b__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide the condemnee with an opportunity to meet with the individual or group of individuals having the power of documented approval or a representative of such individual or individuals.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The condemnee may in writing waive any rights of the condemnee under this Code section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any notice required to be personally served or mailed under this Code section shall be accompanied by a written statement of the rights that the condemnee possesses including but not limited to the right to notice, damages, hearing, and appeal of any award entered by the special master as described in this title. The written statement of rights shall also include the right to bring a motion pursuant to Code Section 22-1-11 as well as a sample motion. The Department of Community Affairs shall promulgate written notice of rights forms that shall be used for purposes of this subsection. The Department of Community Affairs shall promulgate different notice forms for each of the types of condemnation proceedings authorized by law. This subsection shall not become effective until the Department of Community Affairs has promulgated the written notice of rights forms contemplated under this subsection and such forms shall be promulgated no later than January 1, 2007.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Code section shall not apply to condemnations for the purposes of constructing or expanding one or more electric transmission lines, to condemnations pursuant to Code Section 46-8-121, or to any condemnations under Title 32.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-10, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-10, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-10.1">
          <num>22-1-10.1</num>
          <heading>Time for bringing condemnation action; exceptions</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-10.1. Time for bringing condemnation action; exceptions</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10.1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10.1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, no action for condemnation may be brought in any court of this state until at least 30 days after the date of the resolution or documented approval described in Code Section 22-1-10.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an emergency condition exists requiring the acquisition of property for the protection of the public health and safety, the condemnor may declare the existence of an emergency and adopt a resolution defining the emergency. Notice and hearing as required by Code Section 22-1-10 may be waived by the condemning body in an emergency condition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-10.1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Code section shall not apply to the acquisition or condemnation of property where consent is received from each person with a legal claim that has been identified or found.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-10.1, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-10.1, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-11">
          <num>22-1-11</num>
          <heading>Determination of authority to exercise public domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-11. Determination of authority to exercise public domain
Before the vesting of title in the condemnor and upon motion of the condemnee, or within ten days of the entry of the special master's award by entry of exception to the case, the court shall determine whether the exercise of the power of eminent domain is for a public use and whether the condemning authority has the legal authority to exercise the power of eminent domain and may stay other proceedings of the condemnation pending the decision of the court. The condemning authority shall bear the burden of proof by the evidence presented that the condemnation is for a public use as defined in Code Section 22-1-1. Nothing in this Code section shall be construed to require the condemnee to seek or obtain a special master's award prior to a hearing or decision by the court under this Code section.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-11, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-11, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-12">
          <num>22-1-12</num>
          <heading>Reimbursement to property owner of reasonable costs and expenses associated with condemnation proceedings</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-12. Reimbursement to property owner of reasonable costs and expenses associated with condemnation proceedingsIn all actions where a condemning authority exercises the power of eminent domain, the court having jurisdiction of a proceeding instituted by a condemnor to acquire real property by condemnation shall award the owner of any right or title to or interest in such real property such sum as will in the opinion of the court reimburse such owner for his or her reasonable costs and expenses, including reasonable attorney, appraisal, and engineering fees, actually incurred because of the condemnation proceedings, if:
(1)  The final judgment is that the condemning authority cannot acquire the real property by condemnation; or

(2)  The proceeding is abandoned by the condemning authority.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-12, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-12, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-13">
          <num>22-1-13</num>
          <heading>Compensation to condemnee for relocation damages and expenses</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-1-13. Compensation to condemnee for relocation damages and expensesIn addition to the types of relocation damages permissible under law, any condemnee that is displaced as a result of the condemnation shall be entitled to:
(1)  Actual reasonable expenses in moving himself or herself, his or her family, business, farm operation, or other personal property within a reasonable distance from the property condemned;

(2)  Actual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving or discontinuing a business or farm operation;

(3)  Such other relocation expenses as authorized by law; and

(4)  With the consent of the condemnee, the condemnor may provide alternative site property as full or partial compensation.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-13, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-13, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-14">
          <num>22-1-14</num>
          <heading>Valuation of condemned property</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-14. Valuation of condemned property</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-14__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When property is condemned under this title or any other title of this Code, the value of the condemned property may be determined through lay or expert testimony and its admissibility shall be addressed to the sound discretion of the court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-14__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any party to a condemnation proceeding seeks to introduce expert testimony as to the issue of just and adequate compensation, Code Section 24-7-702 shall not apply.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-14, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2011, p. 99, § 38/HB 24.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-14, enacted by Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 5/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2011, p. 99, § 38/HB 24.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-1-15">
          <num>22-1-15</num>
          <heading>Process for condemnor to condemn property for public use; requirements; service</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-1-15. Process for condemnor to condemn property for public use; requirements; service</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this Code section, the term:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Condemnor" means a county, municipality, or consolidated government of this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Economic development" means any economic activity to increase tax revenue, tax base, or employment or improve general economic health, when the activity does not result in:
(A)  Transfer of land to public ownership;

(B)  Transfer of property to a private entity that is a public utility; or

(C)  Lease of property to private entities that occupy an incidental area within a public project.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>"Public use" means the remedy of blight when economic development is a secondary or ancillary public benefit of condemnation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A condemnor seeking to condemn property for public use under this Code section shall first petition the superior court of the county having jurisdiction for a judgment in rem against such property seeking a determination as to whether the property complained of in the petition is blighted property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section shall set forth:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The facts showing the right to condemn;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The property or interest to be taken;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The names and residences of the persons whose property or interests are to be taken or otherwise affected, so far as known;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of any unknown persons or classes of unknown persons whose rights in the property or interest are to be affected;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the appearance of the property and any structures thereon;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Such other facts as are necessary for a full understanding of the cause;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement setting forth the need of the court to review the evidence and determine whether such property meets the definition of blight;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A prayer for an order to be issued by the court as may be proper and desired; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_b__para_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether any of the persons referred to in this subsection are minors or disabled.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p/>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_d__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon presentation of the petition set forth in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, the court shall issue an order requiring all parties of interest to appear at a time and place named in the order and make known their objections if any as to the question of whether the property shall be deemed blighted.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date of the hearing shall be no less than 30 days from the date such petition is filed.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The order described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall give directions for providing notice of the hearing and the service of such notices.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It shall not be necessary to attach any other process to the petition except the order referred to in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, and the cause shall proceed as in rem.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All persons entitled to notice under the facts stated in the petition shall be personally served with a copy of the petition and order issued pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section as in other causes at law, unless such service is waived in writing. All other service shall be made by the method as provided in Part 2 of Article 1 of Chapter 2 of this title, and all persons so served shall be deemed parties to the cause.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any cases where it seems to the court to be in the interest of justice and of more effective notice to cause additional notice or service to be given, it shall be within the court's discretion to so order. In such cases, such additional notice and service shall be made as ordered before the cause proceeds to final hearing. In cases where any taxes are alleged to be due or unpaid, the order shall direct that a separate notice to that effect be given the proper tax collector or tax commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On the day named in the order made pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, or at any other time to which the hearing may be continued, the court, having first passed on and adjudged all questions touching service and notice, shall, after hearing from all persons responding and desiring to be heard, make such order as is appropriate based on the evidence as to whether or not the property shall be deemed blighted.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any property deemed blighted shall be described in the order adjudging such determination and contain a statement of the then current approved land use of the property, or in the case of vacant property, the last lawful use for which the property was occupied, and such property's future use shall be restricted to the same land use as stated in the order for a period of five years from the date of the order.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A condemnor which has obtained an order under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section declaring a property to be blighted shall within 60 days from such order, or in the event of an appeal, 60 days from the date when the remittitur of the appellate court is made the judgment of the court, file an action to condemn the property pursuant to the procedures set forth in Article 3 of Chapter 2 of this title. When a condemnor proceeds as set forth in Article 3 of Chapter 2 of this title, it shall attach a copy of the order issued under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-1-15__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section.

History Code 1981, § 22-1-15, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 754, § 2/HB 434.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-1-15, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 754, § 2/HB 434.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_22-2">
        <num>Chapter 2</num>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-100">
          <num>22-2-100</num>
          <heading>"Condemning body" and "condemnor" defined</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-100. "Condemning body" and "condemnor" definedAs used in this article, "condemning body" or "condemnor" means:
(1)  The State of Georgia or any branch or any department, board, commission, agency, or authority of the executive branch of the government of the State of Georgia;

(2)  Any county or municipality of the State of Georgia;

(3)  Any housing authority with approval of the governing authority of the city or county as provided in Code Section 8-3-31.1;

(4)  Any other political subdivision of the State of Georgia which possesses the power of eminent domain; and

(5)  All public utilities that possess the right or power of eminent domain.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 1; Ga. L. 1962, p. 461, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 825, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 7/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 1; Ga. L. 1962, p. 461, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 825, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 7/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-101">
          <num>22-2-101</num>
          <heading>Effect of article on other methods of condemnation; intent of article</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-101. Effect of article on other methods of condemnation; intent of article
This article shall be supplementary to and cumulative of the methods of condemnation described in Articles 1 and 3 of this chapter in cases in which the state, or any branch of the government of the state, or any county, municipality, or other political subdivision of the state, or any housing authority, or any other person possessing the power of eminent domain is concerned. This article is intended to provide a simpler and more effective method of condemnation in those cases where a judicial supervision of the proceedings is desirable by reason of the necessity for a quick determination of the just and adequate compensation to be paid the owner of the property or interest subject to be condemned, or by reason of the number of parties at interest or the conflicting interests of such parties, or in cases where there are parties who are non compos mentis or who are not sui juris or who are nonresidents, or in cases where there are conflicting interests or doubtful questions. In all particulars not otherwise specially provided for in this article, the court shall conform its procedure as nearly as possible to Articles 1 and 3 of this chapter.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 2.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 2.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-102">
          <num>22-2-102</num>
          <heading>Filing of petition of condemnation; order for parties to appear before special master, make known their rights or interests, and other matters; time of hearing before special master; directions for notice and service thereof; attachment of process to petition; cause to proceed in rem</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-102. Filing of petition of condemnation; order for parties to appear before special master, make known their rights or interests, and other matters; time of hearing before special master; directions for notice and service thereof; attachment of process to petition; cause to proceed in rem</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-102__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the requirements set forth in Chapter 1 of this title, whenever it is desirable, for any reason, to arrive at a quick and certain determination of the compensation to be paid first to the condemnee for the taking or damaging of private property, the condemnor shall:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-102__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>File a petition in a superior court having jurisdiction for a judgment in rem against the property or interest therein, as provided in Code Section 22-2-130; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-102__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At or before the filing of the petition, present a copy of the petition to a judge of the superior court of the county wherein the property or interest sought to be condemned is located. Thereupon, unless waived by the parties the judge shall have a hearing in court, in chambers, or by telephone with the parties not less than ten days nor more than 30 days from the filing of the petition to appoint a special master. After such hearing, the judge shall make an order requiring the condemnor, the person in possession of the property or interest, and each person with a legal claim or interest to appear at a hearing before a special master at a time and place specified in the order and to make known their rights, if any, in and to the property or interest sought to be condemned, their claims as to the value of the property or interest, and any other matters material to their respective rights.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-102__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The hearing before the special master shall take place not less than 30 days nor more than 60 days after the date of the entry of the order appointing the special master.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-102__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The order shall give such directions for notice and the service thereof as are appropriate and as are consistent with this article, in such manner as to provide most effectively an opportunity to all parties at interest to be heard. In condemnations for purposes of constructing or expanding one or more electric transmission lines, in addition to service of the order, a copy of the order shall be mailed by certified mail or sent by statutory overnight delivery to any person shown by the public ad valorem tax records of the county in which the property is located to have an interest in the property and to any other person having open and obvious possession of the property. It shall not be necessary to attach any other process to the petition except the order so made, and the cause shall proceed as in rem.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 5; Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 8/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 5; Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 8/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-102.1">
          <num>22-2-102.1</num>
          <heading>Petitioning superior court for judgment in rem</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-102.1. Petitioning superior court for judgment in rem
In addition to the requirements set forth in Code Section 22-1-10, whenever it shall be necessary for such condemning body to take or damage private property, or any interest or easement therein, in pursuance of any law so authorizing, for any public use, and where, by reason of the necessities of the public needs, of which the condemning body shall be the exclusive judge, and it shall be desirable for these reasons to have a quick and effective adjudication of the just and adequate compensation to be paid the owner or owners of such property before taking the same, and it shall be desirable to have a judicial ascertainment and judicial supervision of all questions and proceedings connected with the matter, such condemning body may, through any authorized representative, petition the superior court of the county having jurisdiction, for a judgment in rem against said property, or any easement or other interest in said property, condemning the same in fee simple to the use of the petitioner upon payment of just and adequate compensation therefor.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 3; Code 1981, § 22-2-102.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 16.1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 9/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 3; Code 1981, § 22-2-102.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 16.1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 9/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-102.2">
          <num>22-2-102.2</num>
          <heading>Contents of petition</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-102.2. Contents of petitionThe petition referred to in Code Section 22-2-102.1 shall set forth:
(1)  The facts showing the right to condemn;

(2)  The property or interest to be taken or damaged;

(3)  The names and residences of the persons whose property or interests are to be taken or otherwise affected, so far as known;

(4)  A description of any unknown persons or classes of unknown persons whose rights in the property or interest are to be affected;

(5)  A statement setting forth the necessity to condemn the private property and describing the public use for which the condemnor seeks the property; and

(6)  Such other facts as are necessary for a full understanding of the cause.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 4; Code 1981, § 22-2-102.2, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 16.1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 10/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 4; Code 1981, § 22-2-102.2, enacted by Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 16.1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 10/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-103">
          <num>22-2-103</num>
          <heading>Appointment of special master -- Generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-103. Appointment of special master -- Generally
The special master provided for in this article shall be appointed by the judge or judges of the superior courts of each judicial circuit and shall discharge the duties provided for in this article. Nothing contained in this article shall be construed as limiting the number of special masters for the circuit, and any judge of the superior court may appoint a special master for any particular case or cases. The special master so appointed must be a competent attorney at law, be of good standing in his profession, and have at least three years' experience in the practice of law. His relation and accountability to the court shall be that of an auditor or master in the general practice existing in this state. He shall hold office at the pleasure of the judge and shall be removable at any time with or without cause. Each special master shall take and file in the office of the clerk of the superior court of the county in which the property or interest to be condemned is situated, along with the order of his appointment, an oath or affidavit substantially in the form prescribed in Code Section 22-2-105.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 6; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 6; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-104">
          <num>22-2-104</num>
          <heading>Appointment of special master -- Form to be used in appointing special master</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-104. Appointment of special master -- Form to be used in appointing special master
Substantially, the following form should be used in appointing a special master:
                , a competent attorney at law, residing in the         
   Judicial Circuit, and of at least three years' experience in the practice 
   of law, is hereby appointed a special master in and for the       Judicial 
   Circuit, to discharge the duties of special master as provided in the 
   condemnation law of this state. This appointment is                     
   (either for general duties or for a particular case, as the case may be).
      This         day of        ,   .

                                                          Judge, Superior Court

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 7; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 22.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 7; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 22.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-105">
          <num>22-2-105</num>
          <heading>Appointment of special master -- Oath of special master</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-105. Appointment of special master -- Oath of special master
The special master is required to take the following oath to be filed along with the order of his appointment in the office of the clerk of the superior court of the county in which the property or interest to be condemned is situated:
      I,          , do swear that I will faithfully, well, and truly perform 
   the duties of special master under the condemnation law, according to law 
   and to the best of my skill and ability.

   Sworn to and subscribed

   before me this      

   day of     ,      .

   (Title and authority
   of attesting officer) 

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 8; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 2; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 22.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 8; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 2; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 22.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-106">
          <num>22-2-106</num>
          <heading>Compensation of special master; allowance by judge of reasonable time for special master to inspect premises</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-106. Compensation of special master; allowance by judge of reasonable time for special master to inspect premises</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-106__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The compensation of the special master shall be provided for by a proper order of the judge of the superior court; shall be included in and made a part of the judgment of the court condemning the property or any interest therein sought to be taken, such judgment to be based on the award of the special master and shall be paid by the condemning body. Such compensation shall be left to the discretion of the court and shall not exceed a reasonable hourly rate consistent with local standards unless otherwise agreed upon by the parties with consent of the court. The compensation of the special master shall be assessed as court costs and shall be paid prior to the filing of any appeal from the judgment of the court; provided, however, that if such compensation has not been determined and assessed at the time of filing any such appeal, the same shall be paid within 30 days from the date of assessment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-106__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The judge may allow the special master a reasonable period of time for personal inspection of the premises and may compensate the special master for his or her time spent inspecting the premises and for any actual expenses incurred by the special master in connection with the inspection, provided that the special master shall file an affidavit with the court showing his or her time spent in inspection and itemizing his or her expenses.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 9; Ga. L. 1975, p. 27, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 408, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 11/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 9; Ga. L. 1975, p. 27, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 408, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 11/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-107">
          <num>22-2-107</num>
          <heading>Service of process; award by special master and judgment of court conclusive as to right of condemnor to take or damage property or interest</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-107. Service of process; award by special master and judgment of court conclusive as to right of condemnor to take or damage property or interest</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Copies of the petition, together with the order of the court provided for in Code Section 22-2-102, shall in all cases be served upon the person in possession of the property or interest sought to be condemned and upon all persons who are known to have any rights in such property or interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The return of service signed by the sheriff or his lawful deputy, or an affidavit of service executed by any citizen of this state, reciting that a copy of the petition and order was served upon the named condemnee in person or by leaving a copy at the place of his residence, shall be sufficient evidence as to the service of the named condemnee. It shall be the duty of the sheriff or citizen, as the case may be, to cause service to be made within three days from the date of the order of the judge on the petition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any of the condemnees or other persons known to have any rights in the property or interest reside outside of the county, the judge shall order service to be made upon such party or parties. Such service shall be perfected by causing a copy of the petition and order to be served upon the party or parties by the sheriff or any lawful deputy of the county of the residence of the party or parties. In addition, service may be made by any citizen. The return of such sheriff or lawful deputy, or the affidavit of such citizen that the party or parties were served, either in person or by leaving a copy of the petition and order at the residence, shall be conclusive as to service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff or any lawful deputy of the county where the petition is filed shall serve nonresidents of this state:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By posting a copy of the petition, together with the order of the judge thereon, on the bulletin board at the courthouse door of the county in which the property or interest sought to be condemned is located for not less than five days prior to the time of the hearing before the special master;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By the insertion of a notice identifying the property or interest sought to be condemned, as well as the date and place of the hearing before the special master, in a newspaper having general circulation in the county wherein such property or interest is located, for one issue of said paper, the date of which shall be not less than four nor more than seven days prior to the hearing before the special master, and which is the same newspaper in which the sheriff's advertisements are carried; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where the address of such nonresidents is known, by mailing to them by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery a copy of the petition and order.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any of the persons entitled to service under this Code section are minors, or insane persons, or persons otherwise laboring under disabilities, the guardian of such persons shall be served. If the guardian resides outside of the county or is a nonresident, he or she shall be served as provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section. If such minor or other person laboring under disabilities has no guardian, service shall be perfected by serving the disabled person personally or, in the event the disabled person lives outside of the county or is a nonresident, by serving the disabled person by the method provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section for other persons who live outside of the county or are nonresidents, and by serving the judge of the probate court of the county wherein such property or interest is located, who shall stand in the place of and protect the rights of the disabled person or appoint a guardian ad litem for such person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event of unknown persons or unborn remaindermen who are likely to have any rights in the property or interest or the proceeds thereof, the judge of the probate court of the county wherein such property or interest is located shall be served with a copy of the petition and order; and it shall be his duty to stand in the place and protect the rights of such unknown parties or unborn remaindermen.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-107__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The purpose of this article being to quicken and simplify the condemnation proceeding in all cases where the public good requires it and to provide for a condemnation in rem against the property or interest required to be taken or damaged and insofar as is reasonably possible to protect the rights of all parties to be heard at the time of the hearing before the special master, a substantial and reasonable effort to comply with the various modes of service provided for in this Code section shall be sufficient. Insofar as concerns the right of the condemning body to take or damage the property or any interest therein, upon the payment of the amount awarded by the special master into the registry of the court, the award of the special master and the judgment of the court condemning the property or interest to the use of the condemning body shall be conclusive.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 10; Ga. L. 1966, p. 388, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3; Ga. L. 2004, p. 161, § 4.3.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 10; Ga. L. 1966, p. 388, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3; Ga. L. 2004, p. 161, § 4.3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-108">
          <num>22-2-108</num>
          <heading>Powers and duties of special master generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-108. Powers and duties of special master generally
The special master appointed pursuant to Code Section 22-2-103 shall serve in lieu of a board of assessors; provided, however, that if two assessors are selected pursuant to Code Section 22-2-108.1, the special master shall serve as the chairperson of the special master panel and shall decide all issues other than value issues which arise at the hearing provided for in Code Section 22-2-102. The special master's duties and authority, except as otherwise provided for in this article, shall be the same as provided by Code Sections 22-2-61 through 22-2-63. The special master shall hold the hearing provided for in Code Section 22-2-102 at the time and place provided by the order of the judge of the superior court and in compliance with the duties and authority conferred by this article. The special master shall not be authorized to continue or delay the hearing, except as otherwise provided by Code Section 22-2-108.1, relating to granting of a recess for selection of assessors, or by Code Section 9-10-150, relating to granting continuances by reason of membership in the General Assembly during sessions thereof, or except upon the written order of the judge of the superior court; and such a continuance shall be granted only for good cause shown to that judge. When it shall be necessary for the judge to grant a continuance, the continuance shall be for not more than five days from the date of the order granting the continuance.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 11; Ga. L. 1973, p. 479, § 1; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 3.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 11; Ga. L. 1973, p. 479, § 1; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-108.1">
          <num>22-2-108.1</num>
          <heading>Special master panel; selection; notice; powers and duties</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-108.1. Special master panel; selection; notice; powers and duties</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-108.1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time at least five calendar days before commencement of the hearing specified in the order of the judge of the superior court, the condemnee or any other person having a right or interest in the property may, by written notice served on the condemnor and all other parties to the proceeding, select an assessor to hear and decide value issues at the hearing. Within five days after receipt of such notice, the condemnor shall, by written notice served on the condemnee and all other parties to the proceeding, select an assessor to hear and decide value issues at the hearing. The provisions of Code Sections 22-2-40 and 22-2-41 shall apply to the selection of such assessors; provided, however, that the special master appointed pursuant to Code Section 22-2-103 shall serve as the third assessor, shall be compensated as provided for in Code Section 22-2-106, and shall continue to perform the duties set forth in Code Section 22-2-108. Notwithstanding the number of condemnees or any other persons having a right or interest in the property, only one assessor shall be selected on behalf of all such condemnees or interested parties.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-108.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event that the notice selecting an assessor by the condemnee or other person having a right or interest in the property is not served on the condemnor more than five days before the time on which the hearing is to commence as specified in the order of the judge of the superior court, the special master shall convene the hearing at the time and place specified in the order; and if requested by the condemnor, the special master shall then recess the hearing to a date certain, but not more than five calendar days after such time, to allow the condemnor additional time to select an assessor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-108.1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After the condemnee or other person having a right or interest in the property has selected an assessor and the condemnor has selected an assessor, the special master and the two assessors selected by the parties shall constitute the special master panel and, except as otherwise provided in this article, shall perform the duties provided by Code Sections 22-2-61 through 22-2-63. A majority of the special master panel shall decide all value issues which arise at the hearing provided for in Code Section 22-2-102 and shall prepare and submit the award as provided in Code Section 22-2-110.

History Code 1981, § 22-2-108.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 3.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-2-108.1, enacted by Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-109">
          <num>22-2-109</num>
          <heading>Factors to be considered in determining or estimating just and adequate compensation; determination of date of taking; inclusion of date of approval of original location of highway in petition for condemnation; newspaper advertisement</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-109. Factors to be considered in determining or estimating just and adequate compensation; determination of date of taking; inclusion of date of approval of original location of highway in petition for condemnation; newspaper advertisement</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-109__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining or estimating just and adequate compensation to be paid to the owner of any property or interest condemned for public road and street purposes, neither the special master nor the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, nor the jury, in the event of an appeal to a jury, shall be restricted to the agricultural or productive qualities of the land; but inquiry shall be made as to all other legitimate purposes to which the land could be appropriated. The date of taking as contemplated in this Code section shall be the date of the filing of the condemnation proceedings for the acquisition of the property or interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-109__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The condemning authority shall cause the petition for condemnation to set forth the date of the approval of the original location of the highway. It shall be the further duty of the condemning authority, within 30 days from the date of the original approval and designation of said location as a highway, to cause the location of said highway in said county to be advertised once each week for four consecutive weeks in the newspaper of the county in which the sheriff's advertisements are carried; and said advertisement shall designate the land lots or land districts of said county through which such highway will be located. Said advertisement shall further show the date of the said original location of such highway as hereinbefore provided for in this subsection. Said advertisement shall further state that a plat or map of the project showing the exact date of original location is on file at the office of the Department of Transportation, and that any interested party may obtain a copy of same by writing to the Department of Transportation (One Georgia Center, 600 West Peachtree NW, Atlanta, Georgia 30308) and paying a nominal cost therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-109__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining just and adequate compensation for property or interests taken or condemned for public road and street purposes, the award of the special master or the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, or the verdict of the jury, in the event of an appeal, shall, in addition to fixing the value of the land actually taken and used for such purposes, take into consideration the prospective and consequential damages to the remaining property or interest from which the property or interest actually taken was cut off, which consequential damages result to such remaining property or interest because of the location of such public road or street upon the portion actually taken. In addition, the increase of the value of such remaining property or interest from the location of such public road or street shall be considered. Such consequential benefits, if any, may be offset against such consequential damages, if any; but in no event shall consequential benefits be offset against the value of the property or interest taken for such public improvement.

History Ga. L. 1966, p. 320, § 2; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 4; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 22/HB 142.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1966, p. 320, § 2; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 4; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 22/HB 142.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-110">
          <num>22-2-110</num>
          <heading>Award of special master and special master panel -- Time of filing; award to become part of record of proceedings; vesting of title in condemnor upon deposit of award into court; form of award; use in subsequent appeal</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-110. Award of special master and special master panel -- Time of filing; award to become part of record of proceedings; vesting of title in condemnor upon deposit of award into court; form of award; use in subsequent appeal</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The award of the special master or the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, shall be served in a manner consistent with Code Section 9-11-5 upon all the parties and filed with the clerk of the superior court of the county where the property or interest is situated within three days after the date on which such hearing is completed. The special master or the special master panel shall mail the award to the condemnor and any condemnees on the date of filing of the award and provide a certificate of service evidencing the mailing of such award.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The award shall become a part of the record of the proceedings in said matter and shall condemn and vest title to the property or other interest in the condemning body upon the deposit by that body of the amount of the award into the registry of the court, subject to the demand of such condemnee or condemnees, according to their respective interests.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The award shall be in the following form:
                                    "AWARD

   The special master appointed and chosen by the court to hear evidence and 
   give full consideration to all matters touching upon the value of the 
   property or interest sought to be condemned, as shown by the description of 
   the property or interest in the case of      (condemning body) versus     
   (acres of land or other described interest in said land) and     
   (condemnee), Civil action file no.   in superior court, having first taken 
   the oath as required by law of the special master, the same having been 
   filed with the clerk of the Superior Court of      County, and the special 
   master panel, in the event such a panel exists, having heard evidence under 
   oath and given consideration to the value of such property or interest on 
   the     day of     , at   :    .M., as provided for in the order of the 
   court, do decide and recommend to the court as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>I/We find and award to     , condemnee, the sum of $   , as the 
      actual market value of the property or interest sought to be condemned;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>I/We find consequential damages to the remaining property or 
      interest in the amount of $   ;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>I/We find consequential benefits to the remaining property or 
      interest in the amount of $    (never to exceed the amount of the 
      consequential damages);</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>I/We find and award to     , condemnee, the sum of $   , as the 
      value of any associated moving costs;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_c__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Balancing the consequential benefits against the consequential 
      damages, I/we find and award to the condemnee in this case in the total 
      sum of $   , and I/we respectfully recommend to the court that the said 
      property or interest be condemned by a judgment in rem to the use of the 
      condemnor upon the payment of the last stated sum into the registry of 
      the court, subject to the demands of the condemnee.
   This     day of     ,   .

                                                                 Special Master

                                                                       Assessor

                                                                      Assessor"</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-110__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any case where there is an appeal from the award of the special master or the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, to a jury in the superior court, such award shall not be competent evidence. Any such appeal shall be a de novo investigation, and such award shall be detached from the papers in the case before the same are delivered to the jury.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 12; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 3; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 5; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 12/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 22/HB 737.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 12; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 3; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 5; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 12/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 22/HB 737.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-111">
          <num>22-2-111</num>
          <heading>Award of special master or special master panel -- Incorporation of award into judgment of court</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-111. Award of special master or special master panel -- Incorporation of award into judgment of court
Upon the entry of the award of the special master or the special master panel, if such a panel exists, and the presentation of the award to the judge of the superior court, the judge shall enter a proper order and judgment of the court condemning the described property or other interest in rem to the use of the condemnor upon the condemnor's paying into the registry of the court the amount provided in the award.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 13; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 6.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 13; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 6.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-112">
          <num>22-2-112</num>
          <heading>Award of special master -- Appeal of award generally; condemnee's right to jury trial on issue of just and adequate compensation</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-112. Award of special master -- Appeal of award generally; condemnee's right to jury trial on issue of just and adequate compensation</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-112__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the condemnor or any condemnee is dissatisfied with the amount of the award, an appeal shall be filed in the superior court and such appeal shall be filed within ten calendar days from the service of the award, plus three additional calendar days for mailing of the award. At the term succeeding the filing of the appeal, it shall be the duty of the judge to cause an issue to be made and tried by a jury as to the value of the property or interest taken or the amount of damage done, with the same right to move for a new trial and file an appeal as in other cases at law. The entering of an appeal and the proceedings thereon shall not hinder or delay in any way the condemnor's work or the progress thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-112__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The condemnee shall have the right to a jury trial on the issue of just and adequate compensation before the superior court having jurisdiction over the property sought to be condemned during the next term of court following the vesting of title in the condemnor. This right to a jury trial at the next term of court may be waived by the condemnee.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 14; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 7; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 13/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 14; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 7; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 13/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-113">
          <num>22-2-113</num>
          <heading>Award of special master or special master panel -- Effect of tender, payment, or acceptance of award on right of appeal; right of owners of separate and distinct parcels to file separate appeal; effect of discrepancy between award of special master and verdict of jury; issuance of execution upon award or judgment</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-113. Award of special master or special master panel -- Effect of tender, payment, or acceptance of award on right of appeal; right of owners of separate and distinct parcels to file separate appeal; effect of discrepancy between award of special master and verdict of jury; issuance of execution upon award or judgment</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-113__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tender, payment, or acceptance of the amount of the award shall not prevent any party from prosecuting the appeal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-113__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where separate and distinct parcels of property are condemned in the same proceeding, the owner of any separate and distinct property may file a separate appeal to a jury in the superior court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-113__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the amount awarded by the special master or the special master panel, if such a panel exists, is less than that found by the verdict of the jury, the condemnor shall be bound to pay the sum so finally adjudged less the amount previously deposited as provided in Code Section 22-2-110 plus lawful interest on the difference from the date of such deposit, in order to retain the property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-113__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the condemnor fails to pay the amount of the award or judgment within ten days after the same is filed or entered, then the clerk shall issue execution upon such award or judgment which may be levied upon any property of the condemnor.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 15; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 8.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 15; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 8.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-114">
          <num>22-2-114</num>
          <heading>Effect of deposit of award into court registry; conflicting claims as to deposit</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-114. Effect of deposit of award into court registry; conflicting claims as to deposit
When the condemnor has paid into the registry of the court the amount provided for in the award of the special master or the special master panel, if such a panel exists, for the use and benefit of and subject to the demands of the condemnees, the effect of such payment into the registry of the court shall be the same as if paid to the condemnees directly, provided that the clerk shall pay out the money to the condemnees or their personal representatives upon proper proof submitted to him or her as to the quantity of their interests. Where there are conflicting claims, the clerk may require the conflicting parties to establish their claims before the court as is provided by law in other similar matters.

History Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 16; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 9.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 16; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 9.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-130">
          <num>22-2-130</num>
          <heading>Authority to petition superior court for judgment in rem; applicability to acquisition of public property</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-130. Authority to petition superior court for judgment in rem; applicability to acquisition of public property</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-130__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever the government of the State of Georgia, the United States government, or any person having the privilege of exercising the right of eminent domain desires to take or damage private property in pursuance of any law so authorizing and finds or believes that the title of the apparent or presumptive owner of such property is defective, doubtful, incomplete, or in controversy or that there are or may be unknown persons or nonresidents who have or may have some claim or demand thereon or some actual or contingent interest or estate therein or that there are minors or persons under disability who are or may be interested therein or that there are taxes due or that should be paid thereon or concludes for any reason that it is desirable to have a judicial ascertainment of any question connected with the matter, such government or person may, through any authorized representative, petition the superior court of the county having jurisdiction for a judgment in rem against the property or interest, condemning the same to the use of the petitioner upon payment of just and adequate compensation therefor to the person or persons entitled to such payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-130__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-130__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, the provisions of this article shall also apply to the acquisition of public property or an interest therein by condemnation and the power of eminent domain. As used in this subsection, the term "public property" has the meaning provided for in Code Section 50-16-180.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 1; Code 1933, § 36-1104; Ga. L. 1937-38, Ex. Sess., p. 251, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1187, § 3.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 1; Code 1933, § 36-1104; Ga. L. 1937-38, Ex. Sess., p. 251, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1187, § 3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-131">
          <num>22-2-131</num>
          <heading>Contents of petition</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-131. Contents of petition</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition referred to in Code Section 22-2-130 shall set forth:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The facts showing the right to condemn;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The property or interest to be taken or damaged;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The names and residences of the persons whose property or interests are to be taken or otherwise affected, so far as known;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of any unknown persons or classes of unknown persons whose rights in the property or interest are to be affected;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Such other facts as are necessary for a full understanding of the cause;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement setting forth the necessity to condemn the private property and describing the public use for which the condemnor seeks the property; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_a__para_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A prayer for such judgment of condemnation as may be proper and desired.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-131__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any of the persons referred to in this Code section are minors or under disability, the fact shall be stated.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 2; Code 1933, § 36-1105; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 14/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 2; Code 1933, § 36-1105; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 14/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-132">
          <num>22-2-132</num>
          <heading>Order to appear, etc.; directions for notice and service thereof; attachment of process to petition; cause to proceed as in rem</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-132. Order to appear, etc.; directions for notice and service thereof; attachment of process to petition; cause to proceed as in rem</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-132__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon presentation of the petition, the presiding judge shall issue an order requiring the condemnor, the owner of the property or of any interest therein, and the representative of any owner to appear at a time and place named in the order and make known their objections if any, rights, or claims as to the value of the property or of their interest therein, and any other matters material to their respective rights; provided, however, that if the petition includes affidavits from known and located persons with a legal claim, stating that such condemnees do not oppose the condemnation, no hearing pursuant to this Code section shall be required.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-132__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The day named in the order shall be as early as may be convenient but shall be no less than 20 days from the date of the petition, due regard being given to the necessities of notice.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-132__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The order shall give appropriate directions for notice and the service thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-132__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It shall not be necessary to attach any other process to the petition except the order referred to in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-132__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, and the cause shall proceed as in rem.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1106; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 15/HB 1313.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1106; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 15/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-133">
          <num>22-2-133</num>
          <heading>Service of process -- Generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-133. Service of process -- Generally
All persons entitled to notice under the facts stated in the petition who are sui juris and within this state and whose residence is known shall be served by the sheriff with a copy of the petition and order as in other causes at law, unless such service is waived in writing. All other service shall be made in the method pointed out by Part 2 of Article 1 of Chapter 2 of this title, and all persons so served shall be deemed parties to the cause.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1107.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1107.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-134">
          <num>22-2-134</num>
          <heading>Service of process -- Discretion of judge to cause additional notice or service to be given; notification of tax collector or tax commissioner</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-134. Service of process -- Discretion of judge to cause additional notice or service to be given; notification of tax collector or tax commissioner
In any cases where it seems to the presiding judge to be in the interest of justice and of more effective notice to cause additional notice or service to be given, it shall be within his discretion so to order. In such cases, the additional notice and service shall be made as ordered before the cause proceeds to final hearing. In cases where any taxes are alleged or supposed to be due or unpaid, the order shall direct that a separate notice to that effect be given the proper tax collector or tax commissioner.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1108.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 3; Code 1933, § 36-1108.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-135">
          <num>22-2-135</num>
          <heading>Appointment of assessors; discretion of judge to have issues tried in first instance by jury</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-135. Appointment of assessors; discretion of judge to have issues tried in first instance by jury
On the day named in the order made pursuant to Code Section 22-2-132, or at any other time to which the hearing may be continued, the court, having first passed on and adjudged all questions touching service and notice, shall, after hearing from all persons responding and desiring to be heard, make such order as to the appointment of assessors as shall conform most nearly to Article 1 of this chapter and give all interested persons equal rights in the selection thereof. If, by reason of conflicting interests or otherwise, such equality of right cannot be preserved, the judge shall himself make such order on the subject as shall secure a fair and impartial assessment or may in his discretion order the issues tried in the first instance by a jury. In any event, it shall be within the power of the court to hear the cause as speedily as may be consistent with justice and due process of law.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 4; Code 1933, § 36-1109.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 4; Code 1933, § 36-1109.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-136">
          <num>22-2-136</num>
          <heading>Appeal from assessors' award</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-136. Appeal from assessors' award
In case assessors are appointed, the same right of appeal shall lie from their award to a jury in the superior court, as is provided in Part 5 of Article 1 of this chapter and upon like terms and conditions in all respects as are therein provided.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 4; Code 1933, § 36-1110.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 4; Code 1933, § 36-1110.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-137">
          <num>22-2-137</num>
          <heading>Factors to be considered in determining or estimating just and adequate compensation; determination of date of taking; inclusion of date of approval of original location of highway in petition for condemnation; newspaper advertisement</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-2-137. Factors to be considered in determining or estimating just and adequate compensation; determination of date of taking; inclusion of date of approval of original location of highway in petition for condemnation; newspaper advertisement</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-137__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining or estimating just and adequate compensation to be paid to the owner of any property or interest condemned for public road and street purposes, neither the board of assessors nor the jury, in the event of an appeal to a jury, shall be restricted to the agricultural or productive qualities of the land; but inquiry shall be made as to all other legitimate purposes to which the land could be appropriated. The date of taking as contemplated in this Code section shall be the date of the filing of the condemnation proceedings for the acquisition of the property or interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The condemning authority shall cause the petition for condemnation to set forth the date of the approval of the original location of the highway. It shall be the further duty of the condemning authority, within 30 days from the date of the original approval and designation of said location as a highway, to cause the location of said highway in said county to be advertised once each week for four consecutive weeks in the newspaper of the county in which the sheriff's advertisements are carried; and said advertisement shall designate the land lots or land districts of said county through which such highway will be located. Said advertisement shall further show the date of the said original location of such highway as hereinbefore provided for in this subsection. Said advertisement shall further state that a plat or map of the project showing the exact date of original location is on file at the office of the Department of Transportation and that any interested party may obtain a copy of same by writing to the Department of Transportation (One Georgia Center, 600 West Peachtree NW, Atlanta, Georgia 30308) and paying a nominal cost therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-2-137__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining just and adequate compensation for property or interests taken or condemned for public road and street purposes, the award of the board of assessors or the verdict of the jury, in the event of an appeal, shall, in addition to fixing the value of the land actually taken and used for such purposes, take into consideration the prospective and consequential damages to the remaining property or interest from which the property or interest actually taken was cut off, which consequential damages result to such remaining property or interest because of the location of such public road or street upon the portion actually taken. In addition, the increase of the value of such remaining property or interest from the location of such public road or street shall be considered. Such consequential benefits, if any, may be offset against such consequential damages, if any; but in no event shall consequential benefits be offset against the value of the property or interest actually taken for such public improvement.

History Code 1933, § 36-1117, enacted by Ga. L. 1966, p. 320, § 1; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 22/HB 142.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1933, § 36-1117, enacted by Ga. L. 1966, p. 320, § 1; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 22/HB 142.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-138">
          <num>22-2-138</num>
          <heading>Scope of award or verdict; molding of award or verdict; power of court to adjudge condemnation of title upon deposit of amount of award or verdict into court; disposition of award by court</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-138. Scope of award or verdict; molding of award or verdict; power of court to adjudge condemnation of title upon deposit of amount of award or verdict into court; disposition of award by court
The award or verdict, as the case may be, shall have respect either to the entire and unencumbered fee or to any separate claim against or interest in the property, as the court may order. The award or verdict may be molded under the direction of the court so as to do complete justice and avoid confusion of interests. It shall be within the power of the court, upon payment of the award or verdict into the registry of the court, to adjudge a condemnation of the title to the property or interest therein and give such direction as to the disposition of the fund as shall be proper, according to the rights of the several respondents, and to cause such pleadings to be filed and such issues to be made as shall be appropriate for an ascertainment and determination of such rights.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 5; Code 1933, § 36-1111.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 5; Code 1933, § 36-1111.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-139">
          <num>22-2-139</num>
          <heading>Right of interested persons to intervene; effect of subsequent proceedings on rights of condemnor</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-139. Right of interested persons to intervene; effect of subsequent proceedings on rights of condemnor
Nothing in this article which refers to any ruling or order, or time for responding thereto, shall be held or construed to exclude any person by way of default from making known his rights or claims in the property or interest or in the fund arising therefrom. Any person making any such claim may file appropriate pleadings or intervention at any time before verdict or award, and such person shall be fully heard thereon. If any person after judgment of condemnation desires to come in and be heard on any such claim, he shall be allowed to do so. After condemnation is had and the fund paid into the registry of the court, the condemnor shall not be concerned with or affected by any subsequent proceedings unless upon appeal from the verdict or award as provided in Code Section 22-2-136.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 7; Code 1933, § 36-1113.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 7; Code 1933, § 36-1113.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-140">
          <num>22-2-140</num>
          <heading>Notification of court by tax collector or tax commissioner of taxes due on property or interest; actions by court to discharge lien</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-140. Notification of court by tax collector or tax commissioner of taxes due on property or interest; actions by court to discharge lien
It shall be the duty of any tax collector or tax commissioner notified as required in Code Section 22-2-134 to make known to the court in writing the taxes due on the property or interest; and the court shall give such direction as will satisfy the tax liability and discharge the lien thereon.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 8; Code 1933, § 36-1114.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 8; Code 1933, § 36-1114.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-141">
          <num>22-2-141</num>
          <heading>Filing and recording of award, decree, and description of condemned property or interest or copies thereof; payment of fees to clerk of superior court</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-141. Filing and recording of award, decree, and description of condemned property or interest or copies thereof; payment of fees to clerk of superior court
When the condemnation is fully completed, the award, whether made by assessors or by the verdict of a jury, together with the decree of the court based thereon and a full and complete description of the property or interest condemned or duly certified copies of such award, decree, and description, shall be filed and recorded in the records of deeds in the office of the clerk of the superior court of the county where the land so condemned lies. If the land lies in more than one county, such filing and recording shall be made in each county in which the land lies. The clerk shall be entitled to the same fees for such filing and recording as are allowed by law for the filing and recording of deeds, said fees to be paid by the party in whose favor said condemnation is had.

History Ga. L. 1919, p. 231, § 1; Code 1933, § 36-1116.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1919, p. 231, § 1; Code 1933, § 36-1116.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-2-142">
          <num>22-2-142</num>
          <heading>Intent of article regarding effect on other methods of condemnation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-2-142. Intent of article regarding effect on other methods of condemnation
This article is intended to be supplementary to and cumulative of Articles 1 and 2 of this chapter in cases in which the State of Georgia, the United States, or any person having the privilege of exercising the right of eminent domain is concerned. This article is also intended to make simpler and more effective the method of condemnation in those cases where conflicting interests or doubtful questions render a judicial supervision of the procedure desirable. In all particulars not otherwise specially provided for in this article, the court shall conform its procedure as nearly as possible to Articles 1 and 2 of this chapter, and the same shall remain in force.

History Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 9; Code 1933, § 36-1115; Ga. L. 1937-38, Ex. Sess., p. 251, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1914, p. 92, § 9; Code 1933, § 36-1115; Ga. L. 1937-38, Ex. Sess., p. 251, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_22-3">
        <num>Chapter 3</num>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-1">
          <num>22-3-1</num>
          <heading>Direction and contents of notice of condemnation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-1. Direction and contents of notice of condemnationWhen a telegraph or telephone company undertakes to condemn so much of the right of way of a railroad company as may be necessary for the purpose of constructing, maintaining, and operating its telegraph or telephone lines along and upon such right of way, the notice of condemnation provided for in Code Section 22-2-26 shall be directed to the railroad company and shall:
(1)  Set out the manner in which the telegraph or telephone company proposes to construct its lines on the right of way of the railroad company;

(2)  Fix the time when the hearing shall be had;

(3)  Give the name of the assessor selected by the telegraph or telephone company; and

(4)  Request the railroad company to select an assessor.

History Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5236; Code 1933, § 36-701.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5236; Code 1933, § 36-701.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-2">
          <num>22-3-2</num>
          <heading>Manner of service of notice</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-2. Manner of service of notice
Notice of condemnation shall be served upon the railroad company in the manner provided for the service of other actions upon railroad companies. It shall not be necessary to serve such notice upon any person or corporation other than the railroad company in possession of and operating the railroad whose right of way is sought to be condemned by the telegraph or telephone company for its use; and only the interest of such railroad company so served shall be affected by the proceedings.

History Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5237; Code 1933, § 36-702.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5237; Code 1933, § 36-702.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-3">
          <num>22-3-3</num>
          <heading>Necessity for only one proceeding; location of proceedings; form of assessors' findings</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-3. Necessity for only one proceeding; location of proceedings; form of assessors' findings
There need be but one condemnation proceeding against the same railroad company, which proceeding may be conducted in any county where service can be made upon the company as provided in Code Section 22-3-2. However, if the railroad company has a main or principal office located in this state, the proceeding shall be conducted in the county in which the main or principal office is located. The assessors shall make their findings of the damages to which the railroad company may be entitled by reason of the construction, maintenance, and operation of the telegraph or telephone lines in the manner set out in the notice.

History Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5238; Code 1933, § 36-703.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5238; Code 1933, § 36-703.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-4">
          <num>22-3-4</num>
          <heading>Location of hearing before assessors; evidence upon which findings may be based</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-4. Location of hearing before assessors; evidence upon which findings may be based
The hearing may be conducted in the office of the judge of the probate court of the county in which the condemnation proceedings are had or at such other place as the assessors may fix. In assessing the damages to the railroad company, the assessors need not go upon or inspect the premises sought to be condemned, but they shall make their findings upon the testimony heard by them.

History Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5239; Code 1933, § 36-704.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1898, p. 54, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5239; Code 1933, § 36-704.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-60">
          <num>22-3-60</num>
          <heading>Authority to lease, purchase, or condemn property or receive donations for waterworks and sewage systems</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-60. Authority to lease, purchase, or condemn property or receive donations for waterworks and sewage systems
Any nongovernmental entity constructing, owning, or operating any waterworks or sanitary sewerage system, or both, in this state shall have the right, power, privilege, and authority to lease, purchase, or condemn property or any interest therein, including easements, or to receive donations or grants of property or any interest therein, including easements, for the purpose of constructing and operating a waterworks, a water distribution system, a sewerage collection system, or a sewage treatment and disposal system, or any combination of such systems or facilities; provided, however, that prior to condemning property in any political subdivision, any such entity shall first obtain the consent of the governing authority of such political subdivision after the requirements of Code Section 22-1-10 have been satisfied. Consent shall be granted by resolution or ordinance.

History Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 2407; Civil Code 1910, § 2923; Code 1933, § 36-901; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 16/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 2407; Civil Code 1910, § 2923; Code 1933, § 36-901; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 16/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-61">
          <num>22-3-61</num>
          <heading>Condemnation procedure</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-61. Condemnation procedure
If a person seeking to exercise the power of eminent domain under this article fails to procure, by contract, title to the land necessary or proper for the construction and successful operation of a waterworks or sanitary sewerage system, or both, and the parties cannot agree upon the damage done, the same shall be assessed as provided in Chapter 2 of this title.

History Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 2; Civil Code 1895, § 2408; Civil Code 1910, § 2924; Code 1933, § 36-902; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 2; Civil Code 1895, § 2408; Civil Code 1910, § 2924; Code 1933, § 36-902; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-62">
          <num>22-3-62</num>
          <heading>Applicability of article</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-62. Applicability of article
The powers granted by this article shall apply to those persons who have entered into a contract with the proper authorities for supplying water for public purposes and to such persons providing water or sanitary sewerage services through water or sanitary sewerage systems, or both, which have been permitted by the Environmental Protection Division of the Department of Natural Resources.

History Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 3; Civil Code 1895, § 2409; Civil Code 1910, § 2925; Code 1933, § 36-903; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1889, p. 184, § 3; Civil Code 1895, § 2409; Civil Code 1910, § 2925; Code 1933, § 36-903; Ga. L. 1990, p. 731, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-63">
          <num>22-3-63</num>
          <heading>Authority to condemn property for purpose of constructing a waterworks, water distribution system, sewage collection system, or sewage treatment and disposal system</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-63. Authority to condemn property for purpose of constructing a waterworks, water distribution system, sewage collection system, or sewage treatment and disposal systemAny other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, any nongovernmental entity which:
(1)  Is privately owned and is operated under the collective management and control of the owners;

(2)  Was in the business of providing water supply and sewerage collection and disposal prior to July 1, 1978;

(3)  Has continuously owned a sanitary sewerage system since July 1, 1978, permitted by the Environmental Protection Division of the Department of Natural Resources; and

(4)  On May 1, 2000, owns and operates one or more sewerage collection treatment and disposal systems serving 1,000 or more customers

shall have the authority to condemn property or any interest therein, including easements, for the purpose of constructing and operating a waterworks, a water distribution system, a sewerage collection system, or a sewage treatment and disposal system, or any combination of such systems or facilities; provided, however, that such authority shall obtain the consent of the governing authority of the county or municipality that controls the land sought to be condemned in accordance with Code Section 22-3-60. The authority granted by this Code section shall extend only to such counties and those counties immediately adjacent to such counties in which such entity owned or operated such waterworks or systems or combination as of January 1, 2000; and provided, further, that the authority provided for in this Code section shall terminate with respect to any entity if any interest in such business is transferred to another person or entity except through inheritance.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-63, enacted by Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 16/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-63, enacted by Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 16/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-80">
          <num>22-3-80</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-80. DefinitionsAs used in this article, the term:
(1)  "Existing petroleum pipeline" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(2)  "Expansion" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(3)  "Extension" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(4)  "Maintenance" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(5)  "New petroleum pipeline" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(6)  "Parallel petroleum pipeline" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(7)  "Petroleum pipeline" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

(8)  "Petroleum pipeline company" shall have the same meaning as set forth in Code Section 12-17-1.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-80, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-80, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-81">
          <num>22-3-81</num>
          <heading>Right to acquire property or property interests by eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-81. Right to acquire property or property interests by eminent domain
Subject to the provisions, conditions, and restrictions of this article, petroleum pipeline companies are granted the power to acquire property or interests in property by eminent domain for the purpose of an expansion, an extension, maintenance, or construction of a new petroleum pipeline.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-81, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-81, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-82">
          <num>22-3-82</num>
          <heading>General certificate and permitting requirements</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-3-82. General certificate and permitting requirements</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-82__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A petroleum pipeline company shall not exercise the power of eminent domain granted in Code Section 22-3-81 for the purpose of constructing a new petroleum pipeline or for an extension unless and until a certificate of public convenience and necessity is issued by the commissioner of transportation as provided in Code Section 22-3-83 and a permit is issued by the director of the Environmental Protection Division of the Department of Natural Resources as provided in Chapter 17 of Title 12.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-82__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No certificate of public convenience and necessity or permit as provided in Code Section 22-3-83 shall be required of a petroleum pipeline company that is:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-82__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not exercising the power of eminent domain to acquire property; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-82__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Exercising the power of eminent domain for the purpose of maintenance or expansion.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-82, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-82, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-83">
          <num>22-3-83</num>
          <heading>Certificate of public convenience and necessity; requirements</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-3-83. Certificate of public convenience and necessity; requirements</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or after July 1, 2017, a petroleum pipeline company desiring to use the power of eminent domain granted under this article to acquire property for a new petroleum pipeline or an extension shall be required to obtain a certificate of public convenience and necessity from the commissioner of transportation as provided in this Code section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity shall contain, at a minimum:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the proposed project together with its siting information, including, but not limited to, a map showing the proposed location of the route of the new petroleum pipeline or of the proposed extension;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the public convenience and necessity that support the proposed location of the route of the new petroleum pipeline or of the proposed extension;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The width of the proposed petroleum pipeline corridor up to a maximum width of one-third mile;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A showing that the use of the power of eminent domain may be necessary for construction of the new petroleum pipeline or for the proposed extension;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A showing that the public convenience and necessity for the petroleum pipeline justifies the use of the power of eminent domain; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_b__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other information that the Department of Transportation may require by rules and regulations.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within ten days of applying for a certificate of public convenience and necessity, the applicant shall provide:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_c__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Public notice in the legal organ of each county through which the proposed route of the new petroleum pipeline or of the extension is to be located; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Written notice of the filing of an application under this Code section to all landowners whose property is located within the proposed route of the new petroleum pipeline or of the extension. Such notice shall be delivered to each landowner and contain the following language in boldface type:
   "YOUR PROPERTY IS LOCATED WITHIN THE PROPOSED ROUTE OF A PETROLEUM PIPELINE FOR WHICH AN APPLICATION FOR A CERTIFICATE OF PUBLIC CONVENIENCE AND NECESSITY HAS BEEN FILED PURSUANT TO ARTICLE 4 OF CHAPTER 3 OF TITLE 22 OF THE OFFICIAL CODE OF GEORGIA ANNOTATED. SAID ARTICLE ALONG WITH CHAPTER 17 OF TITLE 12 OF THE OFFICIAL CODE OF GEORGIA ANNOTATED PROVIDE SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS WHICH MUST BE FOLLOWED BY PETROLEUM PIPELINE COMPANIES BEFORE THEY MAY BUILD A NEW PETROLEUM PIPELINE OR MODIFY AN EXISTING PETROLEUM PIPELINE. THESE PROVISIONS OF THE OFFICIAL CODE OF GEORGIA ANNOTATED ALSO PROVIDE SPECIFIC RIGHTS FOR YOUR PROTECTION. YOU SHOULD FAMILIARIZE YOURSELF WITH THOSE REQUIREMENTS AND YOUR RIGHTS."</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p/>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_d__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In making a decision as to whether to grant a certificate of public convenience and necessity, the commissioner of transportation shall consider the following:
(A)  Whether existing petroleum pipelines or distribution systems are adequate to meet the reasonable public needs;

(B)  The volume of demand for such petroleum, and whether such demand and that reasonably to be anticipated in the future can support already existing petroleum pipelines and distribution systems, if any, and also the petroleum pipeline or distribution system proposed by the applicant;

(C)  The financial ability of the applicant to furnish adequate continuous service and to meet the financial obligations of the service which the applicant proposes to perform;

(D)  The adequacy of the supply of petroleum to serve the public;

(E)  The economic feasibility of the petroleum pipeline or distribution system and the propriety of the engineering and contracting fees, the expenses, and the financing charges and costs connected with the petroleum pipeline or distribution system; and(F)  The effect on existing revenues and service of other petroleum pipelines or distribution systems, and particularly whether the granting of such certificate of public convenience and necessity will or may seriously impair existing public service.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_d__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>This subsection shall not be construed as exhaustively describing all factors which the commissioner of transportation may consider in his or her decision to grant or deny a certificate of public convenience and necessity.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant shall bear the burden of proof to demonstrate that the commissioner of transportation should issue a certificate of public convenience and necessity as provided under this Code section. The decision to issue or deny a certificate of public convenience and necessity shall be based on the record before the commissioner of transportation, which shall include, but not be limited to, the applicant's submissions, any documents submitted to the Department of Transportation pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section, and research the commissioner of transportation may conduct in analyzing the application.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The issuance or denial of a certificate of public convenience and necessity may be reviewed by a judge of the superior court of the county in which the pipeline company has an agent and place of doing business. The review shall be by petition filed within 30 days of the date of approval or disapproval of the application and shall be determined on the basis of the record before the commissioner of transportation. The action of the commissioner of transportation shall be affirmed if supported by substantial evidence.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p/>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_g__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No later than July 1, 2018, the Department of Transportation shall, pursuant to Chapter 13 of Title 50, the "Georgia Administrative Procedure Act," promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary and reasonable for purposes of enforcement of this Code section, which shall include, but may not be limited to:
(A)  The submission of an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity and provisions for the application review process, not to exceed 120 days in length;

(B)  Provisions for a nonrefundable application fee which shall be sufficient to defray the administrative costs of review of the application by the Department of Transportation;

(C)  Reasonable public notice of the filing of an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity to a landowner who, after reasonable efforts, cannot personally be given the notice required in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section; and(D)  Provisions for public meetings to be held prior to any action on any certificates of public convenience and necessity.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-83__subsec_c__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No certificate of public convenience and necessity shall be granted by the commissioner of transportation prior to the promulgation of rules and regulations as provided for in this subsection; provided, however, that once such rules and regulations have been promulgated and applications are accepted for filing, if any application is not approved or is denied within 120 days of the date such application is filed with the Department of Transportation under this Code section, the application shall be deemed to be approved by operation of law.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-83, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-83, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-84">
          <num>22-3-84</num>
          <heading>Notice to landowner</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-84. Notice to landowner

Prior to initiating eminent domain proceedings or threatening to do so, the petroleum pipeline company shall cause to be delivered to each landowner whose property may be condemned a written notice containing the following language in boldface type:

"CHAPTER 17  OF TITLE 12 AND ARTICLE 4 OF CHAPTER 3 OF TITLE 22 OF THE OFFICIAL CODE OF GEORGIA ANNOTATED PROVIDE SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS WHICH MUST BE FOLLOWED BY PETROLEUM PIPELINE COMPANIES BEFORE THEY MAY EXERCISE THE RIGHT TO CONDEMN YOUR PROPERTY. THOSE PROVISIONS OF THE OFFICIAL CODE OF GEORGIA ANNOTATED ALSO PROVIDE SPECIFIC RIGHTS FOR YOUR PROTECTION. YOU SHOULD FAMILIARIZE YOURSELF WITH THOSE REQUIREMENTS AND YOUR RIGHTS PRIOR TO CONTINUING NEGOTIATIONS CONCERNING THE SALE OF YOUR PROPERTY TO A PETROLEUM PIPELINE COMPANY."

History Code 1981, § 22-3-84, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-84, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-85">
          <num>22-3-85</num>
          <heading>Use of condemnation procedures</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-85. Use of condemnation procedures
When a petroleum pipeline company that has met all the requirements of this article is unable to acquire the property or interest required for the purpose of an expansion, an extension, maintenance, or construction of a new petroleum pipeline, after reasonable negotiation with the owner of such property or interest, the petroleum pipeline company may acquire such property or interest by the use of the condemnation procedures authorized by Chapter 2 of this title.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-85, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-85, enacted by Ga. L. 2017, p. 744, § 2/HB 413; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 22/HB 323.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-95">
          <num>22-3-95</num>
          <heading>Eminent domain use by natural gas transporters or distributors</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-95. Eminent domain use by natural gas transporters or distributors
The power of eminent domain may be exercised by persons who are or may be engaged in constructing or operating pipelines for the transportation or distribution of natural or artificial gas and by persons who are or may be engaged in furnishing natural or artificial gas for heating, lighting, or power purposes in this state.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-95, enacted by Ga. L. 2016, p. 744, § 2/HB 1036.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-95, enacted by Ga. L. 2016, p. 744, § 2/HB 1036.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-100">
          <num>22-3-100</num>
          <heading>Authority of counties to exercise power of eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-100. Authority of counties to exercise power of eminent domainEvery county of the State of Georgia may exercise the power of eminent domain for the purpose of taking and acquiring the property or other interests necessary:
(1)  To enable the county to institute and to accomplish the completion of small watershed projects, works of improvements for watersheds, and projects for watershed protection and flood control and prevention under any applicable Act of the State of Georgia or act of the United States;

(2)  For certain public parks, playgrounds, recreation centers, or other recreational facilities to be developed in connection with the development or construction of any small watershed project, any project for watershed protection or flood control and prevention, or works of improvements for watersheds; and

(3)  To allow for ways of ingress to and egress from any and all such watershed projects, improvements of watershed projects, projects for watershed protection and flood control and prevention, and public parks, playgrounds, recreation centers, or other recreational facilities.

History Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, §§ 1-3.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, §§ 1-3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-101">
          <num>22-3-101</num>
          <heading>Condemnation procedure</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-101. Condemnation procedure
For the purposes designated in Code Section 22-3-100, every county of the State of Georgia may proceed to condemn the necessary property or other interest in accordance with the procedures set forth by the pertinent eminent domain statutes of this state and in accordance with all existing laws applicable to the condemnation of private property for public use, including Article 2 of Chapter 2 of this title.

History Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, § 4.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, § 4.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-102">
          <num>22-3-102</num>
          <heading>Requirement of condemnation of fee simple title to land to be flooded permanently</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-102. Requirement of condemnation of fee simple title to land to be flooded permanently
In any proceeding under this article, the condemnor shall be required to condemn the fee simple title to all land not otherwise acquired which will be covered by permanent flooding.

History Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, § 5.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1964, p. 234, § 5.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-120">
          <num>22-3-120</num>
          <heading>Condemnation for construction of lighthouses, beacons, etc</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-120. Condemnation for construction of lighthouses, beacons, etc
In any county in which the United States government authorizes the construction of lighthouses, beacons, range lights, or any other structure designed to assist the navigation of the waters of this state, any proper agency of the United States and the mayor of any city in that county shall mark out, by metes and bounds, the property necessary to be taken and shall convey to the owner of the property or of any interest therein notice of the planned construction. If the agency of the United States and the owner cannot agree on the compensation to be paid for taking the land, the Governor shall appoint one person and the owner of the land another; and these two shall select a third person. The three persons so selected shall constitute a commission to assess the just and adequate compensation to be paid according to the general method of condemning land provided in Article 1 of Chapter 2 of this title.

History Ga. L. 1882-83, p. 118, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 26; Civil Code 1910, § 27; Code 1933, § 36-1101.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1882-83, p. 118, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 26; Civil Code 1910, § 27; Code 1933, § 36-1101.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-121">
          <num>22-3-121</num>
          <heading>Acquisition of right to enter lands and clear or cut timber for purposes of carrying out survey of coasts -- Generally</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-121. Acquisition of right to enter lands and clear or cut timber for purposes of carrying out survey of coasts -- Generally
Any person employed under the act of the Congress of the United States providing for a survey of the coasts may enter upon lands within this state and clear or cut timber upon the same for any purpose legitimately connected with and necessary to carry out the survey, provided that no unnecessary injury be done thereby and all damages to the owner of the land be promptly paid.

History Laws 1847, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 155; Code 1863, § 25; Code 1868, § 23; Code 1873, § 23; Code 1882, § 23; Civil Code 1895, § 27; Civil Code 1910, § 28; Code 1933, § 36-1102.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1847, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 155; Code 1863, § 25; Code 1868, § 23; Code 1873, § 23; Code 1882, § 23; Civil Code 1895, § 27; Civil Code 1910, § 28; Code 1933, § 36-1102.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-122">
          <num>22-3-122</num>
          <heading>Acquisition of right to enter lands and clear or cut timber for purposes of carrying out survey of coasts -- Manner of assessment where parties cannot agree on compensation</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-122. Acquisition of right to enter lands and clear or cut timber for purposes of carrying out survey of coasts -- Manner of assessment where parties cannot agree on compensation
If the parties representing the government of the United States and the owner of the property or of any interest therein pursuant to Code Section 22-3-121 cannot agree upon the amount of compensation to be paid for the property, the damages shall be assessed as provided in this title.

History Laws 1847, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 155; Code 1863, § 26; Code 1868, § 24; Code 1873, § 24; Code 1882, § 24; Civil Code 1895, § 28; Civil Code 1910, § 29; Code 1933, § 36-1103.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Laws 1847, Cobb's 1851 Digest, p. 155; Code 1863, § 26; Code 1868, § 24; Code 1873, § 24; Code 1882, § 24; Civil Code 1895, § 28; Civil Code 1910, § 29; Code 1933, § 36-1103.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-140">
          <num>22-3-140</num>
          <heading>Authorization to utilize the declaration of taking method of eminent domain</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-140. Authorization to utilize the declaration of taking method of eminent domain
Any state agency, political subdivision of the state, county, or municipality owning or operating a sewage collection, treatment, or disposal system, a water or waste-water system, a gas or gas line system, an electrical or electrical line system, or a drain or storm-water system is authorized to utilize the declaration of taking method of eminent domain in order to acquire any private property in fee simple or in any lesser interest, including easements, for such systems and purposes, as such method of eminent domain is provided in Article 1 of Chapter 3 of Title 32. This article and method of eminent domain shall be supplementary to and cumulative of the methods of procedure for the exercise of the power of eminent domain prescribed in this title.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-140, enacted by Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 3.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-140, enacted by Ga. L. 2000, p. 1514, § 3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-160">
          <num>22-3-160</num>
          <heading>"Utility" defined</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-3-160. "Utility" defined
As used in this article, the term "utility" means a person, corporation, or other entity that generates, transmits, distributes, supplies, or sells electricity for public or private use in this state or generates electricity in this state for transmission or distribution outside this state.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-160, enacted by Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-160, enacted by Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-160.1">
          <num>22-3-160.1</num>
          <heading>Public hearings required; exception to hearing requirement</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-3-160.1. Public hearings required; exception to hearing requirement</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before exercising the right of eminent domain for purposes of constructing or expanding an electric transmission line with a design operating voltage of 115 kilovolts or greater and a length of one mile or more, any utility shall schedule and hold one or more public meetings with an opportunity for comment by members of the public. In any proceeding to exercise the right of eminent domain for purposes of an electric transmission line for which the utility began land acquisition negotiations on or after July 1, 2004, the utility shall be required to demonstrate substantial compliance with this Code section as a condition for exercising the right of eminent domain.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior to the public meeting or meetings required by this Code section, the utility shall provide adequate public notice of the utility's intent to construct or expand an electric transmission line and adequate public notice of the public meeting or meetings related to the electric transmission line as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By publishing adequate public notice of said public meeting or meetings in a newspaper of general circulation in each county in which any portion of the electric transmission line is to be constructed or expanded. Said notice shall be published at least 30 days prior to the date of the first public meeting related to the electric transmission line and shall include the following: the date, time, and location of each meeting; a statement that the purpose of the meeting or meetings is to provide public notice of the utility's intent to construct or expand an electric transmission line for which the right of eminent domain may be exercised; a description of the proposed project including the general route of the electric transmission line and the general property area within which the utility intends to construct or expand the electric transmission line; the width of the proposed transmission line route; and a description of the alternative construction approaches considered by the utility and a statement of why such alternatives were rejected by the utility; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By providing written notice of the public meeting or meetings, by means of certified mail, to each owner of property, as indicated in the tax records of the county in which such property is located, over which the utility intends to construct or expand the electric transmission line and to the chairpersons or chief executives of the counties and the mayors of any municipalities in which such property is located. Such notice shall be mailed at least 30 days prior to the date of the first public meeting related to the electric transmission line and shall include all of the information required by paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At least one public meeting shall be held in each county in which the electric transmission line would be located. In any county in which the electric transmission line would require acquisition of property rights from more than 50 property owners, two or more public meetings shall be held. The public meetings shall be held in an accessible location and shall be open to members of the public. At least one of the public meetings shall commence between 6:00 P.M. and 7:00 P.M., inclusive, on a business weekday. At the public meetings, the utility shall provide a description of the proposed project including the general route of the electric transmission line and the general property area within which the utility intends to construct or expand the electric transmission line, the width of the proposed transmission line route, and a description of the alternative construction approaches considered by the utility and a statement of why such alternatives were rejected by the utility. At the public meetings, the utility shall allow a reasonable opportunity for members of the public to express their views on the proposed project and to ask questions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A utility shall not be required to give notice of or hold public meetings with respect to any of the following:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line to be constructed or expanded by a utility on an established right of way or land that was acquired by the utility or any other utility prior to July 1, 2004;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line for which the utility began land acquisition negotiations prior to July 1, 2004;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line to be constructed or expanded by a utility on an established right of way or land that is owned or controlled by a state agency, a county, a municipality, or an agency, bureau, or department of the United States;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line to be constructed or expanded by a utility for the purpose of relocating an existing electric transmission line at the direction, order, or request of a state agency, a county, a municipality, or an agency, bureau, or department of the United States;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line to be constructed or expanded by a utility without exercising the power of eminent domain to acquire the right of way or easement area for such line; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-160.1__subsec_d__para_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An electric transmission line to be constructed by a utility for the purpose of serving an electric substation or switching station to be constructed on a site that is owned or controlled by a utility customer to be served by such substation or switching station.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-160, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2; Code 1981, § 22-3-160.1, as redesignated by Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-160, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2; Code 1981, § 22-3-160.1, as redesignated by Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-161">
          <num>22-3-161</num>
          <heading>Selection of route for electric transmission line; settlement negotiations with property owners</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-3-161. Selection of route for electric transmission line; settlement negotiations with property owners</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On and after July 1, 2004, before exercising the right of eminent domain for purposes of constructing or expanding an electric transmission line described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Code Section 22-3-160.1, the utility shall select a practical and feasible route for the location of the electric transmission line. In selecting the route for the location of the electric transmission line, the utility shall consider existing land uses in the geographic area where the line is to be located, existing corridors, existing environmental conditions in the area, engineering practices related to the construction and operation of the line, and costs related to the construction, operation, and maintenance of the line.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After the utility has selected the preferred route for the location of an electric transmission line, the utility shall attempt in good faith to negotiate a settlement with each property owner from whom the utility needs to acquire property rights for the line. In connection with the negotiations, the utility shall provide the property owner with a written offer to purchase the property rights, a document that describes the property rights, and a drawing that shows the location of the line on the owner's property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The requirements of subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section shall not apply to an electric transmission line described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-161__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Code Section 22-3-160.1.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-161, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2; Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-161, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2; Ga. L. 2005, p. 60, § 22/HB 95.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-3-162">
          <num>22-3-162</num>
          <heading>Application; additional compensation or reconveyance</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-3-162. Application; additional compensation or reconveyance</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Code section shall apply to any easement or other property interest acquired on or after July 1, 2004, through exercise of the right of eminent domain for purposes of constructing or expanding an electric transmission line:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With a capacity of 230 kilovolts or less if the utility has not begun such construction or expansion within 12 years from the date of acquisition and the land burdened by the easement or other property interest is not adjacent to an electric transmission line corridor in existence 12 years from the date of acquisition;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With a capacity of more than 230 kilovolts if the utility has not begun such construction or expansion within 15 years from the date of acquisition and the land burdened by the easement or other property interest is not adjacent to an electric transmission line corridor in existence 15 years from the date of acquisition; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Of any capacity if the land burdened by the easement or other property interest is adjacent to an electric transmission line corridor in existence 15 years after the date of acquisition and the utility has not begun the construction or expansion for which the easement or other property right was acquired within 15 years from the date of acquisition.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When this Code section becomes applicable to an easement or other property interest, the owner of the land burdened by such easement or property interest may apply to the utility that acquired the easement or other property interest or such utility's successor or assign for reconveyance or quitclaim of the easement or other property interest or for additional compensation for such easement or other property interest. The application shall be in writing, and the utility or its successor or assign shall act on the application within 60 days by:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_b__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Executing a reconveyance or quitclaim of the easement or property interest upon receipt of compensation not to exceed the amount of the compensation paid by the utility for the easement or property interest at the time of acquisition; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_b__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Paying additional compensation to the owner of the land burdened by the easement or other property interest, such compensation to be calculated by subtracting the price paid by the utility for the easement or other property interest at the time of acquisition from the fair market value of the easement or other property interest at the time this Code section becomes applicable to such easement or other property interest.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-3-162__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The choice between additional compensation or reconveyance or quitclaim shall be at the discretion of the utility or its successor or assign.

History Code 1981, § 22-3-162, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-3-162, enacted by Ga. L. 2004, p. 568, § 2.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
      <chapter eId="chp_22-4">
        <num>Chapter 4</num>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-1">
          <num>22-4-1</num>
          <heading>Short title; "Uniform Act" defined</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-4-1. Short title; "Uniform Act" defined</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This chapter shall be known as "The Georgia Relocation Assistance and Land Acquisition Policy Act."</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this chapter, the term "Uniform Act" means the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970, as amended by the Uniform Relocation Act Amendments of 1987, Title IV of Public Law 100-17.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-2">
          <num>22-4-2</num>
          <heading>Legislative findings and declaration of necessity</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-2. Legislative findings and declaration of necessity
The General Assembly finds and declares that the prompt and equitable relocation and reestablishment of persons, businesses, farmers, and nonprofit organizations displaced when the state, any of its agencies or institutions (other than the Department of Transportation), or any county, municipal corporation, school district, political subdivision, public authority, public agency, public corporation, or public instrumentality, excluding electric membership corporations as defined in paragraph (3) of Code Section 46-3-171, (collectively referred to in this chapter as "several public entities") created under the Constitution and laws of the State of Georgia acquires land, with federal financial assistance, for a public use, are necessary to ensure that certain individuals do not suffer disproportionate injuries as a result of programs designed for the benefit of the public as a whole. The General Assembly finds and declares that the establishment of uniform fair land acquisition policies will be beneficial to the public. The General Assembly finds that the Congress of the United States has, by enacting the Uniform Act, made funds available for relocation assistance and the implementation of certain land acquisition policies. The General Assembly further finds that the Congress of the United States has by the aforesaid statute provided for the total cessation after July 1, 1972, of federal financial assistance for public works projects which will displace persons or businesses unless the state complies with the requirements of the Uniform Act. The General Assembly finds and declares that the construction of public works projects with federal financial assistance is vital to the state and is in the best interest of the people of the state and that providing for the continuation of federal financial assistance at the highest possible level for public works projects is a legitimate public purpose. The General Assembly further finds that the cost of providing the assistance and services provided for in this chapter should be, and the same are declared to be, part of the necessary cost of federal-aid public works projects.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 2; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 8, § 22.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 2; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 8, § 22.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-3">
          <num>22-4-3</num>
          <heading>Applicability of Code Section 22-1-1 to chapter</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-3. Applicability of Code Section 22-1-1 to chapter
The definitions contained in paragraphs (6) and (8) of Code Section 22-1-1 shall not apply to this chapter.

History Code 1981, § 22-4-3, Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 17/HB 1313.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-4-3, Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 17/HB 1313.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-4">
          <num>22-4-4</num>
          <heading>Payments by public entities for relocation and replacement housing expenses</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-4. Payments by public entities for relocation and replacement housing expenses
The several public entities are authorized to and shall make or approve the payments required by Section 210 of the Uniform Act for the relocation expenses and replacement housing expenses of any person, family, business, farm operation, or nonprofit organization displaced by federal-aid projects in the state, the costs of which are now or hereafter financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to any of the several public entities.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 3; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 3.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 3; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 3.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-5">
          <num>22-4-5</num>
          <heading>Providing of relocation assistance advisory services by public entities</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-5. Providing of relocation assistance advisory services by public entities
The several public entities are authorized to and shall provide the relocation assistance advisory services required by Section 205 of the Uniform Act for any person, family, business, farm operation, or nonprofit organization displaced by federal-aid projects in the state, the costs of which are now or hereafter financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to any of the several public entities.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 4; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 4.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 4; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 4.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-6">
          <num>22-4-6</num>
          <heading>Payments by public entities for expenses incidental to property transfer, for mortgage penalties, and for property taxes</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-6. Payments by public entities for expenses incidental to property transfer, for mortgage penalties, and for property taxes
The several public entities are authorized to and shall make or approve the payments required by Section 305(2) of the Uniform Act for expenses incidental to the transfer of real property acquired by any of the several public entities, for prepayment of mortgage penalties, and for a pro rata portion of real property taxes on real property acquired by any of the several public entities from any person, family, business, farm operation, or nonprofit organization displaced by federal-aid projects in the state, the costs of which are now or hereafter financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to any of the several public entities.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 5; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 5.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 5; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 5.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-7">
          <num>22-4-7</num>
          <heading>Payments by state, public agencies, etc., for litigation expenses -- Condemnation proceedings</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-7. Payments by state, public agencies, etc., for litigation expenses -- Condemnation proceedings
The several public entities are authorized to and shall make or approve the payments required by Section 305(2) of the Uniform Act for litigation expenses actually incurred by any person, family, business, farm operation, or nonprofit organization which is a condemnee in any condemnation proceeding brought by an acquiring public entity to acquire real property for a federal-aid project, the cost of which is now or hereafter financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to an acquiring public entity, if the final judgment is that the acquiring public entity cannot acquire the real property by condemnation or the condemnation proceeding is formally abandoned by the acquiring public entity.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 6; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 6.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 6; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 6.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-8">
          <num>22-4-8</num>
          <heading>Payments by public entities for litigation expenses -- Inverse condemnation proceedings</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-8. Payments by public entities for litigation expenses -- Inverse condemnation proceedings
The several public entities are authorized to and shall make or approve the payments required by Section 305(2) of the Uniform Act for litigation expenses actually incurred by any person, family, business, farm operation, or nonprofit organization which is the plaintiff in any inverse condemnation proceeding brought against an acquiring public entity in which judgment is rendered in favor of the plaintiff for real property taken by the acquiring public entity in its execution of any federal-aid project, the costs of which are now or hereafter financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to the acquiring public entity.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 7; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 7.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 7; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 7.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-9">
          <num>22-4-9</num>
          <heading>Policies guiding acquisition of real property for federal-aid projects</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-9. Policies guiding acquisition of real property for federal-aid projects
In acquiring real property for any federal-aid project, the costs of which are financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to an acquiring public entity, such public entity shall be guided by the land acquisition policies required by Section 301 of the Uniform Act to the greatest extent practicable.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 8; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 8.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 8; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 8.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-10">
          <num>22-4-10</num>
          <heading>Policies guiding acquisition of buildings, structures, and other improvements for federal-aid projects</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-10. Policies guiding acquisition of buildings, structures, and other improvements for federal-aid projects
In acquiring property for any federal-aid project, the costs of which are financed in whole or in part from federal funds allocated to an acquiring public entity, the acquiring public entity shall be guided by the land acquisition policies relating to buildings, structures, and other improvements specified by Section (302) of the Uniform Act to the greatest extent practicable.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 9; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 9; Ga. L. 1990, p. 8, § 22.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 9; Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 9; Ga. L. 1990, p. 8, § 22.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-11">
          <num>22-4-11</num>
          <heading>Adoption of rules by state, public agencies, etc.; appeal and review</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-4-11. Adoption of rules by state, public agencies, etc.; appeal and review</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-11__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The several public entities are authorized to make such rules as may be necessary to provide for the administration of the financial assistance authorized by this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-11__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The determination by the several public entities of the amount of any payment and to whom it shall be paid may be appealed and judicially reviewed in the manner prescribed by Chapter 13 of Title 50, the "Georgia Administrative Procedure Act."

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 11.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 11.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-11.1">
          <num>22-4-11.1</num>
          <heading>Exercise of powers granted under this chapter by municipal corporations with population of 350,000 or more; effect of this Code section on other laws</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-4-11.1. Exercise of powers granted under this chapter by municipal corporations with population of 350,000 or more; effect of this Code section on other laws</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-11.1__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition and supplementary to other powers provided by this chapter for the several public entities, any municipal corporation having a population of 350,000 or more according to the United States decennial census of 1970 or any future such census may exercise the powers provided by this chapter for public works projects which are not financed in whole or in part from federal funds, but which are financed wholly or in part from the funds of any such municipal corporation or from other nonfederal funding sources, if the governing authority of any such municipal corporation shall first pass an ordinance or resolution stipulating that such funds are to be spent in good faith anticipation of whole or partial reimbursement from federal funds. The costs incurred by any such municipal corporation pursuant to the authority provided by this Code section shall be a part of the costs of public works projects. In carrying out the powers granted under this Code section any such municipal corporation shall be authorized to:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-4-11.1__subsec_a__para_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide all relocation assistance and payments as authorized by this chapter;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-4-11.1__subsec_a__para_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Establish and implement all acquisition policies and practices authorized under this chapter; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="sec_22-4-11.1__subsec_a__para_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide for reimbursement of all necessary expenses authorized under this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-11.1__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Code section shall not be construed to repeal or affect in any manner Code Section 32-8-1, relating to relocation assistance for persons displaced by federal-aid highway projects.

History Ga. L. 1981, p. 1417, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1991, p. 307, § 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1981, p. 1417, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1991, p. 307, § 1.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-12">
          <num>22-4-12</num>
          <heading>Functions provided in chapter as public purposes; effect of chapter on power of state, public agencies, etc., to tax</heading>
          <intro>
            <p>§ 22-4-12. Functions provided in chapter as public purposes; effect of chapter on power of state, public agencies, etc., to tax</p>
          </intro>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-12__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The providing of all of the relocation assistances and payments described in this chapter and, in connection with the acquisition of real property for public works projects or programs, the establishing of all of the policies and practices described in this chapter, and the paying or reimbursing of all of the expenses described in this chapter are declared to be necessary and shall and do constitute governmental functions undertaken for public purposes. Therefore, public funds may be expended by said public entities in furtherance of such functions, and those public entities that possess the power of taxation in relation to the public works projects and programs referred to in this subsection may exercise such power in furtherance thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-12__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing contained in this Code section should be construed as a grant of a power of taxation to any of the several public entities which do not possess, independently of this chapter, any powers of taxation. Rather, this Code section shall constitute a grant of the power of taxation in relation to the public purposes enumerated in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="sec_22-4-12__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this Code section to such of the several public entities as possess, independently of this chapter, powers of taxation in relation to the particular public works project or program which is undertaken or sponsored by such public entity and which displaces a person, thereby giving rise to the necessity of relocation assistance and payments, or which requires the acquisition of real property, thereby necessitating the real property acquisition policies, practices, payments, and reimbursements described in this chapter.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 12.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 12.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-13">
          <num>22-4-13</num>
          <heading>Payments under chapter as income or resources</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-13. Payments under chapter as income or resources
No payment received by a displaced person under this chapter shall be considered as income or resources for the purpose of determining the eligibility or extent of eligibility of any person for assistance under any state law or for the purposes of the state's personal income tax law, corporation tax law, or other tax laws. These payments shall not be considered as income or resources of any recipient of public assistance, and the payment shall not be deducted from the amount of aid to which the recipient would otherwise be entitled.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 13.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 13.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-14">
          <num>22-4-14</num>
          <heading>Effect of chapter on condemnation proceedings</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-14. Effect of chapter on condemnation proceedings
Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as creating in any condemnation proceeding brought under the power of eminent domain any element of value or of damage.

History Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 10.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Ga. L. 1973, p. 512, § 10.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_22-4-15">
          <num>22-4-15</num>
          <heading>Authority of public entities to provide replacement housing when federal-aid project cannot proceed to actual construction</heading>
          <content>
            <p>§ 22-4-15. Authority of public entities to provide replacement housing when federal-aid project cannot proceed to actual construction
The several public entities shall have the authority, as a last resort, to provide replacement housing when a federal-aid project financed in whole or in part with federal aid cannot proceed to actual construction because no comparable replacement sale or rental housing is available. In carrying out the relocation assistance activities, the several public entities shall be authorized to make payments, construct or reconstruct with their own forces, cause to be constructed or reconstructed, and purchase by deed or condemnation any real property for the purposes of providing replacement housing. The acquiring public entity may exchange, lease, or sell to the displaced person such replacement housing. Whenever any real property has been acquired under this Code section and thereafter the acquiring public entity determines that all or any part of such property or any interest therein is no longer needed for such purposes because of changed conditions, the acquiring public entity is authorized to dispose of such property or interest therein in accordance with Code Section 50-16-144.

History Code 1981, § 22-4-15, enacted by Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 10.</p>
          </content>
          <notes>
            <note type="history">
              <p>Code 1981, § 22-4-15, enacted by Ga. L. 1989, p. 213, § 10.</p>
            </note>
          </notes>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
