<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/25-3-23/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_25_3_23">
        <num>25-3-23</num>
        <content>
          <p>A lump sum benefit of $6,250.00 subject to limitations specified in the insurance contract and based on severity of cancer and payable to such firefighter upon submission to the insurance carrier or other payor of acceptable proof of diagnosis by a physician board certified in the medical specialty appropriate for the type of cancer involved that:</p>
          <p>There is carcinoma in situ such that surgery, radiotherapy, or chemotherapy has been determined to be medically necessary;</p>
          <p>There are malignant tumors which are treated by endoscopic procedures alone;</p>
          <p>There are malignant melanomas; or</p>
          <p>Payable as a result of a specific injury or illness to begin six months after disability and submission to the insurance carrier or other payor of acceptable proof of disability precluding service as a firefighter and continuing for up to 36 consecutive monthly payments:</p>
          <p>A monthly benefit equal to 60 percent of the member's monthly salary as an employed firefighter with the fire department or a monthly benefit of $5,000.00, whichever is less; or</p>
          <p>If the member is a volunteer, a monthly benefit of $1,500.00.</p>
          <p>The combined total of all benefits received by any firefighter under subdivisions (B)(i)(I) and (B)(i)(II) of this paragraph during his or her lifetime shall not exceed $50,000.00.</p>
          <p>With the exception of the benefit under subdivision (B)(ii)(I) of this paragraph, any person who was simultaneously a member of more than one fire department at the time of diagnosis shall not be entitled to receive benefits under this paragraph from or on behalf of more than one of such fire departments. In the event a volunteer of one fire department is simultaneously employed by another fire department, the fire department for which such person is a volunteer shall not be required to maintain the coverage on such volunteer otherwise required under this subsection during the period of such employment. Any member who receives benefits under division (ii) of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph may be required to have his or her condition reevaluated; in the event any such reevaluation reveals that such person has regained the ability to perform duties as a firefighter, then his or her benefits under division (ii) of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall cease. Benefits under said division shall also cease upon the death of such person. A member who, after at least one year as a firefighter, departs from employment, ceases to be an active volunteer, or retires shall be entitled to continue his or her coverages under this paragraph through a continuation or conversion to individual coverage. The departing member shall be responsible for payment of all premiums.</p>
          <p>In addition to any other purpose authorized under Chapter 8 of Title 33, county governing authorities and municipal governing authorities may use proceeds from county and municipal taxes imposed under said chapter for purposes of providing insurance pursuant to this paragraph.</p>
          <p>Funds received as premiums for the coverages specified in this paragraph shall not be subject to premium taxes under Chapter 8 of Title 33.</p>
          <p>The computation of premium amounts by an insurer for the coverages under this paragraph shall be subject to generally accepted adjustments from insurance underwriting.</p>
          <p>The Georgia Volunteer Fire Service Council shall be authorized to adopt such rules and regulations for fire departments solely utilizing volunteer firefighters as are reasonable and necessary to implement the provisions of this Code section and to establish and modify minimum requirements for all volunteer fire departments operating in this state, provided that such requirements are equal to or exceed the requirements provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this Code section.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_3_23__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Georgia Firefighter Standards and Training Council shall be authorized to adopt such rules and regulations for fire departments employing full-time firefighters or part-time firefighters as are reasonable and necessary to implement the provisions of this Code section and to establish and modify minimum requirements for all fire departments operating in this state, provided that such requirements are equal to or exceed the requirements provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this Code section.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
