<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-11-129/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_11_129">
        <num>16-11-129</num>
        <content>
          <p>(a.1)Gun safety information.</p>
          <p>Upon receipt of an application for a weapons carry license or renewal license, the judge of the probate court may provide applicants printed information on gun safety that is produced by any person or organization that, in the discretion of the judge of the probate court, offers practical advice for gun safety. The source of such printed information shall be prominently displayed on such printed information.</p>
          <p>The Department of Natural Resources shall maintain on its principal, public website information, or a hyperlink to information, which provides resources for information on hunter education and classes and courses in this state that render instruction in gun safety. No person shall be required to take such classes or courses for purposes of this Code section where such information shall be provided solely for the convenience of the citizens of this state.</p>
          <p>Neither the judge of the probate court nor the Department of Natural Resources shall be liable to any person for personal injuries or damage to property arising from conformance to this subsection.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1910, p. 134, §§ 2, 3; Code 1933, §§ 26-5104, 26-5105; Ga. L. 1960, p. 938, § 1; Code 1933, § 26-2904, enacted by Ga. L. 1968, p. 1249, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 1430, § 4; Ga. L. 1978, p. 1607, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1981, p. 946, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 1325, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 1431, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 935, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1388, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 305, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 481, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 138, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 2012, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 16; Ga. L. 1994, p. 351, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 108, §§ 3-5; Ga. L. 1997, p. 514, § 2; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1011, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 264, § 1/HB 1032; Ga. L. 2008, p. 1199, § 6/HB 89; Ga. L. 2009, p. 453, § 3-2/HB 228; Ga. L. 2010, p. 963, § 1-7/SB 308; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 16/HB 142; Ga. L. 2014, p. 599, § 1-7/HB 60; Ga. L. 2015, p. 805, § 6/HB 492; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 16/HB 737; Ga. L. 2017, p. 509, § 1/SB 15; Ga. L. 2017, p. 555, § 6/HB 292; Ga. L. 2018, p. 1112, § 16/SB 365; Ga. L. 2019, p. 275, § 1/HB 33; Ga. L. 2019, p. 808, § 7/SB 72.)</p>
          <p>The 2016 amendment,
      effective May 3, 2016, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection" for "subparagraph (d)(1)(B) of this subsection" in the middle of paragraph (d)(2).</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendments.
      The first 2017 amendment, effective July 1, 2017, substituted the present provisions of subsection (h) for the former provisions, which read: "Except as otherwise provided in Code Section 16-11-130, any person who has served as a law enforcement officer for at least ten of the 12 years immediately preceding the retirement of such person as a law enforcement officer shall be entitled to be issued a weapons carry license as provided for in this Code section without the payment of any of the fees provided for in this Code section. Such person shall comply with all the other provisions of this Code section relative to the issuance of such licenses. As used in this subsection, the term 'law enforcement officer' means any peace officer who is employed by the United States government or by the State of Georgia or any political subdivision thereof and who is required by the terms of his or her employment, whether by election or appointment, to give his or her full time to the preservation of public order or the protection of life and property or the prevention of crime. Such term shall include conservation rangers." The second 2017 amendment, effective May 8, 2017, added subsection (a.1); in paragraph (d)(4), substituted "20 days" for "30 days" near the middle of the first sentence, and added the last sentence; in paragraph (e)(2), substituted "otherwise adjudicated in a matter" for "involved in any matter" near the beginning of the first sentence; and added paragraph (e)(4).</p>
          <p>The 2018 amendment,
      effective May 8, 2018, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, revised the designations in subsections (f) and (h).</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendments.
      The first 2019 amendment, effective July 1, 2019, rewrote subsection (a). The second 2019 amendment, effective July 1, 2019, substituted "game wardens" for "conservation rangers" at the end of the second sentence in paragraph (h)(3).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
