<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/16-5-24/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_5_24">
        <num>16-5-24</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Laws 1833, Cobb's 1851 Digest, pp. 786, 787; Code 1863, § 4238; Code 1868, § 4273; Code 1873, § 4339; Code 1882, § 4339; Penal Code 1895, § 83; Penal Code 1910, § 83; Code 1933, § 26-1201; Code 1933, § 26-1305, enacted by Ga. L. 1968, p. 1249, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 543, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 16; Ga. L. 1984, p. 900, § 2; Ga. L. 1985, p. 628, § 2; Ga. L. 1991, p. 971, §§ 9, 10; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1012, § 9; Ga. L. 1996, p. 988, § 2; Ga. L. 1997, p. 1453, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 381, § 5; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1626, § 2; Ga. L. 2003, p. 140, § 16; Ga. L. 2014, p. 432, § 2-3/HB 826; Ga. L. 2014, p. 599, § 3-2/HB 60; Ga. L. 2016, p. 582, § 2/HB 979; Ga. L. 2017, p. 500, § 3-3/SB 160.)</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2017, substituted "subsections (c) through (g)" for "subsections (c) through (i)" in subsection (b); designated the existing provisions of subsection (c) as paragraph (c)(1); in paragraph (c)(1), substituted "public safety officer while the public safety officer" for "peace officer while the officer" near the middle, added the proviso at the end; added paragraph (c)(2); deleted former subsection (e), which read: "(1) As used in this subsection, the term 'correctional officer' shall include superintendents, wardens, deputy wardens, guards, and correctional officers of state, county, and municipal penal institutions who are certified by the Georgia Peace Officer Standards and Training Council pursuant to Chapter 8 of Title 35 and employees of the Department of Juvenile Justice who are known to be employees of the department or who have given reasonable identification of their employment. The term 'correctional officer' shall also include county jail officers who are certified or registered by the Georgia Peace Officer Standards and Training Council pursuant to Chapter 8 of Title 35."</p>
          <p>"(2) A person who knowingly commits the offense of aggravated battery upon a correctional officer while the correctional officer is engaged in, or on account of the performance of, his or her official duties shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by imprisonment for not less than ten nor more than 20 years."; redesignated former subsection (f) as present subsection (e); deleted the second sentence in present subsection (e), which read: "For purposes of this Code section, 'public transit vehicle' has the same meaning as in subsection (c) of Code Section 16-5-20."; redesignated former subsections (g) and (h) as present subsections (f) and (g), respectively; and deleted former subsection (i), which read: "A person who knowingly commits the offense of aggravated battery upon an emergency health worker while the worker is engaged in, or on account of the performance of, his or her official duties shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by imprisonment for not less than five nor more than 20 years. As used in this subsection, the term 'emergency health worker' means hospital emergency department personnel and emergency medical services personnel."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
