<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/35-2-42/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_35_2_42">
        <num>35-2-42</num>
        <content>
          <p>All members of the Uniform Division, all communications officers, and all recruits or cadets shall be governed by rules and regulations as now or hereafter established under Chapter 20 of Title 45.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 322, art. 2, § 2; Ga. L. 1939, p. 135, § 2; Ga. L. 1946, p. 39, § 2; Ga. L. 1947, p. 1159, § 2; Ga. L. 1949, p. 70, § 4; Ga. L. 1951, p. 635, §§ 1, 1A; Ga. L. 1952, p. 129, § 1; Ga. L. 1955, p. 298, § 1; Ga. L. 1956, p. 573, § 1; Ga. L. 1957, p. 103, § 1; Ga. L. 1958, p. 296, §§ 3, 4; Ga. L. 1960, p. 132, § 1; Ga. L. 1965, p. 125, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 84, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 147, § 1; Ga. L. 1970, p. 117, § 1; Ga. L. 1971, p. 306, § 1; Ga. L. 1971, p. 309, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 354, § 2; Ga. L. 1973, p. 449, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1974, p. 1007, § 1; Ga. L. 1974, p. 1122, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1115, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1977, p. 228, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 35; Ga. L. 1987, p. 3, § 35; Ga. L. 1992, p. 3131, § 3; Ga. L. 2000, p. 951, § 12-5; Ga. L. 2006, p. 1050, § 1/SB 520; Ga. L. 2021, p. 463, § 2/SB 198.)</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective May 4, 2021, rewrote this Code section, which read: "(a) All members of the Uniform Division, all communications officers, and all recruits or cadets shall be governed by rules and regulations as now or hereafter established under Chapter 20 of Title 45.</p>
          <p>"(b) The board shall be authorized to provide for a subsistence and per diem allowance for commissioned officers, noncommissioned officers, and troopers of the Uniform Division.</p>
          <p>"(c) The board shall be authorized to pay to sworn members of the Department of Public Safety additional compensation to be paid upon retirement in the form of the badge and the duty weapon issued by the department to such member.</p>
          <p>"(d) The board shall be authorized to grant incentive pay to those members of the Uniform Division of the Department of Public Safety and those members of the Georgia Bureau of Investigation who have obtained degrees or certificates from an accredited member of the Federation of Regional Accrediting Commissions of Higher Education or who have obtained a degree or certificate of completion from some other educational institution with respect to a course of instruction related to law enforcement, so long as both the course of instruction and the institution are specifically approved by the board. Any such incentive pay shall be paid according to the following schedule:</p>
          <p>"(1) Completion of at least one year of degree-creditable college study consisting of the equivalent of 30 semester hours or 45 quarter hours of education: $200.00 per year;</p>
          <p>"(2) Obtaining of associate or two-year degree or certificate of completion of 60 semester hours or 90 quarter hours of education: $400.00 per year;</p>
          <p>"(3) Obtaining of a bachelor's or four-year degree: $800.00 per year.</p>
          <p>"(e) This Code section is not intended to repeal existing law concerning the following:</p>
          <p>"(1) The authority of the board to pay certain medical expenses incurred by any member of the Georgia State Patrol or the Georgia Bureau of Investigation;</p>
          <p>"(2) The authority of the commissioner to provide uniforms and supplies to members of the Uniform Division;</p>
          <p>"(3) The requirement that board and quarters be furnished to every member of the Uniform Division on active duty; or</p>
          <p>"(4) The authorization for officers and troopers to receive a legal award offered for the apprehension of any criminal."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
