<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/19-3-36/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_3_36">
        <num>19-3-36</num>
        <content>
          <p>The judge of the probate court to whom the application for a marriage license is made shall satisfy himself or herself that the provisions set forth in Code Section 19-3-2 regarding age limitations are met. The judge shall require all applicants to furnish the court with documentary evidence of proof of age in the form of a birth certificate, driver's license, baptismal certificate, certificate of birth registration, selective service card, court record, passport, immigration papers, alien papers, citizenship papers, armed forces discharge papers, armed forces identification card, or hospital admission card containing the full name and date of birth. Applicants who have satisfactorily proved that they have reached the age of majority may be issued a marriage license immediately.</p>
          <p>(Orig. Code 1863, § 1661; Code 1868, § 1704; Code 1873, § 1705; Code 1882, § 1705; Civil Code 1895, § 2419; Civil Code 1910, § 2938; Ga. L. 1924, p. 53, § 2; Ga. L. 1927, p. 224, § 1; Code 1933, § 53-206; Ga. L. 1965, p. 335, § 6; Ga. L. 1972, p. 193, § 6; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1298, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 1719, § 4; Ga. L. 1979, p. 872, § 2; Ga. L. 2006, p. 141, § 6B/HB 847; Ga. L. 2019, p. 558, § 1-3/HB 228.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2019, substituted "The judge shall require all applicants" for "If the judge does not know of his or her own knowledge the age of a party for whom a marriage license is sought, the judge shall require the applicant" at the beginning of the second sentence and deleted the former third sentence, which read: "In the event an applicant does not possess any of the above but appears to the judge to be at least 25 years of age, the applicant, in lieu of furnishing the judge with one of the above, may give an affidavit to the judge stating the applicant's age."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
