<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-11-16/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_11_16">
        <num>33-11-16</num>
        <content>
          <p>An insurer may invest in obligations issued, assumed, or guaranteed by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development or the International Finance Corporation. The investments authorized by this Code section shall not be counted as an investment of reserves under paragraph (4) of Code Section 33-11-5 at any one time in an amount greater than 5 percent of the insurer's admitted assets. Such investments shall be subject to all limitations and requirements of this article. In addition to authority contained in Code Section 33-11-8 and elsewhere in this title, an insurer may invest up to 10 percent of its admitted assets in securities or other investments within a foreign country which are similar in characteristics and quality to like investments authorized pursuant to this article for investments in the United States of America, including obligations of the government of such foreign country and its political subdivisions and instrumentalities, provided that the values of such securities or other investments shall be determined in accordance with the valuation methods then currently formulated or approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its successor organization.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 56-1008, enacted by Ga. L. 1960, p. 289, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2389, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 592, §§ 5, 6.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
