<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-24-23/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_24_23">
        <num>33-24-23</num>
        <content>
          <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions in this title to the contrary, no group policy of accident and sickness insurance offered for sale in this state shall be issued or renewed by any insurer transacting business in this state, or health care plan under Chapter 20 of this title, which by the terms of the group policy excludes or reduces the benefits payable or services to be rendered to or on behalf of any insured by reason of the fact that benefits have been paid or are also payable under any blanket school accident policy regardless of who makes the premium contribution or any individually underwritten and individually issued contract or plan of insurance which provides exclusively for accident and sickness benefits and for which 100 percent of the premiums have been paid by the insured or a member of the insured's family, irrespective of the mode or channel of premium payment to the insurer or any discount received on such premium by virtue of the insured's membership in any organization or status as an employee.Any policy provision in violation of this Code section shall be void and unenforceable.Nothing in this Code section shall affect the practice of coordinating benefits between group policies issued pursuant to Chapter 30 of this title.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 56-2442, enacted by Ga. L. 1975, p. 443, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2017, p. 164, ยง 18/HB 127; Ga. L. 2019, p. 386, ยง 35/SB 133.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2019, deleted "after April 17, 1975," following "shall be issued or renewed" near the beginning of the first sentence.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
