<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/33-6-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_6_4">
        <num>33-6-4</num>
        <content>
          <p>"Covered eye care services" means those health care services and materials related to the care of the eye and related structures and vision care services for which a health care insurer is obligated to pay for or provide to covered persons under an eye care benefit plan, which includes services for which reimbursement is available under such plan, or for which reimbursement would be available but for the application of contractual limitations such as deductibles, copayments, coinsurance, waiting periods, annual or lifetime maximums, frequency limitations, alternative benefit payments, or any other limitation.</p>
          <p>"Covered person" means any subscriber, enrollee, member, beneficiary, or participant, or his or her dependent, for whom benefits are payable when such person receives eye care services rendered or authorized by an ophthalmologist licensed under Chapter 34 of Title 43 or an optometrist licensed under Chapter 30 of Title 43.</p>
          <p>"Eye care benefit plan" means any individual or group plan, policy contract, or subscription agreement which includes or is for eye care services that is issued, delivered, issued for delivery, or renewed in this state whether by a health care insurer, health maintenance organization, preferred provider organization, accident and sickness insurer, fraternal benefit society, nonprofit hospital service corporation, nonprofit medical or eye care service corporation, health care plan, or any other person, firm, corporation, joint venture, or other similar business entity that pays for, purchases, or furnishes eye care services to patients, insureds, beneficiaries, or covered dependents in this state.</p>
          <p>"Health care insurer" or "insurer" means an entity, including but not limited to insurance companies, health care corporations, health maintenance organizations, and preferred provider organizations, authorized by the state to offer or provide health benefit plans, eye care benefit plans, programs, policies, subscriber contracts, or any other agreements of a similar nature which compensate or indemnify health care providers for furnishing covered eye care or other health care services.</p>
          <p>(I) Any person issuing, delivering, or renewing a policy of insurance in this state at any time shall include with such policy or renewal certificate a notice attached thereto containing the following language:</p>
          <p>"NOTICE</p>
          <p>The laws of the State of Georgia prohibit insurers from unfairly discriminating against any person based upon his or her status as a victim of family violence."</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, §§ 56-704, 56-9906, enacted by Ga. L. 1960, p. 289, § 1; Ga. L. 1978, p. 2016, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 1266, § 2; Ga. L. 1989, p. 888, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 1276, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 33; Ga. L. 1992, p. 996, §§ 1-3; Ga. L. 2000, p. 236, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 4, § 33; Ga. L. 2002, p. 441, § 2; Ga. L. 2005, p. 563, § 2/HB 407; Ga. L. 2006, p. 72, § 33/SB 465; Ga. L. 2006, p. 433, § 1/HB 425; Ga. L. 2007, p. 500, § 1/SB 84; Ga. L. 2016, p. 381, § 1/HB 784; Ga. L. 2019, p. 337, § 1-34/SB 132; Ga. L. 2019, p. 866, § 1/HB 227; Ga. L. 2020, p. 743, § 2/SB 482; Ga. L. 2021, p. 560, § 2/SB 43.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendments.
      The first 2019 amendment, effective July 1, 2019, deleted "of Insurance" following "Commissioner" at the end of subparagraph (b)(13)(C) and deleted "within a period of 24 months after July 1, 2000," following "at any time" in subparagraph (b)(15)(I). The second 2019 amendment, effective July 1, 2019, substituted "family violence or sexual assault" for "family violence" throughout paragraph (b)(15); added ", the term" at the end of the introductory language of subparagraph (b)(15)(A); substituted "Confidential abuse information" for "Confidential family violence information" near the beginning of division (b)(15)(A)(i); added division (b)(15)(A)(iii); substituted "family violence or sexual assault" for "abuse" throughout subparagraph (b)(15)(C); substituted "confidential abuse information" for "family violence information" in the first sentence of division (b)(15)(C)(v) and in the last sentence of subparagraph (b)(15)(D); and substituted "Confidential abuse" for "Family violence" at the beginning of the second sentence in division (b)(15)(C)(v).</p>
          <p>The 2020 amendment,
      effective August 5, 2020, added paragraph (b)(14.2).</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2021, deleted "or" at the end of paragraph (b)(14.2), and added paragraph (b)(14.3). See Editor's notes for applicability.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
