<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-10-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51_10_6">
        <num>51-10-6</num>
        <content>
          <p>"Upon reasonable cause, notice is given of
      (my) (our)
      demand for payment of damages in the amount of
      (state amount claimed: total should be $300.00 or triple the amount of the entire loss sustained by the property owner as a result of the willful damage or theft offense, whichever is greater)
      arising out of your
      (willful damage, theft, or unlawful conversion)
      of the following personal property owned by
      (the undersigned or other owner)
      :
   (List affected property) __________________________________________________
   ___________________________________________________________________________
   ___________________________________________________________________________
   Pursuant to Code Section 51-10-6 of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated, you are further notified that if the above-stated amount is not paid, or a written agreement as to its payment is not reached, within 30 days of the date you receive this letter,
      (I) (we) (other owner)
      intend to bring an action against you for such amount, plus attorney's fees, plus court costs, and such other relief as the law provides.
   ________________________"</p>
          <p>If a property owner whose personal property was willfully damaged or was the subject of a theft offense provides written notice of demand for payment upon a person who willfully damaged the personal property or who committed the theft offense, and the person makes payment in accordance with the demand within 30 days after the date of service of the written demand upon him or the person enters into an agreement with the property owner during that 30 day period for such payment and makes payment in accordance with the agreement, the property owner shall not file a civil complaint against the person in relation to the willful property damage or theft offense.</p>
          <p>In a civil action to recover damages for willful damage to personal property or for a theft offense, the trier of fact may determine that an owner's property was willfully damaged or that a theft offense involving the owner's personal property has been committed, whether or not any person has pleaded guilty to or has been convicted of any criminal offense or has been adjudicated delinquent in relation to any act involving the owner's personal property.</p>
          <p>As used in this Code section, the term "value" means the retail value of any personal property that is offered for sale by a mercantile establishment or the replacement value of any other personal property.</p>
          <p>If a civil action is filed pursuant to Article 4 of Chapter 12 of Title 44 to recover personal property or damages resulting from willful damage to or theft of such personal property, no civil action authorized by this Code section shall be permitted.</p>
          <p>The measure of damages provided for in this Code section shall not be applicable in cases involving the unauthorized cutting or cutting and carrying away of timber from the property of another. In such cases, damages shall be awarded in accordance with Code Section 51-12-50.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_51_10_6__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this Code section, written notice of demand for payment shall be substantially as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
