<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/51-7-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51_7_60">
        <num>51-7-60</num>
        <content>
          <p>Whenever the owner or operator of a retail establishment as defined in Code Section 16-7-2 or a food service establishment as defined in Code Section 26-2-370 or any agent or employee thereof detains or causes to be detained any person pursuant to Code Section 17-4-80 and any person who detains or causes to be detained a person while acting pursuant to Article 2 of Chapter 3 of Title 16 wherein the person so detained brings an action for false arrest or false imprisonment against such owner, operator, agent, employee, or person, no recovery shall be had by the plaintiff in such action when it is established by competent evidence:</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1958, p. 693, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2014, p. 404, ยง 2-4/SB 382; Ga. L. 2021, p. 625, ยง 7/HB 479.)</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective May 10, 2021, substituted the present provisions of the introductory paragraph for the former provisions, which read: "Whenever the owner or operator of a mercantile establishment or any agent or employee of the owner or operator detains, arrests, or causes to be detained or arrested any person reasonably thought to be engaged in shoplifting or refund fraud and, as a result of the detention or arrest, the person so detained or arrested brings an action for false arrest or false imprisonment against the owner, operator, agent, or employee, no recovery shall be had by the plaintiff in such action where it is established by competent evidence:", substituted the present provisions of paragraph (1) for the former provisions, which read: "That the plaintiff had so conducted himself or herself or behaved in such manner as to cause a person of reasonable prudence to believe that the plaintiff, at or immediately prior to the time of the detention or arrest, was committing the offense of shoplifting, as defined by Code Section 16-8-14, or refund fraud as defined in Code Section 16-8-14; or", and deleted "or arrest" following "detention" in paragraph (2). See Editor's note for applicability.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
