<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-401/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_2_401">
        <num>11-2-401</num>
        <content>
          <p>Each provision of this article with regard to the rights, obligations, and remedies of the seller, the buyer, purchasers, or other third parties applies irrespective of title to the goods except where the provision refers to such title. Insofar as situations are not covered by the other provisions of this article and matters concerning title become material the following rules apply:</p>
          <p>Unless otherwise explicitly agreed where delivery is to be made without moving the goods:</p>
          <p>If the seller is to deliver a tangible document of title, title passes at the time when and the place where he or she delivers such documents and if the seller is to deliver an electronic document of title, title passes when the seller delivers the document; or</p>
          <p>If the goods are at the time of contracting already identified and no documents of title are to be delivered, title passes at the time and place of contracting.</p>
          <p>A rejection or other refusal by the buyer to receive or retain the goods, whether or not justified, or a justified revocation of acceptance revests title to the goods in the seller. Such revesting occurs by operation of law and is not a "sale."</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 109A-2 - 401, enacted by Ga. L. 1962, p. 156, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2010, p. 481, ยง 2-6/HB 451.)</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective May 27, 2010, inserted "or her" in subsection (2) and in paragraph (2)(a); inserted "the" in the introductory paragraph of subsection (3); in paragraph (3)(a), inserted "tangible", inserted "or she", and added "and if the seller is to deliver an electronic document of title, title passes when the seller delivers the document" at the end; and inserted "of title" in paragraph (3)(b). See the Editor's notes for applicability.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
