<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/11-2-326/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_2_326">
        <num>11-2-326</num>
        <content>
          <p>Goods held on approval are not subject to the claims of the buyer's creditors until acceptance; goods held on sale or return are subject to such claims while in the buyer's possession.</p>
          <p>Any "or return" term of a contract for sale is to be treated as a separate contract for sale within the statute of frauds section of this article (Code Section 11-2-201) and as contradicting the sale aspect of the contract within the provisions of this article on parol or extrinsic evidence (Code Section 11-2-202).</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 109A-2 - 326, enacted by Ga. L. 1962, p. 156, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 188, ยง 2; Ga. L. 2001, p. 362, ยง 6.)</p>
          <p>The 2001 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2001, deleted "consignment sales and" in the catchline, substituted "Goods" for "Except as provided in subsection (3) of this Code section, goods" at the beginning of subsection (2), deleted subsection (3), which read: "Where goods are delivered to a person for sale and such person maintains a place of business at which he deals in goods of the kind involved, under a name other than the name of the person making delivery, then with respect to claims of creditors of the person conducting the business the goods are deemed to be on sale or return. The provisions of this subsection are applicable even though an agreement purports to reserve title to the person making delivery until payment or resale or uses such words as 'on consignment' or 'on memorandum.' However, this subsection is not applicable if the person making delivery: (a) Complies with an applicable law providing for a consignor's interest or the like to be evidenced by a sign; or (b) Establishes that the person conducting the business is generally known by his creditors to be substantially engaged in selling the goods of others; or (c) Complies with the filing provisions of the article on secured transactions (Article 9 of this title).", and redesignated former subsection (4) as present subsection (3).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
