<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-22/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_12_22">
        <num>50-12-22</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1976, p. 748, § 3; Ga. L. 1979, p. 388, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 174, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1903, § 12; Ga. L. 2011, p. 514, § 1/HB 264; Ga. L. 2013, p. 1042, § 3/HB 338.)</p>
          <p>The 2011 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2011, substituted "commissioner of economic development" for "director of the Office of Planning and Budget" at the end of subsection (b).</p>
          <p>The 2013 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2013, substituted the present provisions of subsection (a) for the former provisions, which read: "The council shall consist of two members from each congressional district and four members representing the state at large who shall be appointed by the Governor. All members shall have demonstrated an interest in the arts. Except for certain members who were appointed in 1979, the term of office of each member shall be three years. In 1979, eight members were appointed for terms of office of one year, eight members for terms of two years, and eight members for terms of three years. The initial appointments were made so that no more than one member from each congressional district or two state-at-large members' terms of office would expire in any one year. Vacancies shall be filled for unexpired terms in the same manner as the original appointment. Membership on the council shall be limited to two successive three-year terms, and a member may be reappointed after a lapse of one year. No member initially appointed to one-year or two-year terms of office shall be prohibited from serving two consecutive three-year terms of office."; added subsection (b); redesignated former subsections (b) through (e) as present subsections (c) through (f), respectively; in subsection (e), substituted "chairperson" for "chairman" in the first sentence and added the second sentence; and substituted the present provisions of subsection (f) for the former provisions, which read: "The council shall meet annually, or more often, on the call of the chairman."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
