<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-12-20/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_12_20">
        <num>50-12-20</num>
        <content>
          <p>The General Assembly finds that the general welfare of the people of this state will be promoted by giving recognition to the arts as a vital part of our culture and heritage and economic development. The arts industry fuels cultural heritage tourism, the fastest growing segment of tourism; is a catalyst for community revitalization, boosting local economies; fuels arts education in our schools, which prepares students to be entrepreneurial, critical thinkers; and spurs innovation, helping industries to become more competitive in a global marketplace. The General Assembly, therefore, declares it to be the public policy of this state to encourage the development of the arts.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1976, p. 748, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 174, ยง 2; Ga. L. 2013, p. 1042, ยง 1/HB 338.)</p>
          <p>The 2013 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2013, substituted the present provisions of this Code section for the former provisions, which read: "The General Assembly finds that the general welfare of the people of the state will be promoted by giving recognition to the arts as a vital part of our culture and heritage; that with increasing leisure time, the practice and enjoyment of the arts are of increasing importance; and that many of our citizens lack the opportunity to view, enjoy, or participate in live theatrical performances, film making, photography, music, opera, dance, art exhibits, examples of fine architecture, and the performing and visual arts. The General Assembly finds that many of our citizens possess talents of an artistic and creative nature which are not currently utilized to the fullest extent; that broadened activity in the arts will increase employment in the state by encouraging additional cultural activity throughout the state, thus utilizing the talents and abilities of many more citizens; and that the standards of artistic performance will be further improved by continuing encouragement and support. The General Assembly, therefore, declares it to be the public policy of this state to encourage the development of the arts."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
