<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-15-2/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_15_2">
        <num>50-15-2</num>
        <content>
          <p>At any time prior to the final determination of a public lawsuit in the trial court or on appeal, any political subdivision which is a party to the action may petition for an order of the court that the opposing party or parties or intervenors be dismissed unless such opposing party or parties or intervenors post a bond with surety to be approved by the court payable to the moving party for the payment of all damages and costs which may accrue by reason of such opposition or intervention in the event the moving party prevails. The moving party shall obtain from a judge of the court an order requiring the opposing party or parties or intervenors to appear at such time and place within 20 days from the filing of the petition as the judge may direct and to show cause, if any exists, why the prayers of the petition should not be granted. The petition and order shall be served in the manner provided by law for the service of orders and pleadings subsequent to the original complaint. If, at the hearing of the petition on the order to show cause, the court determines that it is in the public interest to do so, the court shall set the amount of bond to be filed by the opposing party or parties or intervenors in an amount found by the court to cover all damage and costs which may accrue to the political subdivision by reason of the opposition or intervention in the event the political subdivision prevails. In the event the bond is not filed by the opposing party or parties or intervenors with surety approved by the court within ten days after the order is entered, the opposing party or parties or intervenors shall be dismissed by operation of law. Either the opposing party or parties or intervenors or the political subdivision may appeal the order under the procedure provided by law in cases of injunction. The appellate court may stay the lower court order pending its own decision, may set a bond to be filed by the opposing party or parties or intervenors in connection therewith, may modify the order of the lower court, or may enter its order as a final order in the case. In the event no bond is filed as provided in this Code section, the opposing party or parties or intervenors shall be dismissed by operation of law; and, upon final determination of the case, no court shall have further jurisdiction of any action involving any issue which was or could have been raised therein.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1969, p. 815, ยง 2.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
