<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-13-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_13_21">
        <num>50-13-21</num>
        <content>
          <p>As to such regulations, standards, and plans as are required by law to be filed and kept on file with the office of the Secretary of State, the Commissioner of Insurance, when performing the duties as Safety Fire Commissioner, may comply with the filing requirements of this chapter by filing with the office of the Secretary of State merely the name and designation of such regulations, standards, and plans, provided the regulations, standards, and plans are kept on file in the office of the Commissioner of Insurance by the titles otherwise applicable under this chapter and the regulations, standards, and plans are open for public examination and copying. The Commissioner of Insurance, when performing the duties as Safety Fire Commissioner, may also satisfy the procedure for conduct of hearings on contested cases and rule making required under this chapter by following Chapter 2 of Title 33. The Commissioner of Insurance, when performing the duties as Commissioner of Insurance, may satisfy the procedure for conduct of hearings on contested cases required under this chapter by following Chapter 2 of Title 33. When the Commissioner of Insurance is performing rule-making duties as Commissioner of Insurance, he shall satisfy the procedures required under this chapter and under Chapter 2 of Title 33. In the event of any conflicts between rule-making procedures of this chapter and Chapter 2 of Title 33 as it respects duties of the Commissioner of Insurance, this chapter shall govern.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1967, p. 618, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 855, ยง 28; Ga. L. 1989, p. 681, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
