<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/50-6-27/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_6_27">
        <num>50-6-27</num>
        <content>
          <p>The state auditor shall prepare each year a report showing the entire personnel of every office, institution, board, department, and commission in the executive department of the state government, of every state authority, of every university or college in the University System of Georgia, and of every local board of education. The report shall list the name, title or functional area, salary, and travel expense incurred by each such individual, which information shall be allocated to the respective office, institution, board, department, commission, authority, university, college, or local board of education affected. The report shall be kept in the state auditor's office and shall be available for public inspection during regular business hours. Copies of the report or portions of the report shall be made available on request and posted online in a searchable data base. Each office, institution, board, department, commission, authority, university, college, and local board of education is required and directed to submit to the state auditor, in a format prescribed by the state auditor, a listing of all personnel of such office, institution, board, department, commission, authority, university, college, or local board of education showing name, title or functional area, salary, and travel expense for each individual. The state auditor shall furnish each member of the General Assembly a card or form so that a copy of such report may be requested by any member who desires one.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1931, p. 7, § 8; Code 1933, § 40-1814; Ga. L. 1978, p. 220, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 668, § 1; Ga. L. 1995, p. 363, § 1; Ga. L. 2008, p. 522, § 5/SB 300.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
