<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_60">
        <num>34-15-60</num>
        <content>
          <p>Upon receipt of notice of a work-related injury, the Board shall assign a claim number.All subsequently filed forms, reports, or any other correspondence or documents related to or concerning such work-related injury shall have affixed thereto the assigned claim number, date of injury, and claimant's name.Failure to include this information with the filing may result in the rejection of the filing with the Board.</p>
          <p>Written instructions on all workers' compensation forms are deemed to be included in these rules.</p>
          <p>The Board shall have the power to issue writs of fieri facias in order to collect fines imposed by any member of the Board or any Administrative Law Judge against any person. Such writs may be enforced in the same manner as a similar writ issued by a superior court.</p>
          <p>Pleadings, forms, documents, or other filings shall be filed with the Board electronically through ICMS or EDI, unless otherwise authorized in these Rules.However, in the event of an outage preventing an electronic submission and the time for filing is at issue, the document may be filed in paper or by facsimile with any Board office.Any filing by facsimile transmission must be clearly labeled with the name of the claimant, claim number, and Board division or employee to whom the facsimile transmission is directed. The certificate of service, showing concurrent service upon the opposing party electronically or by facsimile transmission shall be a part of any electronic or facsimile transmission. Failure to include a certificate of service shall invalidate the filing. All facsimile transmissions must be identical to the originals and must be legible. The Board, within its discretion, may transmit documents by facsimile or electronic transmission.</p>
          <p>Any party or attorney challenging the authenticity of an electronically filed document or electronic signature on that filing must file an objection to the document within 15 days of receiving the notice of the electronic filing. The burden shall be on the party challenging the authenticity of the signature.</p>
          <p>In order to create a workers' compensation ICMS file at the Board, a Form WC-1 or Form WC-14 shall be filed with the Board.Any document or form filed with the Board, when either a Form WC-1 or Form WC-14 has not been previously filed, shall be rejected by the Board.</p>
          <p>Only the original of any form, document, or other correspondence shall be filed with the Board. Duplicate originals shall not be filed with the Board. Where providing a courtesy copy to an Administrative Law Judge or the Board, that document shall be identified clearly and prominently as a courtesy copy.</p>
          <p>Service upon a party or attorney of any form, document, or other correspondence shall be by electronic mail.Whenever electronic mail is not available, service shall be by U.S. Mail.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_34_15_60__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pursuant to Code Section 10-12-2 et seq., when a signature is required for any electronic filing with the Board, the party or attorney shall type his or her name in the appropriate fields on the document or Board form submitted for filing. Submission of a filing in this manner shall constitute evidence of legal signature by those individuals whose names appear on the filing.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
