<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-386/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_386">
        <num>34-15-386</num>
        <content>
          <p>Assessment for each new participant in the first calendar year of participation shall be $8,000.00. Thereafter, assessments shall be in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection.</p>
          <p>After the first calendar year of participation, the assessment of each participant shall be made on the basis of a percentage of the total of indemnity benefits paid by, or on behalf of, the participant during the previous calendar year. Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection for the first calendar year of participation and paragraph (4) of this subsection, a participant will be assessed 1.5 percent of the indemnity benefits paid by that participant during the previous calendar year or $2,000.00, whichever is greater. The maximum amount of annual assessments, not including those special assessments provided for in paragraph (4) of this subsection, in any calendar year against any one participant shall be $8,000.00.</p>
          <p>If the fund is reduced to an amount below $5 million net of all liabilities as the result of the payment of claims, the administration of claims, or the costs of administration of the Fund, the Board of trustees may levy a special assessment against participants in an amount sufficient to increase the funded level of $5 million net of all liabilities; provided however, that such assessment in any calendar year against any one participant shall not exceed $8,000.00.</p>
          <p>Funds obtained by such assessment shall be used only for the purposes set forth in this article and shall be deposited upon receipt by the Board of trustees into the fund. If payment of any assessment, penalty or fine made under this article is not made within 30 days of the sending of the notice to the participant, the Board of trustees is authorized to do any or all of the following:</p>
          <p>All participants shall be required to maintain surety bonds or the Board of trustees may, in its discretion, accept an irrevocable letter of credit in the amount of no less than $250,000.00. In addition, each active participant shall be required to purchase excess insurance for statutory limits with a self-insured retention specified by the Board, and the excess policy shall include the bankruptcy endorsement required by the board and Board of trustees.For participants who are no longer active, security in an amount commensurate with their remaining exposure, as determined by the board, shall be required until all self-insured claims have been closed and all applicable statutes of limitations have run.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2010, substituted "$8,000.00" for "$4,000.00" in paragraph (a)(2); in paragraph (a)(3), in the first sentence, substituted "the participant" for "each participant", in the second sentence, deleted "not" preceding "be assessed", deleted "at any one time an amount in excess of" preceding "1.5 percent", and substituted "$2,000.00" for "$1,000.00", and rewrote the last sentence; rewrote paragraph (a)(4) and (a)(5); in paragraph (b)(2), substituted "$250,000.00" for "$100,000.00 until the Board, after consultation with the Board of trustees, has determined that the financial capability of the trust fund and the participant no longer warrants any form of security" at the end of the first sentence, and added the last two sentences; substituted "for so long as indemnity or medical benefits are paid" for "as long as indemnity compensation is paid" in the first sentence; and, in subsection (d), substituted "or upon refusal to comply with a board order increasing security" for "when due", substituted "default" for "noncompliance" and added "and forfeiture of its security" at the end.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2016, in paragraph (a)(1), substituted "$15 million" for "$10 million"; in paragraph (a)(5), inserted ", penalty or fine" and substituted "self-insured status" for "insured status" in subparagraph (a)(5)(D); in paragraph (b)(2), substituted "an irrevocable letter of credit in the amount of" for "any irrevocable letter of credit or other acceptable forms of security in the amount of"; in subsection (c), inserted ", penalties and fines"; and, in subsection (d), deleted "increasing security" following "comply with a board order".</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
