<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-226/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_226">
        <num>34-15-226</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any party or attorney filing a request or an objection shall also serve a copy on all counsel and unrepresented parties, along with supporting documents, including a separate certificate of service identifying the names and addresses served.</p>
          <p>When filing a motion for reconsideration, the parties or attorneys shall: (1) immediately notify the Board or assigned Administrative Law Judge by telephone call; (2) use the ICMS doc-type labeled motion for reconsideration; and (3) serve a copy on all counsel and unrepresented parties, along with supporting documents, including a separate certificate of service identifying the names and addresses served.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2008, in paragraph (b), substituted "shall consent to a criminal history check via a Form WC-226(a) or Form WC-226(b)" for "must submit a consent for proof of a criminal history check" in the first sentence, and deleted the former second sentence, which read: "When the petitioner resides, or has resided, in a jurisdiction other than Georgia within the five years prior to the date of the petition for guardianship, the petitioner must submit a certified copy or other proof of a criminal history record check from all jurisdictions of residence."; and added subsection (e).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2009, in subsection (a), deleted the former last sentence which read: "In the case of a stipulated settlement, the guardianship petition should be filed prior to or at the time of the filing of the stipulated settlement agreement." and added the present last sentence.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2012, substituted "conservator" for "guardian" and "conservatorship" for "guardianship" in subsections (a), (b), and (d).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
