<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-108/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_108">
        <num>34-15-108</num>
        <content>
          <p>Immediately upon being employed by an employee or claimant in a matter which is before the Board, the attorney shall file a contract of employment and fees with the Board. No contract shall be filed with the Board which provides for a fee greater than 25 percent of the recovery of weekly benefits. Any contract with these terms, absent compelling evidence to the contrary, shall be deemed to represent the reasonable fee of the attorney.</p>
          <p>No party or any party's attorney shall enter into a loan or assignment with a third-party creditor which requires repayment from the proceeds of a workers' compensation claim. A third-party creditor shall not include a medical provider who has provided reasonable and necessary medical services to the employee pursuant to the fee schedule.</p>
          <p>The contract shall be dated and shall be signed by both the attorney and the client.</p>
          <p>This contract should include the following legible information:(1) name of attorney, (2) bar number, (3) firm name, (4) address, (5) phone number, (6) fax number, (7) email address, and (8) Board claim number.If the Board claim number is not known, this contract shall include the employee's first name, last name, and date of injury.All contracts shall include the employee's name and address.</p>
          <p>The contract should include the following statement:</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
