<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-15/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_15">
        <num>34-15-15</num>
        <content>
          <p>The party submitting the stipulation shall:</p>
          <p>A stipulation which provides for liability of the employer or insurer shall:</p>
          <p>state the legal and/or factual matters about which the parties disagree;</p>
          <p>state that all incurred medical expenses which were reasonable and necessary have been or will be paid by the employer/insurer. If the parties have agreed for medical treatment to be provided for a specific period in the future, then the stipulation must so state, and must further specify whether the agreement is limited to certain specific providers, and whether those providers may refer to others if needed. Furthermore, the stipulation shall provide that the parties will petition the Board for a change of physician in the event that a specifically named physician is unable to render services, and the parties cannot agree. If the stipulation does not contain a provision that medical expenses may be incurred for a specific period in the future after the approval of the stipulation, then the stipulation must contain a statement which explains why that provision is not necessary; and,</p>
          <p>attach the most recent medical report or summary which describes the medical condition of the employee, including a very brief statement of the surgical history, if any, if that history is not already specified within the stipulation. The entire medical record should NOT be attached.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
