<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-240/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_240">
        <num>34-15-240</num>
        <content>
          <p>File with the Board a Form WC-2 and Form WC-240 certifying that at least ten days before the employee was required to report for work he/she was notified on the completed Form WC-240 mailed to the employee and his/her attorney that there was a suitable job available, that it was approved by his/her authorized treating physician(s) after an examination within the last 60 days, and refusal to attempt to perform the job would result in the suspension of payment of weekly income benefits to the employee. The employer/insurer shall provide to the employee and legal counsel a copy of any job description/analysis in reference to subparagraph (3)(i), (ii) and (iii) at the time of submission to the authorized treating physician(s).</p>
          <p>If filing via EDI, section (b)(1) shall be followed and the employer/insurer shall simultaneously mail to, or electronically file with, the Board the filed Subsequent Report of Injury (SROI) or Form WC-2 and a copy of the served Form WC-240 and supporting medical report from employee's authorized treating physician.Pursuant to Board Rule 60(c), all documents filed with the Board shall contain the employee's name, date of injury, and Board claim number.Any document that does not contain this information shall be rejected by the Board.Copies of all filings shall be served on the employee and the employee's attorney, if represented.</p>
          <p>Attached to the Form WC-240 shall be:</p>
          <p>If the employee attempts the proffered job for less than eight cumulative hours or one scheduled workday, whichever is greater, or refuses to attempt to perform the proffered job after receiving the above notification, the employer/insurer shall be authorized to suspend payment of income benefits to the employee effective the date that they unjustifiably refused to report to work.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2008, substituted "shall provide" for "should provide" in the second sentence of paragraph (b)(1).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2009, added paragraph (b)(2), and redesignated former paragraphs (b)(2) and (b)(3) as present paragraphs (b)(3) and (b)(4), respectively.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2011, substituted "subparagraph (3)(i)" for "subparagraph (2)(i)" in the last sentence of paragraph (b)(1).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2013, inserted "attempts the proffered job for less than eight cumulative hours or one scheduled workday, whichever is greater, or" near the beginning of paragraph (b)(4); and inserted "and attempt the proffered job for eight cumulative hours or one scheduled workday, whichever is greater," near the beginning of subsection (c).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
