<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-100/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_100">
        <num>34-15-100</num>
        <content>
          <p>Neither the mediator nor any 3rd party observer present with the permission of the parties may be subpoenaed or otherwise required to testify concerning a mediation or settlement negotiations in any proceeding.The mediator's notes shall not be placed in the Board's file, are not subject to discovery, and shall not be used as evidence in any proceeding.</p>
          <p>Confidentiality does not extend to:</p>
          <p>Each party to the dispute is required to have in attendance at the mediation conference a person or persons who have adequate authority to resolve all pending issues. The employee shall be in attendance at the mediation conference. The employer shall have in attendance at the mediation conference a representative of the employer/insurer who has authority to resolve all pending issues. The requirement of the presence of the employer/insurer's representative shall not be satisfied by the presence of legal counsel of the employer. In claims where the Subsequent Injury Trust Fund (SITF) is a party-at-interest to the claim, a representative of the SITF must either be in attendance at the mediation conference or have extended settlement authority to the representative of the employer/insurer no later than two business days prior to the date of the conference. Exceptions to the attendance requirement may be granted upon permission of an Administrative Law Judge from the ADR Division or his/her designee, obtained prior to the conference date.</p>
          <p>Only the parties and attorneys of record may attend a scheduled mediation.Exceptions to attendance may be granted if agreed or consented to by the parties and attorneys of record and approved by a mediator or an Administrative Law Judge.</p>
          <p>Whenever the pending mediation issues resolve or a case settles prior to a scheduled mediation date, the parties or attorneys shall immediately notify the ADR Division: (1) first, by telephone call; and (2) if so instructed by the ADR Division, by subsequent written or electronic confirmation.</p>
          <p>Any party or attorney who fails to follow the cancellation, postponement, or rescheduling procedures as outlined above in sections (h)(1) &amp; (2), and who is unable to show good cause for such failure, may be subject to civil penalties, assessed attorney's fees, and/or costs.</p>
          <p>The ADR Division may postpone, reset, cancel or take off the calendar any mediation request, scheduled mediation, or Board ordered mediation.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2007, designated the existing provisions of subsection (h) as paragraph (h)(1); in paragraph (h)(1), made a punctuation change near the end, and substituted "if so instructed by the ADR Division, by subsequent written" for "then, when instructed by the ADR Division or when otherwise appropriate or necessary, by a subsequent written"; and added paragraphs (h)(2) and (h)(3).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2008, added paragraph (h)(4).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
