<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-203/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_203">
        <num>34-15-203</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any challenge by a medical provider to the amount of payment for goods, services, or expensesshall be submitted to the payer within 120 days of payment.Failure by a medical provider to challenge the amount of payment of such goods, services, or expenses within 120 days shall result in the waiver of additional payment.</p>
          <p>An employer or insurer shall pay when due all charges deemed reasonable, and follow the procedures set forth in subsection (2) for review of only those specified charges which are disputed.</p>
          <p>For charges not contained in the fee schedule and which are disputed as not being the usual, customary and reasonable charges prevailing in the State of Georgia, the employer, insurer, or physician shall file a request for peer review with a peer review organization authorized by the Board within 30 days of the receipt of charges by the employer/insurer, and shall serve a copy of the request and supporting documentation upon all parties and counsel. A request for peer review of chiropractic charges or treatment shall attach to the application 10 copies of the charges and all of the reports dealing with the treatment of the injured employee.</p>
          <p>Unless peer review is requested as set forth in Rule 203 (c)(2), all reasonable charges for medical, surgical, hospital and pharmacy goods and services shall be payable by the employer or its worker's compensation insurer within 30 days from the date that the employer or the insurer receives the charges and the medical reportsrequired by the Board or within 15 days after receipt of an itemized written request for mileage incurred by the employee. Failure of the health care provider to include with submission of charges the reports or other documents required by the Board, constitutes a defense for the employer or insurer's failure to pay the submitted charges within 30 days of receipt or within 15 days of receipt of an itemized written request for mileage incurred by the employee; however, the employer or insurer must submit to the health care provider written notice indicating the need for further documentation within 30 days of receipt of the charges or within 15 days of an itemized written request for mileage incurred by the employee and failure to do so will be deemed a waiver of the right to defend a claim for failure to pay such charges in a timely fashion on the ground that the charges were not properly accompanied by required documentation. Such waiver shall not extend to any other defense the employer and insurer may have with respect to a claim of untimely payment.</p>
          <p>The employer, insurer, or physician requesting review must comply with the requirements of the statute, Board Rules, and rules of the appropriate peer review organization before the Board will rule on any disputed charges.</p>
          <p>If there is no appropriate peer review organization, the party requesting review may request a mediation conference by filing Form WC-14 with the Board. The charges submitted which conform to the list as published by the Board shall be prima facie proof of the usual, customary, and reasonable charges for the medical services provided.</p>
          <p>The employer/insurer shall, within 30 days from the date that a decision regarding the peer review of charges or treatment is issued by a peer review organization, make payment of disputed charges based upon the recommendations, or request a mediation conference or an evidentiary hearing. The peer review organization shall serve a copy of its decision upon the employee if unrepresented, or the employee's attorney. A physician whose fee has been reduced by the peer review organization shall have 30 days from the date that the recommendation is mailed to request a mediation or hearing. In the event of a hearing or mediation conference, the recommendations of the peer review organization shall be evidence of the usual, customary, and reasonable charges.</p>
          <p>In cases where the peer review organization recommends that the fee be reduced, the employer/insurer shall pay the physician the fee amount recommended by the peer review organization less the fee for peer review initially paid by the employer/insurer. In the event the peer review organization recommends the entire fee be disallowed, the employer/insurer may automatically deduct the fee for the peer review from future allowable expenses submitted by the physician for treatment or services rendered to the employee arising out of the same injury.</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2007, designated the existing provisions of subsection (b) as paragraph (b)(1), and added the last sentence, and added paragraph (b)(2).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2010, deleted the former last sentence of the second paragraph of paragraph (c)(2), which read: "A request for peer review of any other treatment or charges shall attach to the application two copies of the charges and all of the reports dealing with the treatment of the injured employee."</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2011, deleted "Medical Directors Solutions, LLC;" preceding "Georgia Psychological Association" in the concluding paragraph of paragraph (c)(2).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2013, added the third sentence in subsection (a); inserted "or employee" in the last sentence of paragraph (b)(1); substituted "payer" for "payor" in the first sentence of paragraph (a)(2); in paragraph (c)(3), inserted "or within 15 days of an itemized written request for mileage incurred by the employee" three times, and deleted "its" preceding "submission" in the second sentence; in the ending paragraph of subsection (c), inserted "or any reimbursement for health care goods or services paid by the employee or any charges for mileage incurred by the employee are not paid when due" in the first sentence, and substituted "percent" for "%" in the second, third, and fourth sentences; and added the fourth sentence in subsection (e).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2014, substituted the present provisions of the undesignated paragraph of paragraph (c)(2) for the former provisions, which read: "The peer review committees approved by the Board are as follows: Georgia Psychological Association; Georgia Chiropractic Association, Inc.; Appropriate Utilization Group, LLC; and such other committees as the Board has posted as so designated at its Atlanta office."</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2015, substituted "peer review organization" for "peer review committee" throughout; in paragraph (c)(2), deleted "; Exam Works" following "Dane Street", in paragraph (c)(7), substituted "fee for per review" for "filing costs", substituted "organization" for "committee" and substituted "fee" for "filing costs".</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 1, 2017, inserted "or CDT" in three places in subsection (a) and deleted "Dane Street" before "and such other organizations" near the end of the undesignated paragraph following paragraph (c)(2).</p>
          <p>The revision effective July 16, 2018, inserted "Medical Consultants Network (MCN);" in the undesignated paragraph following paragraph (c)(2).</p>
          <p>The revision effective September 1, 2019, in the undesignated language following paragraph (c)(2), inserted "(psychologists)", "(chiropractors)", and "(physical therapists)", and deleted "Medical Consultants Network (MCN)" preceding "and such other organizations."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
