<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-208/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_208">
        <num>34-15-208</num>
        <content>
          <p>All provisions of this Rule constitute the minimum requirements necessary to obtain and maintain certification as a WC/MCO under the Georgia Workers' Compensation Act. To obtain certification of a plan, application shall be submitted on a Form WC-208a accompanied by a non-refundable fee of $1,000.00 and shall include the following information:</p>
          <p>A WC/MCO must contract with the employer or the workers' compensation insurer of an employer.In the event multiple WC/MCO's are contracted to cover the same employer, each employee shall have the initial election of the WC/MCO that will manage the employee's care, and utilization of a WC/MCO will be deemed an election.</p>
          <p>An employee who gives notice to an employer of a compensable injury shall receive medical services in the manner prescribed by the terms and conditions of the WC/MCO contract in effect at the time medical services are rendered.</p>
          <p>To insure continuity of care, the WC/MCO contract shall specify the manner in which an injured employee will receive medical services when a WC/MCO contract or contract with the health care provider terminates. The employee may continue to treat with the health care provider or the WC/MCO under the terminating contract until such time as the employee elects to utilize the employer's current posted panel of physicians, conformed panel of physicians or WC/MCO, or a change of physician is granted.</p>
          <p>A WC/MCO shall provide the Board with a copy of the following contracts:</p>
          <p>Prospective new participating health care providers under a WC/MCO shall submit an application to the WC/MCO. A director, executive director or administrator may approve the application under the requirements of the WC/MCO. The managed care plan shall verify that each new participating health care provider meets all licensing, registration and certification requirements necessary to practice in Georgia or other applicable state of practice.</p>
          <p>A participating provider may elect to terminate participation in the WC/MCO or to be subject to cancellation by the managed care plan under the requirements of the managed care plan. Upon termination of a provider contract, the managed care plan shall make alternate arrangements to provide continuing medical services for an affected injured employee under the plan in compliance with Board Rule 208(b)(3).</p>
          <p>Emergency treatment;</p>
          <p>When the employee is referred to the provider by the managed care organization;</p>
          <p>By order of the Board, or by consent of the parties.</p>
          <p>The WC/MCO must implement a system for peer review to improve patient care and cost effectiveness of treatment.Peer review must include a majority of health care providers of the same discipline being reviewed.The peer review must be designed to evaluate the quality of care given by a health care provider to a patient or patients.The plan must describe in its application for certification how the providers will be selected for review, the nature of the review and how the results will be used.</p>
          <p>The WC/MCO must implement a plan for utilization review. The program must profile each medical supplier and include the collection, review, analysis of group data (utilizing CPT-4 codes) to improve overall quality of care, efficient use of resources and duration of disability.In its application for certification, the WC/MCO must specify the data that will be collected, how the data will be analyzed and how the results will be applied to improve patient care and increase cost effectiveness of treatment.</p>
          <p>The medical case manager must monitor, evaluate and coordinate the delivery of quality, cost effective medical treatment and other health services needed by an injured employee, and must promote an appropriate, prompt return to work. Medical case managers must facilitate communication between the employee, employee's representative, employer, employer's representative, insurer, health care provider, WC/MCO and, when authorized, any qualified rehabilitation consultant to achieve these goals. The WC/MCO must describe in its application for certification how injured employees will be subject to case management, the services to be provided, and who will provide services.</p>
          <p>Case management for an employee covered by a WC/MCO must be provided by a licensed registered health care professional holding one of the following certifications: Certified Rehabilitation Registered Nurse (CRRN), Certified Case Manager (CCM), Certified Occupational Health Nurse (COHN),Certified Occupation Health Nurse Specialist (COHN-S), Certified Disability Management Specialist (CDMS), Certified Rehabilitation Counselor (CRC), Work Adjustment/Vocational Evaluation Specialist (WAVES), or Licensed Professional Counselor (LPC).Case managers must have at least one year experience in workers' compensation. In catastrophic cases, case management must include assignment to a Board-registered rehabilitation supplier, who has been designated by the board as qualified to manage catastrophic cases (Rule 200.1 (f)(4)). If qualified, the case manager may register with the Board to serve as the catastrophic rehabilitation supplier.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
