<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/34-15-61/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_15_61">
        <num>34-15-61</num>
        <content>
          <p>All employers operating under the Georgia Workers' Compensation Law shall post notice as hereinafter provided upon durable material publicly and permanently in a conspicuous place in each business location. [Pursuant to direction of the State Board of Workers' Compensation, the following website address has been provided: www.sbwc.georgia.gov.] Upon request, the Board will furnish suitable notices free of charge. The notice shall be in such form that it can be understood by all employees and read as follows:</p>
          <p>The Board furnishes, upon request, copies of forms required by law. Use originals of the forms or approved copies of the original forms.The text and format of a Board form may not be altered, except with the specific written permission of the Executive Director. Generally, when filing any Board form or document with the Board, file only the original and no copies.Do not use tabs to separate documents.</p>
          <p>Form WC-1. Employer's First Report of Injury. Employers shall complete Section A immediately upon knowledge of an injury and submit the form to their insurer. The insurer, self-insurer, or group self-insurer shall place their SBWC ID Number in the appropriate box on this form.Insurers who receive a Form WC-1 from an employer shall clearly stamp the date of receipt on the form. Insurers and self-insurers shall complete Section B or C and mail the original to the Board and a copy to the employee within 21 days of the employer's knowledge of disability. Use this form to report accidents and injuries for cases involving more than seven days of lost time. Cases with seven or less days of lost time should be reported on Form WC-26. For previously designated "medical only" claims, you must check the appropriate box in Section B or C.In death cases with accident dates before July 1, 1995, a copy of Form WC-1 shall also be filed with the Administrator of the Subsequent Injury Trust Fund at the same time it is mailed to the Board. In accepted catastrophic claims, Form WC-1 shall be filed within 48 hours of the employer's acceptance of a catastrophic injury as compensable.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
