<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/39-4-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_39_4_4">
        <num>39-4-4</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children is enacted into law and entered into with all other jurisdictions legally joining therein in form substantially as follows:</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE I. PURPOSE AND POLICY.</p>
          <p>It is the purpose and policy of the party states to cooperate with each other in the interstate placement of children to the end that:</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE II. DEFINITIONS.</p>
          <p>"Child" means a person who, by reason of minority, is legally subject to parental, guardianship or similar control.</p>
          <p>"Sending agency" means a party state, or officer or employee thereof; a subdivision of a party state, or officer or employee thereof; a court of a party state; a person, corporation, association, charitable agency or other entity which sends, brings, or causes to be sent or brought any child to another party state.</p>
          <p>"Receiving state" means the state to which a child is sent, brought, or caused to be sent or brought, whether by public authorities or private persons or agencies, and whether for placement with state or local public authorities or for placement with private agencies or persons.</p>
          <p>"Placement" means the arrangement for the care of a child in a family free or boarding home or in a child-caring agency or institution but does not include any institution caring for the mentally ill, mentally defective or epileptic or any institution primarily educational in character, and any hospital or other medical facility.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE III. CONDITIONS FOR PLACEMENT.</p>
          <p>No sending agency shall send, bring, or cause to be sent or brought into any other party state any child for placement in foster care or as a preliminary to a possible adoption unless the sending agency shall comply with each and every requirement set forth in this Article and with the applicable laws of the receiving state governing the placement of children therein.</p>
          <p>Prior to sending, bringing or causing any child to be sent or brought into a receiving state for placement in foster care or as a preliminary to a possible adoption, the sending agency shall furnish the appropriate public authorities in the receiving state written notice of the intention to send, bring, or place the child in the receiving state. The notice shall contain:</p>
          <p>Any public officer or agency in a receiving state which is in receipt of a notice pursuant to paragraph (b) of this Article may request of the sending agency, or any other appropriate officer or agency of or in the sending agency's state, and shall be entitled to receive therefrom, such supporting or additional information as it may deem necessary under the circumstances to carry out the purpose and policy of this compact.</p>
          <p>The child shall not be sent, brought or caused to be sent or brought into the receiving state until the appropriate public authorities in the receiving state shall notify the sending agency, in writing, to the effect that the proposed placement does not appear to be contrary to the interests of the child.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE IV. PENALTY FOR ILLEGAL PLACEMENT.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE V. RETENTION OF JURISDICTION.</p>
          <p>The sending agency shall retain jurisdiction over the child sufficient to determine all matters in relation to the custody, supervision, care, treatment and disposition of the child which it would have had if the child had remained in the sending agency's state, until the child is adopted, reaches majority, becomes self-supporting or is discharged with the concurrence of the appropriate authority in the receiving state. Such jurisdiction shall also include the power to effect or cause the return of the child or its transfer to another location and custody pursuant to law. The sending agency shall continue to have financial responsibility for support and maintenance of the child during the period of the placement. Nothing contained herein shall defeat a claim of jurisdiction by a receiving state sufficient to deal with an act of delinquency or crime committed therein.</p>
          <p>When the sending agency is a public agency, it may enter into an agreement with an authorized public or private agency in the receiving state providing for the performance of one or more services in respect of such case by the latter as agent for the sending agency.</p>
          <p>Nothing in this compact shall be construed to prevent a private charitable agency authorized to place children in the receiving state from performing services or acting as agent in that state for a private charitable agency of the sending state; nor to prevent the agency in the receiving state from discharging financial responsibility for the support and maintenance of a child who has been placed on behalf of the sending agency without relieving the responsibility set forth in paragraph (a) hereof.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VI. INSTITUTIONAL CARE OF DELINQUENT CHILDREN.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VII. COMPACT ADMINISTRATOR.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VIII. LIMITATIONS.</p>
          <p>The sending or bringing of a child into a receiving state by his parent, step-parent, grandparent, adult brother or sister, adult uncle or aunt, or his guardian and leaving the child with any such relative or non-agency guardian in the receiving state.</p>
          <p>Any placement, sending or bringing of a child into a receiving state pursuant to any other interstate compact to which both the state from which the child is sent or brought and the receiving state are party, or to any other agreement between said states which has the force of law.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE IX. ENACTMENT AND WITHDRAWAL.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE X. CONSTRUCTION AND SEVERABILITY.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1977, p. 578, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
