<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/42-8-25/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_8_25">
        <num>42-8-25</num>
        <content>
          <p>DCS shall employ officers. DCS may assign one officer to each judicial circuit in this state or, for purposes of assignment, may consolidate two or more judicial circuits and assign one officer thereto. In the event DCS determines that more than one officer is needed for a particular circuit, additional officers may be assigned to the circuit. DCS is authorized to direct any officer to assist any other officer wherever assigned. In the event more than one officer is assigned to the same office or to the same division within a particular judicial circuit, DCS shall designate one of the officers to be in charge.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1956, p. 27, § 5; Ga. L. 1958, p. 15, § 5; Ga. L. 1965, p. 413, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 604, § 4; Ga. L. 2015, p. 422, § 4-1/HB 310.)</p>
          <p>The 2015 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2015, substituted the present provisions of this Code section for the former provisions, which read: "The department shall employ probation supervisors. The department may assign one supervisor to each judicial circuit in this state or, for purposes of assignment, may consolidate two or more judicial circuits and assign one supervisor thereto. In the event the department determines that more than one supervisor is needed for a particular circuit, an additional supervisor or additional supervisors may be assigned to the circuit. The department is authorized to direct any probation supervisor to assist any other probation supervisor wherever assigned. In the event that more than one supervisor is assigned to the same office or to the same division within a particular judicial circuit, the department shall designate one of the supervisors to be in charge." See Editor's notes for applicability.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
