<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/38-3-71/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_38_3_71">
        <num>38-3-71</num>
        <content>
          <p>Section 1. Purpose.</p>
          <p>In order to protect the public through verification of competency and ensure accountability for patient care related activities all states license emergency medical services (EMS) personnel, such as emergency medical technicians (EMTs), advanced EMTs, and paramedics. This Compact is intended to facilitate the day-to-day movement of EMS personnel across state boundaries in the performance of their EMS duties as assigned by an appropriate authority and authorize state EMS offices to afford immediate legal recognition to EMS personnel licensed in a member state. This Compact recognizes that states have a vested interest in protecting the public's health and safety through their licensing and regulation of EMS personnel and that such state regulation shared among the member states will best protect public health and safety. This Compact is designed to achieve the following purposes and objectives:</p>
          <p>Section 2. Definitions.</p>
          <p>In this compact:</p>
          <p>"Advanced Emergency Medical Technician (AEMT)" means: an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p>
          <p>"Adverse Action" means: any administrative, civil, equitable, or criminal action permitted by a state's laws which may be imposed against licensed EMS personnel by a state EMS authority or state court, including, but not limited to, actions against an individual's license such as revocation, suspension, probation, consent agreement, monitoring, or other limitation or encumbrance on the individual's practice, letters of reprimand or admonition, fines, criminal convictions, and state court judgments enforcing adverse actions by the state EMS authority.</p>
          <p>"Alternative program" means: a voluntary, non-disciplinary substance abuse recovery program approved by a state EMS authority.</p>
          <p>"Certification" means: the successful verification of entry-level cognitive and psychomotor competency using a reliable, validated, and legally defensible examination.</p>
          <p>"Commission" means: the national administrative body of which all states that have enacted the compact are members.</p>
          <p>"Emergency Medical Technician (EMT)" means: an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p>
          <p>"Home State" means: a member state where an individual is licensed to practice emergency medical services.</p>
          <p>"License" means: the authorization by a state for an individual to practice as an EMT, AEMT, paramedic, or a level in between EMT and paramedic.</p>
          <p>"Medical Director" means: a physician licensed in a member state who is accountable for the care delivered by EMS personnel.</p>
          <p>"Member State" means: a state that has enacted this compact.</p>
          <p>"Paramedic" means: an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p>
          <p>"Privilege to Practice" means: an individual's authority to deliver emergency medical services in remote states as authorized under this compact.</p>
          <p>"Remote State" means: a member state in which an individual is not licensed.</p>
          <p>"Restricted" means: the outcome of an adverse action that limits a license or the privilege to practice.</p>
          <p>"Rule" means: a written statement by the interstate Commission promulgated pursuant to Section 12 of this compact that is of general applicability; implements, interprets, or prescribes a policy or provision of the compact; or is an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the Commission and has the force and effect of statutory law in a member state and includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</p>
          <p>"Scope of Practice" means: defined parameters of various duties or services that may be provided by an individual with specific credentials. Whether regulated by rule, statute, or court decision, it tends to represent the limits of services an individual may perform.</p>
          <p>"Significant Investigatory Information" means:</p>
          <p>Section 3. Home State Licensure.</p>
          <p>Any member state in which an individual holds a current license shall be deemed a home state for purposes of this compact.</p>
          <p>Any member state may require an individual to obtain and retain a license to be authorized to practice in the member state under circumstances not authorized by the privilege to practice under the terms of this compact.</p>
          <p>A home state's license authorizes an individual to practice in a remote state under the privilege to practice only if the home state:</p>
          <p>Section 4. Compact Privilege to Practice.</p>
          <p>Member states shall recognize the privilege to practice of an individual licensed in another member state that is in conformance with Section 3.</p>
          <p>To exercise the privilege to practice under the terms and provisions of this compact, an individual must:</p>
          <p>Section 5. Conditions of Practice in a Remote State.</p>
          <p>An individual may practice in a remote state under a privilege to practice only in the performance of the individual's EMS duties as assigned by an appropriate authority, as defined in the rules of the Commission, and under the following circumstances:</p>
          <p>Section 6. Relationship to Emergency Management Assistance Compact.</p>
          <p>Upon a member state's governor's declaration of a state of emergency or disaster that activates the Emergency Management Assistance Compact (EMAC), all relevant terms and provisions of EMAC shall apply and to the extent any terms or provisions of this Compact conflicts with EMAC, the terms of EMAC shall prevail with respect to any individual practicing in the remote state in response to such declaration.</p>
          <p>Section 7. Veterans, Service Members Separating from Active Duty Military, and Their Spouses.</p>
          <p>Member states shall consider a veteran, active military service member, and member of the National Guard and Reserves separating from an active duty tour, and a spouse thereof, who holds a current valid and unrestricted NREMT certification at or above the level of the state license being sought as satisfying the minimum training and examination requirements for such licensure.</p>
          <p>Member states shall expedite the processing of licensure applications submitted by veterans, active military service members, and members of the National Guard and Reserves separating from an active duty tour, and their spouses.</p>
          <p>All individuals functioning with a privilege to practice under this Section remain subject to the Adverse Actions provisions of Section 8.</p>
          <p>Section 8. Adverse Actions.</p>
          <p>A home state shall have exclusive power to impose adverse action against an individual's license issued by the home state.</p>
          <p>If an individual's license in any home state is restricted or suspended, the individual shall not be eligible to practice in a remote state under the privilege to practice until the individual's home state license is restored.</p>
          <p>Section 9. Additional Powers Invested in a Member State's EMS Authority.</p>
          <p>A member state's EMS authority, in addition to any other powers granted under state law, is authorized under this compact to:</p>
          <p>Section 10. Establishment of the Interstate Commission for EMS Personnel Practice.</p>
          <p>The Compact states hereby create and establish a joint public agency known as the Interstate Commission for EMS Personnel Practice.</p>
          <p>If a meeting, or portion of a meeting, is closed pursuant to this provision, the Commission's legal counsel or designee shall certify that the meeting may be closed and shall reference each relevant exempting provision. The Commission shall keep minutes that fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in a meeting and shall provide a full and accurate summary of actions taken, and the reasons therefore, including a description of the views expressed. All documents considered in connection with an action shall be identified in such minutes. All minutes and documents of a closed meeting shall remain under seal, subject to release by a majority vote of the Commission or order of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
          <p>The Commission shall, by a majority vote of the delegates, prescribe bylaws and/or rules to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes and exercise the powers of the compact, including, but not limited to:</p>
          <p>For the establishment and meetings of other committees; and</p>
          <p>Governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the Commission;</p>
          <p>Section 11. Coordinated Database.</p>
          <p>The Commission shall provide for the development and maintenance of a coordinated database and reporting system containing licensure, adverse action, and significant investigatory information on all licensed individuals in member states.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of state law to the contrary, a member state shall submit a uniform data set to the coordinated database on all individuals to whom this compact is applicable as required by the rules of the Commission, including:</p>
          <p>Section 12. Rulemaking.</p>
          <p>The Commission shall exercise its rulemaking powers pursuant to the criteria set forth in this Section and the rules adopted thereunder. Rules and amendments shall become binding as of the date specified in each rule or amendment.</p>
          <p>If a majority of the legislatures of the member states rejects a rule, by enactment of a statute or resolution in the same manner used to adopt the Compact, then such rule shall have no further force and effect in any member state.</p>
          <p>Rules or amendments to the rules shall be adopted at a regular or special meeting of the Commission.</p>
          <p>Prior to promulgation and adoption of a final rule or rules by the Commission, and at least sixty (60) days in advance of the meeting at which the rule will be considered and voted upon, the Commission shall file a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking:</p>
          <p>Section 13. Oversight, Dispute Resolution, and Enforcement.</p>
          <p>Oversight</p>
          <p>If a state in default fails to cure the default, the defaulting state may be terminated from the Compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the member states, and all rights, privileges and benefits conferred by this compact may be terminated on the effective date of termination. A cure of the default does not relieve the offending state of obligations or liabilities incurred during the period of default.</p>
          <p>Termination of membership in the compact shall be imposed only after all other means of securing compliance have been exhausted. Notice of intent to suspend or terminate shall be given by the Commission to the governor, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and each of the member states.</p>
          <p>A state that has been terminated is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including obligations that extend beyond the effective date of termination.</p>
          <p>The Commission shall not bear any costs related to a state that is found to be in default or that has been terminated from the compact, unless agreed upon in writing between the Commission and the defaulting state.</p>
          <p>The defaulting state may appeal the action of the Commission by petitioning the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia or the federal district where the Commission has its principal offices. The prevailing member shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorney's fees.</p>
          <p>Dispute Resolution</p>
          <p>Section 14. Date of Implementation of the Interstate Commission for EMS Personnel Practice and Associated Rules, Withdrawal, and Amendment.</p>
          <p>The compact shall come into effect on the date on which the compact statute is enacted into law in the tenth member state. The provisions, which become effective at that time, shall be limited to the powers granted to the Commission relating to assembly and the promulgation of rules. Thereafter, the Commission shall meet and exercise rulemaking powers necessary to the implementation and administration of the compact.</p>
          <p>Any state that joins the compact subsequent to the Commission's initial adoption of the rules shall be subject to the rules as they exist on the date on which the compact becomes law in that state. Any rule that has been previously adopted by the Commission shall have the full force and effect of law on the day the compact becomes law in that state.</p>
          <p>Any member state may withdraw from this compact by enacting a statute repealing the same.</p>
          <p>Section 15. Construction and Severability</p>
          <p>This Compact shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes thereof. If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any state member thereto, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining member states. Nothing in this compact supersedes state law or rules related to licensure of EMS agencies.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
