<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/3-3-7/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_3_7">
        <num>3-3-7</num>
        <content>
          <p>"[
   ] YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of county) be authorized to permit
   and
   [
   ]
   NO
   regulate Sunday sales of distilled spirits or alcoholic beverages for beverage purposes by the drink?"</p>
          <p>All persons desiring to vote for approval of Sunday sales shall vote "Yes," and those persons desiring to vote for rejection of Sunday sales shall vote "No."If more than one-half of the votes cast on the question are for approval of Sunday sales, the governing authority in such counties and the governing authority of all municipalities within such counties may by appropriate resolution or ordinance permit and regulate Sunday sales by licensees.</p>
          <p>The expense of the election shall be borne by the county in which the election is held.It shall be the duty of the superintendent to hold and conduct the election.It shall be his further duty to certify the result thereof to the Secretary of State.</p>
          <p>"[
   ] YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of municipality or county) be authorized to permit and regulate
   Sunday
   [
   ]
   NO
   sales of distilled spirits or alcoholic beverages for beverage purposes by the drink?"</p>
          <p>"[
   ] YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of municipality or county) be authorized to permit and regulate
   Sunday
   [
   ]
   NO
   sales of distilled spirits or alcoholic beverages for beverage purposes by the drink?"</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding this subsection or any other provision of law, all county or municipal resolutions or ordinances enacted prior to April 6, 1984, pursuant to the authorizations granted by subsections (a) through (i) of this Code section are declared to be valid and shall remain in full force and effect unless affirmatively repealed by the governing authority of the county or municipality.</p>
          <p>(j.1) (1)Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, all counties or municipalities in which the governing authority prior to May 8, 2018, has been authorized pursuant to a referendum to permit the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises on Sundays from 12:30 P.M. until 12:00 Midnight in any licensed establishment which derives at least 50 percent of its total annual gross sales from the sale of prepared meals or food in all of the combined retail outlets of the individual establishment where food is served and in any licensed establishment which derives at least 50 percent of its total annual gross income from the rental of rooms for overnight lodging may, by resolution or ordinance conditioned on approval in a referendum, authorize the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises of any such establishments on Sundays for an additional hour and a half during the time period of 11:00 A.M. until 12:30 P.M.</p>
          <p>"[
   ] YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of municipality or county) be to
   permit
   [
   ]
   NO
   and regulate Sunday sales of distilled spirits or alcoholic beverages for beverage purposes by the drink from 11:00 A.M. to 12:30 P.M.?"</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding this subsection or any other provision of law, all county or municipal resolutions or ordinances enacted prior to April 6, 1984, pursuant to the authorizations granted by subsections (a) through (i) of this Code section are declared to be valid and shall remain in full force and effect unless affirmatively repealed by the governing authority of the county or municipality.</p>
          <p>(j.2) (1)Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, on and after August 3, 2020, in all counties or municipalities in which the governing authority has been authorized pursuant to a referendum held under this Code section to permit the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises on Sundays from 12:30 P.M. until 12:00 Midnight and has been authorized pursuant to a referendum held pursuant to subsection (p) of this Code section to permit package sales of malt beverages and wine, but not distilled spirits, on Sundays from 12:30 P.M. to 11:30 P.M., the governing authority of the county or municipality may, by resolution or ordinance conditioned on approval in a referendum, authorize on Sundays from 11:00 A.M. until 12:00 Midnight the sale of:</p>
          <p>"(
   ) YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of municipality or county) be
   authorized
   (
   ) NO
   to permit and regulate Sunday sales of malt beverages and wine by the drink from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight and Sunday sales of malt beverages and wine by the package from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight?"</p>
          <p>"(
   ) YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of municipality or county) be
   authorized
   (
   ) No
   to permit and regulate Sunday sales of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits by the drink from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight and by the package from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight?"</p>
          <p>"[
   ] YES
   Shall Sunday sales of alcoholic beverages by the drink be authorized
   in
   [
   ]
   NO
   (name of municipality)?"</p>
          <p>"(
   ) YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of county or municipality) be authorized to permit and regulate package sales
   by
   (
   ) NO
   retailers of both malt beverages and wine on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M.?"</p>
          <p>Whenever package sales of malt beverages and wine on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M. are authorized by a county or municipality pursuant to this subsection, Sunday package sales by retailers of malt beverages and wine may be made only by licensed retailers that are licensed to sell by the package.</p>
          <p>The provisions of this subsection are in addition to or cumulative of and not in lieu of any other provisions of this title relative to the sale of malt beverages and wine by retailers.</p>
          <p>(p.1)Notwithstanding other laws, in all counties or municipalities in which package sales by retailers of malt beverages and wine, but not distilled spirits, have been authorized on Sunday from 12:30 P.M. to 11: 30 P.M. pursuant to a referendum held under subsection (p) of this Code section and sales of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises on Sundays from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight, including for an additional hour and a half from 11:00 A.M. to 12:30 P.M., have been authorized pursuant to a referendum held under subsection (j) or (j.1) of this Code section, the governing authority of the county or municipality, as appropriate, may by adoption of a resolution or ordinance allow package sales by retailers of malt beverages and wine for consumption off the premises on Sundays from 11:00 A.M. until 12:00 Midnight. The provisions of this subsection are in addition to or cumulative of and not in lieu of any other provisions of this title relative to the sale of alcoholic beverages by retailers.</p>
          <p>"(
   ) YES
   Shall the governing authority of (name of county or municipality) be authorized to permit and regulate package sales by retailers of malt
   beverages,
   (
   )
   NO
   wine, and distilled spirits on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M.?"</p>
          <p>Whenever package sales of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M. are authorized by a county or municipality pursuant to this subsection, Sunday package sales by retailers of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits may be made only by licensed retailers that are licensed to sell by the package.</p>
          <p>The provisions of this subsection are in addition to or cumulative of and not in lieu of any other provisions of this title relative to the sale of alcoholic beverages by retailers.</p>
          <p>(q.1)Notwithstanding other laws, in all counties or municipalities in which package sales by retailers of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits have been authorized on Sundays beginning from 12:30 P.M. to 11:30 P.M. pursuant to a referendum held under subsection (q) of this Code section and sales of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises on Sundays from 11:00 A.M. to 12:00 Midnight have been authorized pursuant to a referendum held under subsection (j) or (j.1) of this Code section, the governing authority of the county or municipality, as appropriate, may by adoption of a resolution or ordinance allow package sales by retailers of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits for consumption off the premises on Sundays from 11:00 A.M. until 12:00 Midnight. The provisions of this subsection are in addition to or cumulative of and not in lieu of any other provisions of this title relative to the sale of alcoholic beverages by retailers.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 5A-507, enacted by Ga. L. 1980, p. 1573, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 540, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 521, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1463, §§ 2, 9; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1768, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1855, §§ 1, 3; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 4; Ga. L. 1983, p. 806, § 5; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 3; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1683, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1685, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1691, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 149, § 3; Ga. L. 1985, p. 1000, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 381, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 232, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 1487, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 8, § 3; Ga. L. 1992, p. 1214, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2929, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 237, § 2; Ga. L. 1994, p. 395, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 830, § 1; Ga. L. 1998, p. 839, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 1225, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1473, § 1; Ga. L. 2011, p. 49, § 1/SB 10; Ga. L. 2013, p. 767, § 1/HB 124; Ga. L. 2014, p. 13, § 1/SB 318; Ga. L. 2015, p. 20, § 1/SB 103; Ga. L. 2018, p. 896, § 1/SB 17; Ga. L. 2020, p. 615, § 2/HB 879; Ga. L. 2021, p. 922, § 3/HB 497.)</p>
          <p>The 2018 amendment,
      effective May 8, 2018, in paragraph (j)(1), inserted "on and after the effective date of this Act," near the beginning and substituted "11:00 A.M." for "12:30 P.M." in the middle; inserted "or her" in the last sentence of the ending undesignated paragraph in paragraph (j)(2); and added subsection (j.1).</p>
          <p>The 2020 amendment,
      effective August 3, 2020, added subsections (j.2), (j.3), (p.1), and (q.1).</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective May 10, 2021, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "in which the governing authority" for "in which governing authority" near the middle of paragraphs (j.2)(1) and (j.3)(1).</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Not less than ten nor more than 20 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday sales to the electors of the county for approval or rejection.
   The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 45 days after the date of the issuance of the call.
   The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof.
   The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate Sunday sales pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance. Not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county or municipality to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday sales to the electors of the county or municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate Sunday sales pursuant to this subsection, but only after a referendum election, shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance conditioned on a referendum. Not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county or municipality to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday sales to the electors of the county or municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate Sunday sales pursuant to this subsection shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance conditioned on approval in a referendum election. Not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county or municipality to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday sales to the electors of the county or municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate such Sunday sales pursuant to this subsection, but only after a referendum election, shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance conditioned on a referendum. Not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county or municipality to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of such Sunday sales to the electors of the county or municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate such Sunday sales pursuant to this subsection, but only after a referendum election, shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance conditioned on a referendum. Not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance, it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the county or municipality to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of such Sunday sales to the electors of the county or municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a resolution or ordinance is approved pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection and by its terms has its effectiveness contingent upon referendum approval pursuant to this paragraph, not less than ten nor more than 60 days after the date of approval of such resolution or ordinance it shall be the duty of the election superintendent of the municipality, whose governing authority approved that resolution or ordinance, to issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday sales to the electors of that municipality for approval or rejection. The superintendent shall set the date of the election for a day not less than 30 nor more than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the call. The superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published in the official organ of the county in which that municipality is located once a week for two weeks immediately preceding the date thereof. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate package sales by retailers of both malt beverages and wine on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M., pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance specifying the hours during such period when such package sales may occur. Upon receipt of the resolution or ordinance, the election superintendent shall issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday package sales by retailers of both malt beverages and wine to the electors of that county or municipality for approval or rejection. The election superintendent shall issue the call and shall conduct the election on a date and in the manner authorized under Code Section 21-2-540. The election superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published once a week for four weeks immediately preceding the date of the election in the official organ of the county. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_3_7__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any governing authority desiring to permit and regulate package sales by retailers of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits on Sundays between the hours of 12:30 P.M. and 11:30 P.M., pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall so provide by proper resolution or ordinance specifying the hours during such period when such package sales may occur. Upon receipt of the resolution or ordinance, the election superintendent shall issue the call for an election for the purpose of submitting the question of Sunday package sales by retailers of malt beverages, wine, and distilled spirits to the electors of that county or municipality for approval or rejection. The election superintendent shall issue the call and shall conduct the election on a date and in the manner authorized under Code Section 21-2-540. The election superintendent shall cause the date and purpose of the election to be published once a week for four weeks immediately preceding the date of the election in the official organ of the county. The ballot shall have written or printed thereon the words:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
