<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/28-5-50/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_28_5_50">
        <num>28-5-50</num>
        <content>
          <p>Except as otherwise provided in this Code section, no regulation, rule, order, or administrative law which would have a fiscal impact which in the aggregate exceeds $5 million on local political subdivisions in this state shall be valid unless 30 days prior to its adoption by a board, commission, agency, department, officer, or other authority of the government of this state, except the General Assembly, the courts, and the Governor, such board, commission, agency, department, officer, or other authority shall file a fiscal note with the members of the General Assembly. Any local political subdivisions that will be affected by the proposed regulation, rule, policy, order, or administrative law, upon request, shall immediately be furnished with a copy of the fiscal note by the board, commission, agency, department, officer, or other authority. This Code section shall not apply to an emergency regulation, rule, order, or administrative law as described by subsection (b) of Code Section 50-13-4, to any rule or regulation adopted or order issued pursuant to legislation exempted from Code Section 28-5-49, or to any other order issued to abate or prevent violations of specific statutory provisions enacted by the General Assembly.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1981, p. 1809, ยง 4; Ga. L. 1995, p. 1189, ยง .5.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
