<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-11-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_11_6">
        <num>48-11-6</num>
        <content>
          <p>The commissioner may suspend or refuse to renew a license issued to any person under this chapter for violation of any provision of this chapter or Chapters 13 and 13A of Title 10 or of the rules and regulations made pursuant to those chapters. After notice and opportunity for hearing, the commissioner may revoke a license issued to any person under this chapter for violation of any provision of this chapter or of any rule or regulation of the commissioner made pursuant to this chapter or Chapters 13 and 13A of Title 10 or of the rules and regulations made pursuant to those chapters. Any person aggrieved by the suspension of or refusal to renew his or her license may apply to the commissioner for a hearing as provided in subsection (a) of Code Section 48-11-18; and any person aggrieved by the action of the commissioner in revoking or refusing to renew his or her license after hearing may further appeal to the courts as provided in subsection (b) of Code Section 48-11-18. No legal proceedings or other action by the commissioner shall be barred or abated by the suspension, revocation, or expiration of any license issued under this chapter.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1955, p. 268, § 7; Code 1933, § 91A-5506, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2; Ga. L. 2016, p. 528, § 5/HB 899; Ga. L. 2020, p. 257, § 2/SB 375.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
