<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-16/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_3_16">
        <num>48-3-16</num>
        <content>
          <p>If the respondent in an action provided for in Code Section 48-3-13 or 48-3-14 does not appear in answer to the rule, the superior court shall ascertain for itself that service of the rule has been perfected in accordance with Code Section 48-3-13 or 48-3-14 and shall enter a finding to that effect. The superior court shall further order that the tax execution described in the petition, with the tax, penalties, and interest being stated separately, be reduced to a judgment of the court and that all costs of the action, including, but not limited to, advertising costs as per the sworn statement of the costs submitted by the commissioner, be added to the judgment and charged against the respondent. A copy of the finding and order shall be sent by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery by the clerk of the court to the respondent at the foreign address shown in the published notice and to the Secretary of State of this state when he is appointed as agent of the nonresident to receive service. The clerk of the court shall enter this action on the original order of the court.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1957, p. 619, ยง 7; Code 1933, ยง 91A-319, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, ยง 2; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, ยง 3.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
