<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-3-18/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_3_18">
        <num>48-3-18</num>
        <content>
          <p>When action is required to be taken by the commissioner, it shall be sufficient compliance with this chapter if the action is done by his deputy or his attorney. When action is required of the clerk of the superior court, it shall be sufficient compliance with this chapter if the action is done by his deputy. When the various papers and processes required to be mailed to the Secretary of State are received by him and it appears to him that a copy of the paper or process has been mailed by the commissioner to a known address of the respondent, a second mailing shall not be required of the Secretary of State to the same address; but he shall keep the copy received by him on file as a source of information for any inquiry from the respondent, for whom the Secretary of State is attorney in fact, concerning the respondent's tax liabilities and obligations incident to his taxable acts or activities within this state. When action is required of the Secretary of State, it shall be sufficient compliance with this chapter if the action is done by his deputy.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1957, p. 619, ยง 9; Code 1933, ยง 91A-321, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, ยง 2.)</p>
          <p>RESEARCH REFERENCES</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
