<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_4_3">
        <num>48-4-3</num>
        <content>
          <p>The tax collector or tax commissioner may place his executions in the hands of any constable of the county, who shall be authorized to collect or levy the executions in any part of the county. The constable or other levying officer to whom the tax collector or tax commissioner delivers the tax executions for collection shall proceed promptly to enforce by levy and sale the collection of the executions. The levying or collecting officer shall make prompt settlements with the tax collector or tax commissioner and in no event shall be allowed longer than 90 days from the time the executions are placed in his hands within which to make final settlement with the tax collector or tax commissioner and return to the tax collector or tax commissioner the tax collected and the uncollected executions with proper entries on the executions. Any constable or other levying officer who fails or refuses to make a final return or settlement within the time provided in this Code section shall forfeit all costs due him on the executions and shall be subject to be ruled before any court of competent jurisdiction and made to account as required by this Code section.</p>
          <p>(Orig. Code 1863, § 812; Code 1868, § 892; Code 1873, § 889; Code 1882, § 889; Civil Code 1895, § 906; Ga. L. 1899, p. 26, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 1166; Code 1933, § 92-8104; Code 1933, § 91A-403, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
