<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-4-81/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_4_81">
        <num>48-4-81</num>
        <content>
          <p>When recorded, please
   CROSS-REFERENCE:
   return to:
   Deed Book ______, page ______,
   ________________________
   ______________ County, Georgia Records
   ________________________
   ________________________
   STATE OF GEORGIA
   COUNTY OF ______________</p>
          <p>TAX DEED</p>
          <p>This indenture (the "Deed") made this ____________ day of ____________________________, ______________, by and between ________________________, a ________________________ ("Grantor") and ________________________, a ________________________ ("Grantee").</p>
          <p>WITNESSETH</p>
          <p>WHEREAS, on the ____________ day of ____________________________, ________, during the legal hours of sale, Grantor did expose for sale at public outcry to the highest bidder for cash before the courthouse door in ____________ County, Georgia, the Property (as hereinafter defined) at which sale Grantee was the highest and best bidder for the sum of $______________ and the Property was then and there knocked off to Grantee for said sum. The sale was made by Grantor pursuant to and by virtue of the power and authority granted to it in that certain Order granted ____________________________, __________, Case No. ____________, Superior Court of ______________ County, Georgia (the "Order"). Said sale was made after advertising the time, place, and terms thereof in the ____________________________________, published in ____________________________, Georgia, in the aforesaid county, and being the publication in which Sheriff's advertisements for said county are now published, once a week for four consecutive weeks prior to said sale on the __________, __________, __________, and __________ of ____________, ____________, and said advertisement in all respects complied with the requirements of Code Section ______________ of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated. Notice of the time, place, and terms of the sale of the Property was given pursuant to Code Section ______________ of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated. Said sale was made for the purpose of paying the ad valorem taxes owed to ________________________________________, the interest and penalties on said indebtedness, the expenses of the sale including attorneys' fees, all of which were mature and payable because of failure of the owner to pay the ad valorem taxes owed.
   NOW, THEREFORE, Grantor, acting under and by virtue of the Order and pursuant to Code Section ________________________ of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated, for and in consideration of the facts hereinbefore recited, has bargained, sold, and conveyed and does hereby bargain, sell, and convey unto Grantee, its successors and assigns, the following described property (herein referred to as the "Property"); to wit:
   All that tract or parcel of land lying and being in Land Lot __________ of the __________ District, ____________ County, Georgia, and being more particularly described on
      Exhibit "A"
      attached hereto and by this reference made a part hereof.
   This Deed is given subject to all restrictions and easements, if any, to which the Deed is junior and inferior in terms of priority, and any and all tax liens which pursuant to subsection (b) of Code Section 48-2-56 of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated are superior to the rights conveyed herein relating to the Property.
   TO HAVE AND TO HOLD, the Property unto Grantee, its successors and assigns in fee simple.
   IN WITNESS WHEREOF, Grantor, has caused its duly authorized officer to sign and seal this Deed as of the day and year first above written.
   ________________________________________________________________
   Signed, sealed, and
   delivered in the
   presence of:
   ________________________________________
   Unofficial Witness
   By: ____________________________________________________ (SEAL)
   Its: ___________________________________________________________
   ____________________________
   Notary Public
   Commission Data:
   ____________________________
   (NOTARIAL SEAL)</p>
          <p>EXHIBIT A</p>
          <p>Description of the Property</p>
          <p>__________________________________________________________________________
   __________________________________________________________________________
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Together with all right, title, and interest running with the above-described property but not taxed under a separate tax reference number as delineated on the tax maps of the petitioner for the year(s) for the taxes being foreclosed.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_48_4_81__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The form of the deed provided for in subsection (d) of this Code section shall be substantially as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
