<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-5-311/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_5_311">
        <num>48-5-311</num>
        <content>
          <p>(a.1)Appeal administrator.</p>
          <p>(a.2)Establishment of boards of equalization.</p>
          <p>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, there is established in each county of this state a county board of equalization to consist of three members and three alternate members appointed in the manner and for the term set forth in this Code section. In those counties having more than 10,000 parcels of real property, the county governing authority, by appropriate resolution adopted on or before November 1 of each year, may elect to have selected one additional county board of equalization for each 10,000 parcels of real property in the county or for any part of a number of parcels in the county exceeding 10,000 parcels.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding any part of this subsection to the contrary, at any time the governing authority of a county makes a request to the grand jury of the county for additional alternate members of boards of equalization, the grand jury shall appoint the number of alternate members so requested to each board of equalization, such number not to exceed a maximum of 21 alternate members for each of the boards. The alternate members of the boards shall be duly qualified and authorized to serve on any of the boards of equalization of the county. The members of each board of equalization may designate a chairperson and two vice chairpersons of each such board of equalization. The appeal administrator shall have administrative authority in all matters governing the conduct and business of the boards of equalization so as to provide oversight and supervision of such boards and scheduling of appeals. Any combination of members or alternate members of any such board of equalization of the county shall be competent to exercise the power and authority of the board. Any person designated as an alternate member of any such board of equalization of the county shall be competent to serve in such capacity as provided in this Code section upon appointment and taking of oath.</p>
          <p>(e.1)Appeals to hearing officer.</p>
          <p>(A) For any dispute involving the value or uniformity of a parcel of nonhomestead real property with a fair market value in excess of $500,000.00 as shown on the taxpayer's annual notice of current assessment under Code Section 48-5-306, at the option of the taxpayer, an appeal may be submitted to a hearing officer in accordance with this subsection. If such taxpayer owns nonhomestead real property contiguous to such qualified nonhomestead real property, at the option of the taxpayer, such contiguous property may be consolidated with the qualified property for purposes of the hearing under this subsection.</p>
          <p>Individuals desiring to serve as hearing officers and who are either state certified general real property appraisers or state certified residential real property appraisers as classified by the Georgia Real Estate Commission and the Georgia Real Estate Appraisers Board for real property appeals or are designated appraisers by a nationally recognized appraiser's organization for wireless property appeals shall complete and submit an application, a list of counties the hearing officer is willing to serve, disqualification questionnaire, and resume and be approved by the Georgia Real Estate Commission and the Georgia Real Estate Appraisers Board to serve as a hearing officer. Such board shall annually publish a list of qualified and approved hearing officers for Georgia.</p>
          <p>The appeal administrator shall furnish any hearing officer so selected the necessary facilities.</p>
          <p>An appeal shall be effected by emailing, if the county board of tax assessors has adopted a written policy consenting to electronic service, or by filing with the county board of tax assessors a notice of appeal to a hearing officer within 45 days from the date of mailing the notice of assessment pursuant to Code Section 48-5-306. A written objection to an assessment of real property or wireless property received by a county board of tax assessors stating the taxpayer's election to appeal to a hearing officer and showing the location of the real property or wireless property contained in the assessment notice shall be deemed a notice of appeal by the taxpayer.</p>
          <p>The county board of tax assessors may for no more than 90 days review the taxpayer's written appeal, and if changes or corrections are made by the county board of tax assessors, the board shall notify the taxpayer in writing of such changes. Within 30 days of the county board of tax assessors' mailing of such notice, the taxpayer may notify the county board of tax assessors in writing that the changes or corrections made by the county board of tax assessors are not acceptable, in which case, the county board of tax assessors shall, within 30 days of the date of mailing of such taxpayer's notification, send or deliver all necessary documentation to the appeal administrator, in paper or electronic format as agreed upon by the county board of tax assessors and appeal administrator, and mail a copy to the taxpayer or, alternatively, forward the appeal to the board of equalization if so elected by the taxpayer and such election is included in the taxpayer's notification that the changes are not acceptable. If, after review, the county board of tax assessors determines that no changes or corrections are warranted, the county board of tax assessors shall notify the taxpayer of such decision. The taxpayer may elect to forward the appeal to the board of equalization by notifying the county board of tax assessors within 30 days of the mailing of the county board of tax assessor's notice of no changes or corrections. Upon the expiration of 30 days following the mailing of the county board of tax assessors' notice of no changes or corrections, the county board of tax assessors shall certify the notice of appeal and send or deliver all necessary documentation to the appeal administrator, in paper or electronic format as agreed upon by the county board of tax assessors and appeal administrator, for the appeal to the hearing officer, or board of equalization if elected by the taxpayer, and mail a copy to the taxpayer. If the county board of tax assessors fails to respond in writing, either with changes or no changes, to the taxpayer within 180 days after receiving the taxpayer's notice of appeal, the property valuation asserted by the taxpayer on the property tax return or the taxpayer's notice of appeal shall become the assessed fair market value for the taxpayer's property for the tax year under appeal.</p>
          <p>(A) The appeal administrator shall randomly select from such list a hearing officer who shall have experience or expertise in hearing or appraising the type of property that is the subject of appeal to hear the appeal, unless the taxpayer and the county board of tax assessors mutually agree upon a hearing officer from such list. The appeal administrator shall notify the taxpayer and the taxpayer's attorney in compliance with subsection (o) of this Code section of the name of the hearing officer and transmit a copy of the hearing officer's disqualification questionnaire and resume provided for under paragraph (2) of this subsection. If no hearing officer is appointed or if no hearing is scheduled within 180 days after the county board of tax assessors receives the taxpayer's notice of appeal, the property valuation asserted by the taxpayer on the property tax return or the taxpayer's notice of appeal shall become the assessed fair market value for the taxpayer's property for the tax year under appeal, and subsection (c) of Code Section 48-5-299 shall apply. The hearing officer, in conjunction with all parties to the appeal, shall set a time and place to hear evidence and testimony from both parties. The hearing shall take place in the county where the property is located, or such other place as mutually agreed to by the parties and the hearing officer. The hearing officer shall provide electronic or written notice to the parties personally or by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery not less than ten days before the hearing. Such written notice shall advise each party that he or she may request a list of witnesses, documents, or other written evidence to be presented at the hearing by the other party. Such request must be made not less than ten days prior to the hearing date, and such information shall be provided to the requesting party not less than seven days prior to the time of the hearing. Any failure to comply with this requirement shall be grounds for an automatic continuance or for exclusion of such witnesses, documents, or other written evidence.</p>
          <p>(g.1)Valuation. The provisions in subsection (c) of Code Section 48-5-299 shall apply to the valuation, unless otherwise waived in writing by both parties, as to:</p>
          <p>The valuation established or announced by any county board of equalization, arbitrator, hearing officer, or superior court; and</p>
          <p>Any written agreement or settlement of valuation reached by the county board of tax assessors and the taxpayer as permitted by this Code section.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1913, p. 123, § 6; Ga. L. 1918, p. 230, § 1; Ga. L. 1931, p. 7, § 85; Code 1933, § 92-6912; Ga. L. 1958, p. 387, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 1094, §§ 1-9; Ga. L. 1973, p. 709, § 1; Ga. L. 1974, p. 609, §§ 2-4; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1090, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1976, p. 276, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 366, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 1744, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 588, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 903, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 1009, § 1; Code 1933, § 91A-1449, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2; Ga. L. 1979, p. 519, § 2; Ga. L. 1980, p. 1722, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 1554, § 5; Ga. L. 1983, p. 576, § 2; Ga. L. 1983, p. 1158, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 48; Ga. L. 1984, p. 352, § 3; Ga. L. 1986, p. 419, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 220, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1988, p. 487, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1122, § 4; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1361, § 1; Ga. L. 1991, p. 664, § 1; Ga. L. 1991, p. 1110, § 2; Ga. L. 1992, p. 1678, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2352, § 1; Ga. L. 1993, p. 435, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1993, p. 1777, § 3; Ga. L. 1994, p. 318, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1994, p. 787, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1051, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1088, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1823, § 2; Ga. L. 1995, p. 10, § 48; Ga. L. 1999, p. 1043, § 3; Ga. L. 2000, p. 136, § 48; Ga. L. 2000, p. 873, §§ 2, 3; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3; Ga. L. 2001, p. 495, § 1; Ga. L. 2004, p. 455, § 3; Ga. L. 2006, p. 769, § 1/SB 597; Ga. L. 2008, p. 1149, §§ 4, 5, 6/HB 1081; Ga. L. 2009, p. 216, §§ 1, 2/SB 240; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1104, §§ 2-1, 4-3, 6-1/SB 346; Ga. L. 2013, p. 655, § 5/HB 197; Ga. L. 2014, p. 672, § 4/HB 755; Ga. L. 2015, p. 1219, §§ 15, 16/HB 202; Ga. L. 2016, p. 166, § 5/SB 258; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 48/HB 737; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 48/HB 323; Ga. L. 2018, p. 162, § 2/HB 374; Ga. L. 2019, p. 656, § 2/HB 183; Ga. L. 2019, p. 1056, § 48/SB 52; Ga. L. 2020, p. 254, § 1/SB 410; Ga. L. 2021, p. 377, § 1/HB 292; Ga. L. 2021, p. 922, § 48/HB 497.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
