<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-86/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_8_86">
        <num>48-8-86</num>
        <content>
          <p>If the imposition of the tax provided in Code Section 48-8-82 is approved in a referendum election as provided by Code Section 48-8-85, the governing authority of the county whose geographical boundary is conterminous with that of the special district and the governing authority of each qualified municipality located wholly or partially within the district shall each adopt a resolution during the first 30 days following the certification of the result of the election imposing the tax authorized by Code Section 48-8-82 on behalf of the county and each qualified municipality located wholly or partially within the special district. The resolution shall be effective on the first day of the next succeeding calendar quarter which begins more than 80 days after the adoption of the resolution. With respect to services which are regularly billed on a monthly basis, however, the resolution shall become effective with the first regular billing period coinciding with or following the otherwise effective date of the resolution. A certified copy of the resolution shall be forwarded to the commissioner so that it will be received within five days after its adoption.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 984, § 2; Ga. L. 1976, p. 1019, § 1; Code 1933, § 91A-4604, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2; Ga. L. 1979, p. 446, § 1; Code 1933, § 91A-4606, enacted by Ga. L. 1979, p. 446, § 2.)</p>
          <p>OPINIONS OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
