<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-30/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_8_30">
        <num>48-8-30</num>
        <content>
          <p>(c.1) (1) (A)Every purchaser of tangible personal property at retail outside this state from a dealer when such property is to be used, consumed, distributed, or stored for use or consumption in this state, shall be liable for a tax on the purchase at the rate of 4 percent of the sales price of the purchase. The tax shall be paid by the purchaser to the retailer making the sale, as provided in this article. The retailer shall remit the tax to the commissioner as provided in this article, and when received by the commissioner, the tax shall be a credit against the tax imposed on the retailer.</p>
          <p>(e.1) (1)Every person who leases, as lessor, or rents tangible personal property outside this state for use within this state shall be liable for a tax at the rate of 4 percent of the sales price paid for that lease or rental if that person is a dealer, as defined in Code Section 48-8-2, and title to that property remains in that person. It shall be prima-facie evidence that such property is to be used within this state if that property is delivered in this state to the lessee or renter of such property, or to the agent of either. The tax shall be paid by the lessee or renter and payment of the tax shall be made to the lessor or person receiving rental payments for that property, which person shall be the dealer for purposes of this article. The dealer shall remit the tax to the commissioner as provided in this article and, when received by the commissioner, the tax shall be a credit against the tax imposed on the dealer. Every person who is a dealer, as defined in Code Section 48-8-2, and who leases or rents tangible personal property outside this state to be delivered in this state to the lessee, renter, or agent of either shall be a dealer and shall be liable as such for a tax on the lease or rental at the rate of 4 percent of the sales price from such leases or rentals or the amount of taxes collected by that dealer for leases or rentals of tangible personal property delivered in this state, whichever is greater.</p>
          <p>No lease or rental shall be taxable to the dealer which is not taxable to the lessee or renter. The tax imposed by this subsection shall be subject to the credit granted by this article for like taxes previously paid in another state. This subsection shall not be construed to require a duplication in the payment of the tax.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1951, p. 360, § 2; Ga. L. 1960, p. 153, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 284, § 1; Code 1933, § 91A-4502, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2; Ga. L. 1980, p. 10, § 24; Ga. L. 1989, p. 62, § 5; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1243, §§ 2-4; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 48; Ga. L. 1996, p. 1635, § 1; Ga. L. 1998, p. 602, § 4; Ga. L. 2001, p. 4, § 48; Ga. L. 2001, p. 984, § 17; Ga. L. 2007, p. 309, § 2/HB 219; Ga. L. 2010, p. 662, § 7/HB 1221; Ga. L. 2011, p. 674, § 1-4/HB 117; Ga. L. 2013, p. 141, § 48/HB 79; Ga. L. 2015, p. 236, § 5-5/HB 170; Ga. L. 2018, p. 259, § 2/HB 61; Ga. L. 2019, p. 282, § 2/HB 182; Ga. L. 2020, p. 1, § 2/HB 276.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
