<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/48-8-87/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48_8_87">
        <num>48-8-87</num>
        <content>
          <p>The tax levied pursuant to this article shall be exclusively administered and collected by the commissioner for the use and benefit of each county whose geographical boundary is conterminous with that of a special district and of each qualified municipality located wholly or partially therein. Such administration and collection shall be accomplished in the same manner and subject to the same applicable provisions, procedures, and penalties provided in Article 1 of this chapter, except that the joint tax provided in this article shall be applicable to sales of motor fuels as prepaid local tax as that term is defined in Code Section 48-8-2; provided, however, that all moneys collected from each taxpayer by the commissioner shall be applied first to such taxpayer's liability for taxes owed the state. Dealers shall be allowed a percentage of the amount of the tax due and accounted for and shall be reimbursed in the form of a deduction in submitting, reporting, and paying the amount due if such amount is not delinquent at the time of payment. The deduction shall be at the rate and subject to the requirements specified under subsections (b) through (f) of Code Section 48-8-50.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 984, § 2; Code 1933, § 91A-4605, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 309, § 2; Ga. L. 1979, p. 446, § 1; Code 1933, § 91A-4607, enacted by Ga. L. 1979, p. 446, § 2; Ga. L. 1992, p. 815, § 2; Ga. L. 2007, p. 309, § 5/HB 219; Ga. L. 2009, p. 8, § 48/SB 46; Ga. L. 2010, p. 662, § 20/HB 1221.)</p>
          <p>JUDICIAL DECISIONS</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
