<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-16-80/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_16_80">
        <num>47-16-80</num>
        <content>
          <p>In addition to listing and claiming credit for prior services as a sheriff under paragraph (4) of Code Section 47-16-40, the applicant may elect to list and claim credit for service in the armed forces of the United States, not to exceed four years, and service as a peace officer other than as a sheriff, not to exceed four years, provided that he was employed during such period as a peace officer by the state, a municipality, or any other political subdivision of this state and was required by the terms of such employment, whether by election or appointment, to devote his full time to the duties of a peace officer. Upon approval or acceptance of such claims by the board, the applicant shall be credited with such service as a basis for future contemplated retirement, provided that credit for such service shall be available only if the applicant shall have served as a sheriff for a minimum of eight years subsequent to December 31, 1960, and subsequent to periods of service for which credit under this Code section is claimed; provided, further, that amounts due under paragraph (5) of Code Section 47-16-40 have been paid for such periods.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1963, p. 630, ยง 12; Ga. L. 1968, p. 1203, ยง 7.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
