<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-110/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_2_110">
        <num>47-2-110</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1949, p. 138, § 5; Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 349, § 3; Ga. L. 1953, Nov.-Dec. Sess., p. 160, § 4; Ga. L. 1957, p. 172, § 1; Ga. L. 1957, p. 283, § 4; Ga. L. 1957, p. 465, § 1; Ga. L. 1962, p. 54, § 4; Ga. L. 1968, p. 1356, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1969, p. 1015, § 1; Ga. L. 1971, p. 338, § 1; Ga. L. 1979, p. 416, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1487, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 283, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2178, § 1; Ga. L. 1997, p. 554, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1449, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1288, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 1010, § 1/HB 1020; Ga. L. 2009, p. 752, § 1/SB 98; Ga. L. 2009, p. 947, § 17/HB 202; Ga. L. 2010, p. 424, §§ 1, 2/HB 916; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, § 16/SB 436; Ga. L. 2019, p. 808, § 7/SB 72; Ga. L. 2020, p. 474, § 2/SB 176.)</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendments.
      The first 2009 amendment, effective July 1, 2009, substituted "State Personnel Administration" for "State Merit System of Personnel Administration" in paragraphs (c)(2) and (c)(3). The second 2009 amendment, effective May 11, 2009, in subsection (a), designated the existing provisions of subsection (a) as paragraph (a)(1), added the last two sentences in paragraph (a)(1), and added paragraph (a)(2); and rewrote subsection (c). See the Code Commission note regarding the effect of these amendments.</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendments.
      The first 2010 amendment, effective July 1, 2010, in paragraph (a)(1), designated the existing provisions as subparagraph (a)(1)(A), in subparagraph (a)(1)(A), substituted "shall" for "will" in the third sentence and deleted "and that no agreement exists to allow the employee to return to service, including service as or for an independent contractor. Any return to employment or rendering of any paid service, including service as or for an independent contractor, for any employer within two consecutive calendar months of the effective date of retirement shall render the severance invalid, nullifying the application for retirement" following "severed" at the end, and added subparagraph (a)(1)(B); and, in paragraph (c)(3), added the proviso at the end and added subparagraphs (c)(3)(A) through (c)(3)(C). The second 2010 amendment, effective July 1, 2010, deleted former subsection (b), which read: "(b)(1) Effective July 1, 1983, no member of the retirement system may be required to retire because of age except the following members:</p>
          <p>"(A) Those employed as prison guards by the Department of Corrections;</p>
          <p>"(B) Those employed by the Uniform Division of the Department of Public Safety as officers and troopers;</p>
          <p>"(C) Those employed by the Department of Natural Resources as conservation rangers;</p>
          <p>"(D) Those employed by the Department of Revenue as alcohol and tobacco officers or agents;</p>
          <p>"(E) Those employed as officers or agents of the Georgia Bureau of Investigation;</p>
          <p>"(F) Those employed by the Department of Transportation as enforcement officers prior to July 1, 2001;</p>
          <p>"(G) Those employed by the Department of Motor Vehicle Safety as enforcement officers on or after July 1, 2001; and</p>
          <p>"(H) Those employed by the State Board of Pardons and Paroles as parole officers as well as other employees of said board who possess the power of arrest.</p>
          <p>"(2) Those members specified by paragraph (1) of this subsection who may be required to retire because of age shall be subject to the laws specifying retirement ages for the various classifications of such members or subject to the rules, regulations, or policies specifying retirement ages of the various state departments or agencies employing such members, provided such rules, regulations, or policies are in compliance with other laws of this state. Any state department or agency specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be authorized to employ or continue the employment of any member, regardless of age, with professional, scientific, or technical skills who is so certified to the board of trustees by the state department or agency."; and redesignated former subsections (c) and (d) as present subsections (b) and (c), respectively.</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2019, substituted "game wardens" for "conservation rangers" in the second sentence of paragraph (a)(2).</p>
          <p>The 2020 amendment,
      effective January 1, 2021, repealed and reserved former subsection (b), which read: "(b)(1) As used in this subsection, in addition to the definition provided in Code Section 47-2-1, the term 'employer' shall also include the retired member's last employer which reported to the retirement system prior to the member's effective date of retirement. Such term shall also include the Board of Regents of the University System of Georgia.</p>
          <p>"(2) Except as provided in this subsection, if a member accepts paid employment with or renders services for pay to any employer, including, without limitation, service directly or indirectly as or for an independent contractor, after his or her retirement, payment of his or her retirement allowance shall be suspended and no contributions to the retirement system shall be made on account of such service either by that member or his or her employer, provided that, upon termination of such service, all rights shall vest in that member as if he or she had continued his or her option to retire.</p>
          <p>"(3) The retirement allowance of a retired member who accepts employment with or renders services to any employer after his or her retirement shall not be suspended if the employee has attained normal retirement age or has not been employed by or rendered service for any employer for at least two consecutive calendar months and performs no more than 1,040 hours of paid employment or paid service, including, without limitation, service as or for an independent contractor, for the employer in any calendar year; provided, however, that return to service as or for an independent contractor shall not result in the suspension of an employee's retirement allowance if the employing agency certifies to the board of trustees that:</p>
          <p>"(A) The contracting entity has multiple employees;</p>
          <p>"(B) The contracting entity has multiple contracts, and the contracts are not limited to employers, as such term is defined in Code Section 47-2-1; and</p>
          <p>"(C) The contractual relationship with the employer was not created to allow a retired employee to continue employment after retirement in a position similar to the one he or she held before retirement.</p>
          <p>"(4) Any employer that employs a retired plan member shall within 30 days of the employee's accepting employment notify the board of trustees in writing stating the name of the plan member and the number of hours the employee is expected to work annually and shall provide such other information as the board may request. If the retired plan member performs more than 1,040 hours in any calendar year, the employer shall so notify the board of trustees as soon as such information is available. Any employer that fails to notify the board of trustees as required by this subsection shall reimburse the retirement system for any benefits wrongfully paid. It shall be the duty of the retired plan member seeking employment by the employer to notify the employer of his or her retirement status prior to accepting such position. If a retired plan member fails to so notify the employer and the employer becomes liable to the retirement system, the plan member shall hold the employer harmless for all such liability."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
