<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_2_1">
        <num>47-2-1</num>
        <content>
          <p>As used in this chapter, the term:</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1949, p. 138, § 1; Ga. L. 1950, p. 416, § 1; Ga. L. 1951, p. 394, § 1; Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 349, § 1; Ga. L. 1953, Nov.-Dec. Sess., p. 160, § 1; Ga. L. 1956, p. 54, § 1; Ga. L. 1961, p. 101, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1961, p. 143, § 1; Ga. L. 1967, p. 751, § 1; Ga. L. 1968, p. 195, § 1; Ga. L. 1971, p. 96, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 925, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 47; Ga. L. 1983, p. 1859, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1296, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 209, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1543, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 575, §§ 5, 6; Ga. L. 1988, p. 1351, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 1742, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 52, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 535, §§ 3, 4/HB 460; Ga. L. 2006, p. 93, § 1/SB 466; Ga. L. 2008, p. 562, § 1/SB 434; Ga. L. 2009, p. 752, § 1/SB 98; Ga. L. 2009, p. 947, §§ 9-12/HB 202; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, §§ 3, 64/SB 436; Ga. L. 2012, p. 413, § 2/HB 805.)</p>
          <p>The 2008 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2008, substituted "Technical College System of Georgia" for "Department of Technical and Adult Education" twice in paragraphs (16.3) and (16.4).</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendments.
      The first 2009 amendment, effective July 1, 2009, in subparagraphs (16)(A) and (17)(A), substituted "State Personnel Administration" for "state merit system of personnel administration" and, in paragraph (16.2), substituted "State Personnel Administration" for "State Merit System of Personnel Administration". The second 2009 amendment, effective May 11, 2009, in paragraph (1), substituted "earnable compensation of a member or paid by the member to establish or reestablish credit for service, which amounts are credited to the member's" for "compensation of a member and credited to his" in the first sentence and added ", excluding employee contributions paid by the employer or the employee for group term life insurance" at the end of the second sentence; in paragraph (15), inserted "or her" in the middle of the first sentence and added the last sentence; in paragraph (17), in subparagraph (17)(A), inserted "or her" in the second sentence and inserted "or she" in the third sentence, and added subparagraph (17)(C); and added paragraphs (16.6) and (28.1).</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2010, substituted "Reserved." for the former provisions of paragraph (9), which read: "'Commencement date affecting employers operating under a merit system of personnel administration at the time of the passage of this chapter' means January 1, 1950. Anything in this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, any employee of an employer which is not operating under the retirement system who, without a break in service, becomes an employee of an employer which is operating under the retirement system, within two years of the commencement date affecting such employer, shall have a commencement date as of the date employment with the latter department became effective; and in such cases all other dates found in this chapter shall be set in the same relation to his commencement date as they would otherwise be set in relation to the commencement date affecting such employer."; substituted "Reserved." for the former provisions of paragraph (10), which read: "'Commencement date affecting employers that after February 3, 1949, operate under a merit system of personnel administration or those employers for which funds are not available on that date under Code Section 47-2-57' means: if the employees of any employer shall hereafter become eligible for inclusion in the Employees' Retirement System of Georgia, the commencement date set for such employer by the board of trustees shall be not less than six months or more than 12 months from the date such employer becomes eligible for membership; and all other dates mentioned in this chapter shall be set in the same relation to this commencement date as they would otherwise be set in relation to the commencement date in the original chapter, provided that in the application of dates to subsection (a) of Code Section 47-2-96, no date shall be later than July 1, 1953. Anything in this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, any employee of an employer which is not operating under the retirement system who, without a break in service, becomes an employee of an employer which is operating under the retirement system, within two years of the commencement date affecting such employer, shall have a commencement date as of the date employment with the latter employer became effective; and in such cases all other dates found in this chapter shall be set in the same relation to his commencement date as they would otherwise be set in relation to the commencement date affecting such employer."; in paragraph (14), substituted "means the division" for "and 'Division B' mean the divisions" at the beginning and deleted ", and those who are not, respectively" following "Section 47-2-71" at the end; substituted "Section" for "Sections" near the end of paragraph (15); and, substituted "under the State Personnel Administration" for "under a State Personnel Administration" in subparagraphs (16)(A) and (17)(A).</p>
          <p>The 2012 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2012, inserted "or her" throughout this Code section; substituted "the employee" for "he" in paragraph (6); substituted "subject to the state system of personnel administration created by Chapter 20 of Title 45 and the State Personnel Board" for "under the State Personnel Administration" in subparagraph (16)(A); added "or" at the end of the undesignated language following division (16)(B)(iii); substituted "as defined by Code Section 45-20-2" for "of the State Personnel Administration" in the first sentence of paragraph (16.2); in subparagraph (17)(A), substituted "subject to the state system of personnel administration created by Chapter 20 of Title 45 and the State Personnel Board" for "under the State Personnel Administration" in the first sentence and substituted a semicolon for a period at the end of the last sentence; substituted "; or" for a period at the end of subparagraph (17)(B); substituted "Any" for "'Employer' shall include any" in subparagraph (17)(C); and inserted "or she" in paragraph (24).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
