<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-163/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_2_163">
        <num>47-2-163</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any other provisions of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, the board of trustees is authorized by rules or regulations to provide for group term life insurance protection for members and former members of the General Assembly; provided, however, that the provisions of this Code section shall not be applicable to persons who become or again become members of the General Assembly on or after July 1, 2009. The board of trustees may contract for such coverage with the State Employees' Assurance Department pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 19 of this title. The board of trustees shall determine the amount of such coverage and the employee contribution that shall be made for such coverage by the members of the General Assembly. The board of trustees shall also determine the employer contribution necessary for such group term life insurance protection for members of the General Assembly. Such employer contribution shall be paid from funds appropriated or available to the legislative branch of the state government. The employee and employer contributions shall be paid into the survivors benefit fund provided for in subsection (c) of Code Section 47-2-128.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1962, p. 54, ยง 6; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, ยง 47; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1263, ยง 3; Ga. L. 2009, p. 398, ยง 2/SB 177.)</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2009, added the proviso at the end of the first sentence.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
