<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-2-28/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_2_28">
        <num>47-2-28</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1949, p. 138, § 6; Ga. L. 1959, p. 107, § 6; Ga. L. 1964, p. 119, § 1; Ga. L. 1968, p. 1356, § 4; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1104, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 535, § 5/HB 460; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, § 4/SB 436.)</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2010, deleted former subsection (a), which read: "Any other law to the contrary notwithstanding, the board of trustees, for the purpose of administering the social security program, may, with due regard for the actuarial soundness of the retirement system and after an actuarial investigation into its benefit structure, adopt such tables, calculations, and compensation and deduction schedules as it shall deem desirable in connection with the proper operation of the retirement system. All tables, calculations, and compensation and deduction schedules adopted under this Code section shall be based on final monthly earnings, which shall mean monthly earnable compensation as reflected by monthly contributions during employment, except that no salary increase by adjustment in compensation in any manner during the last 12 months, which increase is in excess of 10 percent, shall be included. Such tables and calculations as may be adopted shall not diminish or impair the amount of any allowances or benefits which would have been payable to the member by use of tables or calculations that were in effect on January 1, 1959. The board of trustees may also, from time to time, establish rules and regulations for the administration of the funds created under this chapter and for the transaction of its business."; and redesignated former subsections (b) and (c) as present subsections (a) and (b), respectively.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
