<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_3_60">
        <num>47-3-60</num>
        <content>
          <p>(e.1)A member who has not withdrawn the member's contributions to the retirement system and who has a break in service of more than four years but not more than five years may be reinstated to membership if the member pays a sum equal to 12 1/2 percent of the member's salary for the last year of service prior to the break in service. A member who has not withdrawn the member's contributions to the retirement system and who has a break in service of more than five years but not more than six years may be reinstated to membership if the member pays a sum equal to 25 percent of the member's salary for the last year of service prior to the break in service. A member who has not withdrawn the member's contributions to the retirement system may be reinstated to membership without paying the reinstatement fees after the member renders at least one year of membership service subsequent to the break in service. All interest credits shall cease after any such break in service but shall begin again on the date of payment of the sum required for reinstatement to membership or on the first day of July immediately following the completion of one year of membership service following the break in service. The board of trustees may approve the continued membership of a member while in the armed forces of the United States or other emergency wartime service of the United States, or a member whose membership would be terminated because of illness which prevents the member from rendering the service otherwise required by this Code section. The board of trustees may also grant an additional year of leave to a teacher for each child born to or adopted by such teacher while on authorized leave.</p>
          <p>(h.1)Personnel employed for the first time by the State Board of Education or by the State Department of Education on or after July 1, 1988, who, at the time of becoming so employed, are members of this retirement system shall continue as members of this retirement system unless such personnel elect membership in the Employees' Retirement System of Georgia at the time of their employment. Such election shall be made in writing to the board of trustees of this retirement system and to the board of trustees of the Employees' Retirement System of Georgia. Once such election is made by such personnel, the election is irrevocable during the tenure of employment with the State Board of Education or the State Department of Education. The State Board of Education shall provide by regulation for informing prospective employees who are subject to the provisions of this subsection of the option provided for by this subsection so that such personnel may choose to continue membership in this retirement system or become members of the Employees' Retirement System of Georgia at the time of their employment.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1943, p. 640, § 3; Ga. L. 1947, p. 1494, § 1; Ga. L. 1952, p. 254, § 1; Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 270, § 1; Ga. L. 1953, Nov.-Dec. Sess., p. 394, § 1; Ga. L. 1959, p. 319, § 1; Ga. L. 1960, p. 1116, § 3; Ga. L. 1961, p. 388, § 2; Ga. L. 1964, p. 699, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 384, § 1; Ga. L. 1971, p. 409, § 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 896, § 1; Ga. L. 1973, p. 903, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1579, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 1458, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 825, § 1; Ga. L. 1979, p. 1007, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 828, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 1327, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 1859, § 4; Ga. L. 1985, p. 209, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1543, § 3; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1547, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1987, p. 575, § 9; Ga. L. 1987, p. 959, § 4; Ga. L. 1988, p. 1351, §§ 3, 4; Ga. L. 1988, p. 1742, § 3; Ga. L. 1992, p. 477, § 1; Ga. L. 1993, p. 1690, § 4; Ga. L. 1996, p. 389, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1268, § 1; Ga. L. 2008, p. 562, § 1/SB 434; Ga. L. 2009, p. 752, § 1/SB 98; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, § 41/SB 436; Ga. L. 2012, p. 413, § 9/HB 805.)</p>
          <p>The 2008 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2008, substituted "Technical College System of Georgia" for "Department of Technical and Adult Education" three times in paragraph (j)(2) and once in paragraph (j)(3).</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2009, substituted "State Personnel Administration" for "State Merit System of Personnel Administration" in the middle of paragraph (i)(1).</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2010, throughout this Code section, inserted "or her" and "or she"; and substituted "Reserved." for the former provisions of subsection (c), which read: "Any teacher who was alive as of March 28, 1947, who has reached the age of 60, who had taught for at least 35 years as of March 19, 1943, in the public schools of the state operated by the Department of Education or any of the state educational institutions financed by this state and who retired from service in such schools or educational institutions before March 19, 1943, shall be deemed a member of the retirement system. Benefits to be paid to such a member shall be computed on the average earnings received by such a member for the last five years of actual service rendered in such schools and educational institutions."</p>
          <p>The 2012 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2012, substituted "as defined by Code Section 45-20-2" for "of the State Personnel Administration" in paragraph (i)(1).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
