<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-3-67/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_3_67">
        <num>47-3-67</num>
        <content>
          <p>(d.1)Until such time as the rate of employee contribution required of all members of the Teachers Retirement System of Georgia shall be increased, no transferred teacher who remains in the employ of the county school system shall be required to pay any greater percentage of the teacher's salary to the Teachers Retirement System of Georgia than such transferred teacher would have been required to pay to the local retirement fund had such teacher remained a member of the local retirement fund. In the event that a contribution in excess of such amount shall be required by the Teachers Retirement System of Georgia, such excess contribution shall be made by the county school system; provided, however, that any increase in the rate of employee contribution required of all members of the Teachers Retirement System of Georgia after July 1, 1988, shall be paid for by the transferred teacher.</p>
          <p>(e.1) (1)Any excess employee contributions paid to the Teachers Retirement System of Georgia pursuant to the provisions of subsection (d.1) of this Code section shall be paid into the pension accumulation fund and shall not constitute "accumulated contributions" within the meaning of paragraph (1) of Code Section 47-3-1 or for the purposes of Code Section 47-3-128.</p>
          <p>From the funds paid to the board of trustees pursuant to the provisions of subsection (e) of this Code section, that portion thereof representing employee contributions paid to the local retirement fund by the transferred teacher shall be paid into the annuity savings fund and shall constitute "accumulated contributions" within the meaning of paragraph (1) of Code Section 47-3-1 and for the purposes of Code Section 47-3-128; and the remaining portion shall be paid into the pension accumulation fund and shall have the same status as excess employee contributions described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</p>
          <p>(e.2) (1)If a transferred teacher who has maintained continuous service with the county school system or a beneficiary of such a transferred teacher does not qualify to receive a monthly benefit under this retirement system but would be qualified to receive a monthly benefit under the local retirement fund if the transferred teacher's membership in the local retirement fund had continued, such transferred teacher or the beneficiary of such transferred teacher may elect to receive a monthly benefit under the provisions of subsection (d) of this Code section. If such transferred teacher or a beneficiary of such transferred teacher thereafter qualifies to receive a monthly benefit under this retirement system, the amount payable to the transferred teacher or beneficiary under subsection (d) of this Code section shall be reduced accordingly.</p>
          <p>A transferred teacher or a beneficiary of a transferred teacher who makes the election provided for in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be entitled to a refund of the accumulated contributions which have been credited to the transferred teacher's account at the time of said election. If such a transferred teacher subsequently returns to active service, this paragraph shall not apply to accumulated contributions credited to the transferred teacher's account after returning to active service.</p>
          <p>If a transferred teacher who makes the election provided for in paragraph (1) of this subsection does not at any time thereafter qualify to receive a monthly benefit under this retirement system and if no beneficiary of the transferred teacher is qualified to receive a monthly benefit under this retirement system upon the death of the transferred teacher, then upon the death of such transferred teacher, the board of trustees shall pay to the county school system an amount equal to the accumulated contributions of the deceased transferred teacher and an amount equal to the funds paid into the pension accumulation fund pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e.1) of this Code section, plus regular interest on that amount. The board of trustees shall maintain such records as may be necessary to comply with the provisions of this paragraph.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
