<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-4-80/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_4_80">
        <num>47-4-80</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1969, p. 998, § 5; Ga. L. 1974, p. 1242, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1490, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 311, § 1; Ga. L. 1981, p. 1888, § 1; Ga. L. 1988, p. 638, § 1; Ga. L. 1993, p. 86, § 1; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, § 49/SB 436.)</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2010, deleted former subsection (b), which read: "Under such rules and regulations as the board shall adopt, each member who was a public school employee at any time from July 1, 1945, until the commencement date shall be entitled to file a detailed statement of all services as a public school employee rendered by him prior to the commencement date and for which he claims credit. If any person who would otherwise have qualified under this subsection is on leave in the armed forces of the United States, such person shall have six months after termination of his military service to qualify under this subsection for prior service credit. Upon verification of such statement of service, the board shall issue a prior service certificate based on the member's statement of service and certifying to the member the period of service prior to the commencement date with which he is credited. As long as a membership continues, a prior service certificate shall be final and conclusive proof of such service for retirement purposes. A member may within one year from the date of issuance or modification of his prior service certificate request the board to modify or correct such certificate. When membership ceases, such prior service certificate shall become void."; redesignated former subsections (c) and (d) as present subsections (b) and (c), respectively; in present subsection (b), inserted "or her" twice and inserted "or she" near the middle; deleted former subsections (e) through (i); and redesignated former subsection (j) as present subsection (d).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
