<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/47-6-40/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_6_40">
        <num>47-6-40</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1967, p. 259, § 4; Ga. L. 1971, p. 930, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 611, § 2; Ga. L. 2010, p. 1207, § 51/SB 436; Ga. L. 2012, p. 663, § 2/HB 183.)</p>
          <p>The 2010 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2010, deleted former subsection (b) which read: "Any other provisions of law to the contrary notwithstanding, any person who was a member of the General Assembly on April 1, 1971, and who elected not to be a member of the system as provided for in subsection (a) of this Code section could elect, on or before April 30, 1971, to become a member of the system and, upon so electing, become a member under the same conditions as any other member. In order for any such member to receive credit for membership service such member must make the required contributions for such periods, plus interest at the rate of 4 1/4 percent per annum from the time such contributions would have been made had he been a member at that time."; redesignated former subsections (c) and (d) as present subsections (b) and (c), respectively; and inserted "or she" and "or her" throughout present subsections (b) and (c).</p>
          <p>The 2012 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2012, substituted the present provisions of subsection (a) for the former provisions, which read: "All persons who are members of the General Assembly on July 1, 1967, shall become members of the system as of such date, except that within six months from such date any such person may irrevocably elect not to be a member of the system. All other persons shall become members of the system on taking office as members of the General Assembly. Staff members shall have the option to become members of the system under the same conditions as elected members of the General Assembly."; and added subsections (d) and (e).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
