<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/8-4-4/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_4_4">
        <num>8-4-4</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any housing authority established pursuant to Article 1 of Chapter 3 of this title, the "Housing Authorities Law," is authorized to prepare or cause to be prepared redevelopment plans and to undertake redevelopment projects within its area of operation, in accordance with this chapter. In undertaking such redevelopment projects, a housing authority shall have all the rights, powers, privileges, and immunities that such authority has under Article 1 of Chapter 3 of this title, the "Housing Authorities Law," and any other provision of law relating to slum clearance and housing projects for persons of low income, including, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, the power to make and execute contracts, to issue bonds and other obligations and give security therefor, to acquire real property by eminent domain or purchase, and to do any and all things necessary to carry out projects in the same manner as though all of the provisions of law applicable to slum clearance and housing projects were applicable to redevelopment projects undertaken under this chapter, provided that nothing contained in Code Sections 8-3-11 and 8-3-12 shall be construed as limiting the power of an authority, in the event of a default by a purchaser or lessee of land in a redevelopment plan, to acquire property and operate it free from the restrictions contained in said Code sections.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1946, p. 157, ยง 4; Ga. L. 1951, p. 683, ยง 2.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
