<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/22-2-110/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_22_2_110">
        <num>22-2-110</num>
        <content>
          <p>"AWARD</p>
          <p>The special master appointed and chosen by the court to hear evidence and give full consideration to all matters touching upon the value of the property or interest sought to be condemned, as shown by the description of the property or interest in the case of ________ (condemning body) versus ________ (acres of land or other described interest in said land) and ________ (condemnee), Civil action file no.____ in superior court, having first taken the oath as required by law of the special master, the same having been filed with the clerk of the Superior Court of ________ County, and the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, having heard evidence under oath and given consideration to the value of such property or interest on the ______ day of ________, at ____:____ _.M., as provided for in the order of the court, do decide and recommend to the court as follows:
   (1) I/We find and award to ________, condemnee, the sum of $______, as the actual market value of the property or interest sought to be condemned;
   (2) I/We find consequential damages to the remaining property or interest in the amount of $______;
   (3) I/We find consequential benefits to the remaining property or interest in the amount of $______ (never to exceed the amount of the consequential damages);
   (4) I/We find and award to ________, condemnee, the sum of $______, as the value of any associated moving costs;
   (5) Balancing the consequential benefits against the consequential damages, I/we find and award to the condemnee in this case in the total sum of $______, and I/we respectfully recommend to the court that the said property or interest be condemned by a judgment in rem to the use of the condemnor upon the payment of the last stated sum into the registry of the court, subject to the demands of the condemnee.
   This ______ day of ________, ____.
   __________________
   Special Master
   __________________
   Assessor
   __________________
   Assessor"</p>
          <p>In any case where there is an appeal from the award of the special master or the special master panel, in the event such a panel exists, to a jury in the superior court, such award shall not be competent evidence. Any such appeal shall be a de novo investigation, and such award shall be detached from the papers in the case before the same are delivered to the jury.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1957, p. 387, § 12; Ga. L. 1984, p. 682, § 3; Ga. L. 1998, p. 1539, § 5; Ga. L. 2006, p. 39, § 12/HB 1313; Ga. L. 2016, p. 864, § 22/HB 737.)</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_22_2_110__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The award shall be in the following form:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
