<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-185/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1_185">
        <num>10-1-185</num>
        <content>
          <p>Before any brake fluid shall be sold, exposed for sale, or stored, packed, or held with intent to sell within this state, a sample thereof must be inspected or approved by the state oil chemist. Upon application of the manufacturer, packer, seller, or distributor and the payment of a license or inspection fee of $25.00 for each brand or type of brake fluid submitted, the state oil chemist shall subject to inspection or analysis the brake fluid so submitted. If the brake fluid is not adulterated or misbranded and meets the standards established and promulgated by the Commissioner and is not such a type or kind that is in violation of this part, the Commissioner may issue the applicant a written license or permit authorizing the sale of such brake fluid in this state for the calendar year in which the license or inspection fee is paid, which license or permit shall be subject to renewal annually upon payment of a $25.00 renewal fee. If, in accordance with Chapter 13 of Title 50, the "Georgia Administrative Procedure Act," the Commissioner shall find that any brake fluid has been materially altered or adulterated or a change has been made in the name, brand, or trademark under which the brake fluid is sold or that it violates this part, he shall notify the applicant; and the license or permit shall be canceled forthwith. No license or permit for the sale of brake fluid in this state shall be issued until application has been made as provided by this part and such samples of the brake fluid as may be necessary for the state oil chemist to inspect it have been submitted and until the state oil chemist notifies the Commissioner that said brake fluid meets the specifications adopted by the Commissioner.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1956, p. 237, ยง 6.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
