<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-203/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1_203">
        <num>10-1-203</num>
        <content>
          <p>Before any antifreeze shall be sold, exposed for sale, or stored, packed, or held with intent to sell within this state, a current certified test report thereof prepared by an independent laboratory recognized by the Department of Agriculture to do such testing must be submitted and evaluated under the supervision of the state oil chemist in the Department of Agriculture. Upon application of the manufacturer or packer or distributor, submission of container label, and the payment of a license fee of $50.00 for each brand or type of antifreeze submitted, the state oil chemist shall evaluate the test report so submitted. Any fees collected pursuant to this Code section shall be retained pursuant to the provisions of Code Section 45-12-92.1. If the antifreeze is not adulterated or misbranded, if it meets the standards established and promulgated by the Commissioner of Agriculture, and if the antifreeze is not a type or kind that is in violation of this part, the Commissioner shall issue the applicant a written license or permit authorizing the wholesale and retail sale by the applicant and by others of such antifreeze in this state for the fiscal year in which the license is issued, which license or permit shall be subject to renewal annually. If the Commissioner shall find at a later date that the antifreeze product or substance to be sold, exposed for sale, or held with intent to sell has been materially altered or adulterated or that a change has been made in the name, brand, or trademark under which the antifreeze is sold or that it violates this part, the Commissioner is authorized to revoke or suspend the license or permit issued under this part of the licensee found in violation of this part after notice and hearing before the Commissioner. No license or permit for the sale of antifreeze in this state shall be issued until the application, fee, and label submission have been made as provided by this part, the certified test report has been evaluated by the state oil chemist, and the state oil chemist notifies the Commissioner of Agriculture that said antifreeze meets the requirements of this part.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 706, ยง 4; Ga. L. 1997, p. 416, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 136, ยง 10; Ga. L. 2010, p. 9, ยง 1-26/HB 1055.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
