<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-394/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1_394">
        <num>10-1-394</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 376, ยง 4; Ga. L. 2015, p. 1088, ยง 2/SB 148.)</p>
          <p>The 2015 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2015, substituted "Attorney General is authorized to adopt reasonable rules, regulations, and standards appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this part and prohibit specific acts or practices that are deemed to be a violation of this part.
   The Attorney General is also authorized to adopt as" for "administrator is authorized to adopt as" in subsection (a); deleted former subsection (b), which read: "Such rules shall be promulgated only when it is determined by the administrator, in the reasonable exercise of his discretion, on the basis of his expertise and facts, submissions, evidence, and all information before him, that such rules are needed to prohibit or control acts or practices which create the probability of actual and substantial injury to consumers.
   No rule shall be promulgated where it is reasonably certain that the burden of complying with the rule will outweigh the public interest in prohibiting or controlling the practice which would be so prohibited or controlled.
   No such rule so promulgated shall be arbitrary or capricious nor shall its promulgation be characterized by an abuse of discretion or an unwarranted exercise of discretion."; redesignated former subsection (c) as present subsection (b) and substituted "Attorney General" for "administrator" in such subsection; and deleted former subsection (d), which read: "The Consumer Advisory Board shall be authorized to ratify or veto rules promulgated by the administrator at its next regular meeting after the rules are promulgated by the administrator under the provisions of Chapter 13 of Title 50."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
