<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-152/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1_152">
        <num>10-1-152</num>
        <content>
          <p>Every person, firm, or corporation delivering at wholesale or retail any gasoline in this state shall deliver the same to the purchaser only in tanks, barrels, casks, cans, or other containers having the word "gasoline" plainly stenciled or labeled thereon in vermilion red, in English. Such dealers shall not deliver kerosene oil in any barrel, cask, can, or other container which shall have been so stenciled or labeled or that has ever contained gasoline unless such barrel, cask, can, or other container shall have been thoroughly cleaned and all traces of gasoline removed. Every purchaser of gasoline for use or sale shall procure and keep the same only in tanks, barrels, casks, cans, or other containers stenciled or labeled as provided in this Code section. Every person delivering at wholesale or retail any kerosene in this state shall deliver same to the purchaser only in tanks, barrels, casks, cans, or other containers having the word "kerosene" in English, plainly stenciled or labeled thereon in vermilion red; and every person purchasing same for use or sale shall procure and keep the same only in tanks, barrels, casks, cans, or other containers stenciled or labeled as provided in this Code section. Nothing in this Code section shall prohibit the delivery of gasoline by hose or pipe from a tank directly into the tank of any automobile or other motor. In cases where gasoline or kerosene is sold in bottles, cans, or other containers of not more than one gallon, for cleaning and other similar purposes, such bottles, cans, or other containers shall bear a label with the words "unsafe when exposed to heat or fire."</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1927, p. 279, ยง 5; Code 1933, ยง 73-213.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
