<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/10-1-413/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1_413">
        <num>10-1-413</num>
        <content>
          <p>"NOTICE REQUIRED BY STATE</p>
          <p>LAW REGARDING DISCLOSURES</p>
          <p>State law requires that a multilevel distribution company shall make available certain disclosures regarding the company prior to obtaining participants.
   This is your official notice that you have a right to request to see these disclosures prior to entering into any agreement with a multilevel distribution company. This will be the only notice you receive regarding your rights to see these disclosures. If you waive these rights, you are giving up an important consumer protection that the State of Georgia has found you should be provided. If you wish to exercise these rights, please indicate below that you want to see the disclosures before agreeing to be a participant, then do not agree to become a participant until the disclosures have been made available to you.
      SIGN
    ONLY
    ONE
    OF
    THE
    FOLLOWING STATEMENTS:
      I wish to see the disclosures required by law before I agree to become a
   participant. _________________________________________________________________
   Date: __________________
   I do not wish to see the disclosures required by law; I understand that I will not be seeing important information which might affect my decision to
   participate in this multilevel distribution company. _________________________
   Date: __________________"</p>
          <p>Every multilevel distribution company shall maintain on file all of the statements as described in subsection (c) of this Code section for a period of two years from the date such statements are signed.</p>
          <p>Every seller shall include the following regarding each officer, director, principal, and owner in the disclosures required by subsection (b) of Code Section 10-1-411 and by subsection (a) of Code Section 10-1-413:</p>
          <p>The disclosures required under subsection (e) of this Code section shall include any of the following which are applicable:</p>
          <p>The identity and location of the court or agency;</p>
          <p>The date of conviction, judgment, or decision;</p>
          <p>The penalty imposed;</p>
          <p>The damages assessed;</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1980, p. 1233, ยง 4; Ga. L. 1984, p. 522, ยง 4; Ga. L. 1988, p. 1868, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 2370, ยง 3.)</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_1_413__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a multilevel distribution company must provide the disclosure statement required by subsection (a) of this Code section, the multilevel distribution company, prior to obtaining any participant, shall provide that participant with an 8 1/2 inch by 11 inch document in at least ten-point type, which reads as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
