<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-2-18/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_2_18">
        <num>27-2-18</num>
        <content>
          <p>The department shall be authorized to issue to a person who cultivates crops, who is immediately responsible for their cultivation, or who is the principal owner of the crops a permit to kill deer which have caused or are reasonably certain to cause damage to crops which were planted for the purpose of harvesting and marketing such crops or their by-products. The person shall apply to the department for such a permit on a form containing such information as may be necessary for the proper evaluation and consideration of the application. Permits shall be issued only in cases where the department has determined that the killing of deer is justified. Representatives of the department are authorized to investigate claims of damage and the necessity of killing deer prior to the issuance of such a permit. Permits issued by the department shall include restrictions and conditions relative to the property on which deer may be killed, persons authorized to kill deer on the property, crops which may be protected, number and sex of deer which may be killed, expiration of permit, and such other restrictions and conditions as may be necessary. It shall be unlawful for any person to kill any deer under the authority of any such permit except in accordance with the restrictions and conditions of the permit.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1976, p. 645, ยง 1; Code 1933, ยง 45-321, enacted by Ga. L. 1977, p. 396, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, ยง 20.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
