<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-7/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_3_7">
        <num>27-3-7</num>
        <content>
          <p>(a.1)As used in this Code section, the term "alcohol concentration" means grams of alcohol per 100 milliliters of blood or grams of alcohol per 210 liters of breath.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1953, Nov.-Dec. Sess., p. 327, § 1; Ga. L. 1955, p. 483, § 56; Code 1933, § 45-506, enacted by Ga. L. 1977, p. 396, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 1134, § 2; Ga. L. 2013, p. 92, § 3/SB 136; Ga. L. 2014, p. 344, § 2/HB 783; Ga. L. 2019, p. 295, § 1/HB 471; Ga. L. 2020, p. 827, § 2-2/HB 998.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective April 28, 2019, substituted the present provisions of paragraph (g)(2) for the former provisions, which read: "At the time a chemical test or tests are requested, the arresting officer shall read to the person the following implied consent warning:</p>
          <p>"'Georgia law requires you to submit to state administered chemical tests of your blood, breath, urine, or other bodily substances for the purpose of determining if you are under the influence of alcohol or drugs. If you refuse this testing and you are convicted of hunting while under the influence of alcohol or drugs, your privilege to hunt in this state will be suspended for a period of two years. Your refusal to submit to the required testing may be offered into evidence against you at trial. If you submit to testing and the results indicate an alcohol concentration of 0.08 grams or more and if you are subsequently convicted of hunting under the influence of alcohol by having an alcohol concentration of 0.08 grams or more at any time within three hours after hunting from alcohol consumed before such hunting ended, your privilege to hunt in this state will be suspended for a period of one year. After first submitting to the required state tests, you are entitled to additional chemical tests of your blood, breath, urine, or other bodily substances at your own expense and from qualified personnel of your own choosing. Will you submit to the state administered chemical tests of your
      (designate which tests)
      under the implied consent law?'"</p>
          <p>The 2020 amendment,
      effective August 5, 2020, added subsection (a.1); substituted "an alcohol concentration" for "a blood alcohol concentration" throughout subsection (f); and substituted "requested state tests" for "required state tests" in the fifth sentence of the warning in paragraph (g)(2).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
