<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/27-3-9/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_3_9">
        <num>27-3-9</num>
        <content>
          <p>(a.1)Nothing in subsection (a) of this Code section shall prohibit any person from placing, exposing, depositing, distributing, or scattering any corn, wheat, or other grains, salts, apples, or other feeds or bait so as to constitute a lure or attraction or enticement for deer on lands that are not under the ownership or control and management of the state or federal government; provided, however, that any such lure or attraction or enticement shall not be placed, exposed, deposited, distributed, or scattered so as to cause hunting any species of wildlife on any adjoining property to be prohibited under subsection (b) of this Code section.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1925, p. 302, § 6; Code 1933, § 45-317; Ga. L. 1955, p. 483, § 64; Ga. L. 1968, p. 497, § 18; Code 1933, § 45-508, enacted by Ga. L. 1977, p. 396, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 469, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1179, § 5; Ga. L. 2007, p. 47, § 27/SB 103; Ga. L. 2011, p. 249, § 1/HB 277; Ga. L. 2019, p. 808, §§ 4, 7/SB 72.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2019, deleted former subsection (a), which read: "As used in this Code section, the term:</p>
          <p>"(1) 'Northern zone' means the northern zone for hunting deer with firearms as established pursuant to subsection (c) of Code Section 27-3-15.</p>
          <p>"(2) 'Southern zone' means the southern zone for hunting deer with firearms as established pursuant to subsection (c) of Code Section 27-3-15.";</p>
          <p>redesignated former subsections (a.1) and (a.2) as present subsections (a) and (a.1), respectively; in subsection (a.1), substituted "subsection (a)" for "subsection (a.1)" near the beginning and inserted "be placed, exposed, deposited, distributed, or scattered so as to" and "any species of wildlife" near the end; rewrote paragraph (b)(2), which formerly read: "The prohibitions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to:</p>
          <p>"(A) The hunting of deer in the northern zone, other than on lands under the ownership or control and management of the state or federal government, if the hunter is at least 200 yards away from and not within sight of such feed or bait; and</p>
          <p>"(B) The hunting of deer in the southern zone, other than on lands under the ownership or control and management of the state or federal government, if the hunter has written permission of the landowner to hunt upon, over, around, or near such feed or bait, except as otherwise provided by paragraph (3) of this subsection."; and substituted "game warden" for "conservation ranger" throughout subsection (c).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
