<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/53-12-155/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53_12_155">
        <num>53-12-155</num>
        <content>
          <p>The trustee of a trust created under Code Section 53-12-151 shall have sole and exclusive management and control of the property, in accordance with the terms of the deed creating the estate. The exercise by the trustee of any power granted or conferred by the deed, including the power to lease, encumber, and sell, when exercised in accordance with the terms thereof, shall be as valid and effective to all intents and purposes as if the trustee was the sole and exclusive owner of the property in his or her own right. The trustee may resign or be removed and his or her successor may be appointed in the manner of and in accordance with the terms fixed by the deed creating the estate. The same rights, powers, and title over and to the property shall belong to and be vested in the new trustee as are conferred upon the original trustee by the deed creating the estate. The death of a trustee shall not operate to cast title upon his or her heirs, devisees, executors, or administrators, but the same shall vest in his or her successor, when appointed.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
