<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/26-2-248/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_26_2_248">
        <num>26-2-248</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any person, firm, or corporation subject to this article and the other milk laws of this state who violates any of said provisions or any valid rules and regulations made thereunder may be enjoined from such continued violation. The Commissioner is authorized to apply for, and for cause shown the superior court having jurisdiction of the defendant in any such action may grant, injunctive relief, by interlocutory injunction, permanent injunction, or temporary restraining order, as the circumstances may warrant. The proceeding may be maintained notwithstanding the pendency of any civil action and notwithstanding the pendency of or conviction in a criminal proceeding arising from the same transaction. Such action may be maintained without bond. The purpose of this Code section is to create a statutory cause of action by way of injunction, and the Commissioner is authorized to bring such proceedings in the same form and manner and in the same court as other equitable proceedings may be brought. This remedy is not exclusive but is cumulative of other remedies afforded to protect the consuming public from unwholesome products which are economic frauds.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1929, p. 280, § 19; Code 1933, § 42-501; Ga. L. 1935, p. 167, § 2; Ga. L. 1961, p. 501, § 11; Ga. L. 1978, p. 1988, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 981, § 15.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
