<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-13/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_4A_13">
        <num>49-4A-13</num>
        <content>
          <p>As used in this Code section, the term "family attention home" means a private family home that has contracted with the Department of Juvenile Justice to provide 24 hour, short-term care for youth in the custody of the department and placed by the department in the home.Said youth are either awaiting a juvenile court hearing or have been temporarily removed from their homes for other reasons. Prior to a youth being placed in a private family attention home, an assessment of the youth's risk to the public will be completed by the department, and based on that assessment a plan of care for each youth will be developed within 72 hours after placement. This plan shall detail the youth's need for adult supervision, the youth's need for structured after-school activities, the need for electronic monitoring, if appropriate, and any other additional treatment needs while the youth is in the home. This plan of care shall be developed and implemented to ensure the safety of the children and youth in each private family attention home and the residents of the communities in which the private family attention homes are located.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
