<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-4A-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_4A_8">
        <num>49-4A-8</num>
        <content>
          <p>(e.1) (1)When a child who has been adjudicated for the commission of a class A designated felony act or class B designated felony act as defined in Code Section 15-11-2 is released from confinement or custody of the department, it shall be the responsibility of the department to provide notice to any person who was the victim of such child's acts that such child is being released from confinement or custody.</p>
          <p>The department and employees of the department shall not be liable for damages incurred by reason of the department's failure to provide the notice required by paragraph (1) of this subsection.</p>
          <p>When a child convicted of a felony offense in a superior court is released from confinement or custody of the department, the department shall provide written notice, including the delinquent act or class A designated felony act or class B designated felony act committed, to the superintendent of the school system in which such child was enrolled or, if the information is known, the school in which such child was enrolled or plans to be enrolled.</p>
          <p>The department and employees of the department shall not be liable for damages incurred by reason of the department's failure to provide notice required by paragraph (3) of this subsection.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
