<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/49-6-60/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_6_60">
        <num>49-6-60</num>
        <content>
          <p>The purpose of this article is to assist functionally impaired elderly persons in living dignified and reasonably independent lives in their own homes or in the homes of relatives or caregivers through the development, expansion, reorganization, and coordination of various community based services. In recognition of the desire of older Georgians to reside at home or with their families as long as possible, the General Assembly intends that a continuum of care be established so that functionally impaired elderly persons age 60 and older may be assured the least restrictive environment suitable to their needs. The General Assembly further intends to maximize the utilization of existing community social and health services in order to prevent unnecessary placement of individuals in long-term care facilities. The development of innovative approaches to program management, staff training, and service delivery that impact on cost avoidance, cost effectiveness, and program efficiency shall be encouraged. It is further the intent of the General Assembly that the Department of Community Health shall serve as the agency responsible for planning and implementing the provision of community based services to the elderly reimbursable under the "Georgia Medical Assistance Act of 1977."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
