<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_27_5">
        <num>31-27-5</num>
        <content>
          <p>The person holding or promoting a mass gathering shall provide a bond of $1 million issued by a surety company authorized to transact business in this state. The purpose of the bond shall be to guarantee full compliance with this chapter as well as other applicable provisions of this title and the provisions of Title 12, relating to air quality control and water supply quality control, and rules and regulations promulgated thereunder and to cover cleanup of the site. This bond shall be in favor of the state for the benefit of any person who is damaged as a result of the activity of a mass gathering. Any person claiming against the bond may maintain an action at law against the person holding or promoting the mass gathering and the surety. In lieu of furnishing the bond, the person holding or promoting a mass gathering may deposit with the commissioner a cash deposit in like amount. However, the bond specified in this Code section shall not be required in cases where the other requirements of this chapter are met by the applicant for a permit and an incorporated municipality or county owns the area upon which the mass gathering is to be held and commits itself, in writing, to clean up the site upon which the gathering is to be held.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 88-1205a, enacted by Ga. L. 1971, p. 252, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1972, p. 912, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 149, ยง 31.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
