<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-27-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_27_3">
        <num>31-27-3</num>
        <content>
          <p>Application for a permit to promote or hold a mass gathering shall be made to the department on a form and in a manner prescribed by the department by the person who will promote or hold the mass gathering. Application for a permit to promote or hold a mass gathering shall be made at least 15 days before the first day of advertising and at least 45 days before the first day of the gathering. Water and sewage facilities shall be constructed and operational not later than 48 hours before the first day of the mass gathering. The application shall be accompanied by such plans, reports, and specifications as the department shall deem necessary. The plans, reports, and specifications shall provide for adequate and satisfactory water supply and sewage facilities, adequate drainage, adequate toilet and lavatory facilities, adequate refuse storage and disposal facilities, adequate sleeping areas and facilities, wholesome food and sanitary food service, adequate medical facilities, insect control, adequate fire protection, and such other matters as may be appropriate for security of life or health. The application shall disclose the names and addresses of all of the persons, firms, or corporations providing financial backing to the mass gathering and the amounts of such backing.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 88-1203a, enacted by Ga. L. 1971, p. 252, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
