<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/31-21-20/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_21_20">
        <num>31-21-20</num>
        <content>
          <p>The academic deans of medical, osteopathic medical, and dental colleges or a representative appointed by the president of such schools incorporated under the laws of this state or otherwise operating in this state with authorization from the Nonpublic Postsecondary Education Commission shall constitute the Board for the Distribution of Cadavers to expedite the distribution and delivery of dead bodies described in Code Section 31-21-21 to and among such institutions as are entitled thereto. This board shall have power to establish rules and regulations for its governance and to appoint and remove its officers and shall keep minutes of its transactions. Records shall be kept, under its direction, of all bodies received and distributed, both from within and without this state, and of the persons or institutions to whom they may be distributed, which records shall be open at all times to the inspection of members of this board, any district attorney, or prosecuting attorney of any city or state court. The board shall appoint a member of the board to be chairperson, and such member shall call at least one meeting per year to carry out the responsibilities of the board. For the purposes of this article, the term "board" shall mean the Board for the Distribution of Cadavers.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1887, p. 86, § 1; Civil Code 1895, § 1511; Civil Code 1910, § 1755; Code 1933, § 88-701; Code 1933, § 88-2701, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, p. 499, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 884, § 3-25; Ga. L. 2007, p. 472, § 1/SB 204.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
