<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-14-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_14_6">
        <num>43-14-6</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1949, p. 1622, §§ 4-6, 14, 15; Ga. L. 1968, p. 308, §§ 4-6, 14, 15; Ga. L. 1971, p. 583, §§ 10, 13, 16; Ga. L. 1980, p. 1299, § 8; Ga. L. 1981, p. 1703, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 43; Ga. L. 1983, p. 424, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1129, § 6; Ga. L. 1989, p. 1756, § 6; Ga. L. 1991, p. 1581, § 1; Ga. L. 1993, p. 1339, §§ 5, 6; Ga. L. 1994, p. 383, § 3; Ga. L. 1994, p. 659, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1706, § 19; Ga. L. 2008, p. 894, § 1/HB 611; Ga. L. 2011, p. 632, § 3/HB 49; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 43/HB 142; Ga. L. 2014, p. 866, § 43/SB 340; Ga. L. 2015, p. 5, § 43/HB 90; Ga. L. 2019, p. 462, § 4-1/SB 214.)</p>
          <p>The 2014 amendment,
      effective April 29, 2014, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "The Division of Conditioned Air Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of Conditioned Air Contractor Class I and Class II licenses" for "With respect to Conditioned Air Contractor Class I and Class II licenses, the Division of Conditioned Air Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of licenses" in paragraph (d)(1); substituted "The Division of Electrical Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of Electrical Contractor Class I and Class II licenses" for "With respect to Electrical Contractor Class I and Class II licenses, the Division of Electrical Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of licenses" in paragraph (e)(1); substituted "The Division of Utility Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of utility foreman certificates and utility manager certificates issued under this chapter" for "With respect to utility foreman certificates and utility manager certificates issued under this chapter, the Division of Utility Contractors shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of such certificates" in paragraph (f)(1); and substituted "The Division of Master Plumbers and Journeyman Plumbers shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of Journeyman Plumber, Master Plumber Class I, and Master Plumber Class II licenses" for "With respect to Journeyman Plumber, Master Plumber Class I, and Master Plumber Class II licenses, the Division of Master Plumbers and Journeyman Plumbers shall be authorized to require persons seeking renewal of such licenses" in paragraph (g)(1).</p>
          <p>The 2015 amendment,
      effective March 13, 2015, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "conditioned air contracting" for "conditioned air work" in the first and second sentences of subparagraph (a)(4)(G).</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2019, in paragraph (e)(1), inserted "courses" near the end of the first sentence, substituted the present second sentence for the following provisions, which read: "The division shall be authorized to approve courses offered by institutions of higher learning, vocational-technical schools, and trade, technical, or professional organizations; provided, however, that continuing education courses or programs related to electrical contracting provided or conducted by public utilities, equipment manufacturers, or institutions under the State Board of the Technical College System of Georgia shall constitute acceptable continuing professional education programs for the purposes of this subsection. Continuing education courses or programs conducted by manufacturers specifically to promote their products shall not be approved", and added the third through fifth sentences.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
