<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-21-6/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_21_6">
        <num>43-21-6</num>
        <content>
          <p>For the enforcement of the lien created by Code Section 43-21-5, the keeper of the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house claiming the lien may retain possession of the property against which the lien is claimed. At any time after 30 days after the person creating such debt or obligation has left the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house, if the debt or obligation is still unpaid, the innkeeper may sell at public auction at the office of the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house where such lien is claimed, to the highest bidder for cash, any and all property subject to such lien, without any further process being necessary. The proceeds of such sale shall be applied, first, to the payment of the expense of such sale; second, to the reduction or discharge of the debt or obligation due to the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house; and any surplus remaining shall be held subject to the demand of the person creating such debt or obligation, provided that such sale shall be advertised by written or printed posters at the office of the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house and at the courthouse door of the county in which the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house is located for at least ten days before such sale. The advertisement shall specify the time and place of sale. The keeper of the inn, boarding house, lodging house, or eating house shall give the owner or agent, or both, written notice by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery addressed to him at his last known address at least ten days prior to the sale, notifying him of the time and place of sale and of the amount claimed against him. Any surplus proceeds of the sale, after payment of the amount claimed against such owner or agent and the cost of sale, if not claimed by the owner or agent within 12 months after the sale, shall be turned over to the board of education of the county in which the sale occurred for educational purposes.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1873, p. 42, § 17; Code 1873, § 1992; Ga. L. 1880-81, p. 63, § 4; Code 1882, § 1992; Civil Code 1895, § 2818; Civil Code 1910, § 3368; Ga. L. 1923, p. 101, § 2; Code 1933, § 52-106; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
