<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-34-191/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_34_191">
        <num>43-34-191</num>
        <content>
          <p>The General Assembly finds that the practice of orthotics and prosthetics in this state is an allied health profession recognized by the American Medical Association, with educational standards established by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs. The increasing population of elderly and physically challenged individuals who need orthotic and prosthetic services requires that the orthotic and prosthetic professions be regulated to ensure the provision of high-quality services and devices. The people of this state deserve the best care available and will benefit from the assurance of initial and ongoing professional competence of the orthotists and prosthetists practicing in this state. The practice of orthotics and prosthetics serves to improve and enhance the lives of individuals with disabilities by enabling them to resume productive lives following serious illness, injury, or trauma. Unregulated dispensing of orthotic and prosthetic care does not adequately meet the needs or serve the interests of the public. In keeping with requirements imposed on similar health disciplines, licensure of the orthotic and prosthetic professions will help ensure the health and safety of consumers, as well as maximize their functional abilities and productivity levels. This article shall be liberally construed to best carry out these subjects and purposes.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
