<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-45-17/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_45_17">
        <num>43-45-17</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Commissioner is authorized and directed to enforce this chapter and rules and regulations promulgated under this chapter and is authorized to utilize any employee of the Department of Agriculture. The Commissioner may inspect any materials used or work performed by persons engaged in the business of household pest control, wood-destroying organism control, or fumigation in this state. The Commissioner shall be authorized, after notice and hearing, to revoke, suspend, or cancel any license, certification, or registration issued under this chapter for a violation of this chapter or the rules and regulations promulgated under this chapter, for conviction or imposition of a final order imposing a civil penalty pursuant to Section 14 of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, as amended, or for conviction of a crime involving moral turpitude. It is the intent and purpose of this chapter to provide for the enforcement of this chapter by the Commissioner and to provide for the licensing, certification, and registration of those persons engaged in the business of structural pest control by the commission. It is the further intent of this chapter to provide that the commission shall advise the Commissioner with respect to the enforcement of this chapter. In connection therewith, the Commissioner, his designated agent, or a designated hearing officer is authorized to exercise the authority granted the commission to hold hearings, subpoena witnesses, and compel the production of documents and papers.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1955, p. 564, § 16; Ga. L. 1960, p. 813, § 11; Ga. L. 1966, p. 171, § 8; Ga. L. 1976, p. 308, § 14; Ga. L. 1977, p. 701, § 13; Ga. L. 1994, p. 97, § 43.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
