<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/43-6-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_6_21">
        <num>43-6-21</num>
        <content>
          <p>Should the auctioneer change his or her place of business, he or she shall notify the commission in writing within ten days of such change, and thereupon a new pocket card shall be granted to the auctioneer.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 84-317A, enacted by Ga. L. 1975, p. 53, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, ยง 3; Ga. L. 2014, p. 294, ยง 10/HB 1042.)</p>
          <p>The 2014 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2014, substituted the present provisions of this Code section for the former provisions, which read: "(a) Should the auctioneer change his place of business, he shall notify the commission in writing within ten days of such change, and thereupon a new pocket card shall be granted to the auctioneer and to his apprentice auctioneers."</p>
          <p>"(b) When an apprentice auctioneer is discharged or terminates his employment with the auctioneer for any reason, it shall be the immediate duty of the auctioneer to deliver or mail by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery to the commission the license of the apprentice auctioneer. It shall be unlawful for any apprentice auctioneer to perform any of the acts contemplated by this chapter, either directly or indirectly under authority of his license, until the apprentice auctioneer receives a new license bearing the name and address of his new employer. No more than one license shall be issued to any apprentice auctioneer for the same period of time."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
