<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/9-10-150/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_10_150">
        <num>9-10-150</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1905, p. 93, § 1; Civil Code 1910, § 5711; Code 1933, § 81-1402; Ga. L. 1952, p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1973, p. 478, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 760, § 1; Ga. L. 1991, p. 376, § 1; Ga. L. 1996, p. 112, § 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 403, § 1; Ga. L. 2006, p. 494, § 1/HB 912; Ga. L. 2009, p. 303, § 18/HB 117; Ga. L. 2019, p. 777, § 1/HB 502.)</p>
          <p>The 2006 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2006, added the fourth sentence.</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendment,
      effective April 30, 2009, substituted "the Senate or of the Judiciary Committee or Judiciary, Non-civil Committee of the" for "either the Senate or the" in the first sentence. For intent, see the Editor's notes.</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective May 7, 2019, substituted the present provisions of this Code section for the former provisions, which read: "A member of the General Assembly who is a party to or the attorney for a party to a case, or any member of the staff of the Lieutenant Governor, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, the Speaker Pro Tempore of the House of Representatives, or the chairperson of the Judiciary Committee or Special Judiciary Committee of the Senate or of the Judiciary Committee or Judiciary, Non-civil Committee of the House of Representatives who is the lead counsel for a party to a case pending in any trial or appellate court or before any administrative agency of this state, shall be granted a continuance and stay of the case. The continuance and stay shall apply to all aspects of the case, including, but not limited to, the filing and serving of an answer to a complaint, the making of any discovery or motion, or of any response to any subpoena, discovery, or motion, and appearance at any hearing, trial, or argument. Unless a shorter length of time is requested by the member, the continuance and stay shall last the length of any regular or extraordinary session of the General Assembly and during the first three weeks following any recess or adjournment including an adjournment sine die of any regular or extraordinary session. A continuance and stay shall also be granted for such other times as the member of the General Assembly or staff member certifies to the court that his or her presence elsewhere is required by his or her duties with the General Assembly. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule of court, or administrative rule or regulation, the time for doing any act in the case which is delayed by the continuance provided by this Code section shall be automatically extended by the same length of time as the continuance or stay covered."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
