<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-431/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_14_431">
        <num>44-14-431</num>
        <content>
          <p>Before any sale is made as provided in Code Section 44-14-430, the person, firm, or corporation making the sale shall give 30 days' notice thereof by posting a notice of the sale before the courthouse door of the county in which the repairs were made. Such notice shall give the name of the owner of the article or articles so repaired, if known, and, if not known, the name of the person from whom the article or articles were received; a description of the article or articles to be sold; and the name of the person, firm, or corporation making the repairs and proposing to make such sale. The person, firm, or corporation shall also give written notice thereof by sending a registered or certified letter to the last known address of the owner of the article or articles or the person who left the article or articles for repairs advising such persons of the time and place of the sale, the description of the article or articles to be sold, and the amount claimed by the person, firm, or corporation for such repairs, including work done and materials furnished; and the amount so claimed for the repairs shall also be stated in the notice posted before the courthouse door.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1927, p. 218, ยง 2; Code 1933, ยง 67-2102.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
