<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-14-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_14_3">
        <num>44-14-3</num>
        <content>
          <p>(c.1)In the event that a grantee or holder of record has failed to transmit properly a legally sufficient satisfaction or cancellation to authorize and direct the clerk or clerks to cancel the instrument of record within 60 days after a written notice mailed to such grantee or holder of record by registered or certified mail or statutory overnight delivery, return receipt requested, the clerk or clerks are authorized and directed to cancel the instrument upon recording an affidavit by an attorney who has caused the secured indebtedness to be paid in full or by an officer of a regulated or chartered financial institution whose deposits are federally insured if that financial institution has paid the secured indebtedness in full. The notice to be mailed to the grantee or holder of record shall identify the indebtedness and include a recital or explanation of this subsection. The affidavit shall include a recital of actions taken to comply with this subsection. Such affidavit shall include as attachments the following items:</p>
          <p>A written verification which was given at the time of payment by the grantee or holder of record of the amount necessary to pay off such loan; and</p>
          <p>(A) Copies of the front and back of a canceled check to the grantee or holder of record paying off such loan.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 1134, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1983, p. 677, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 44; Ga. L. 1986, p. 754, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 3, § 44; Ga. L. 1991, p. 413, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1998, p. 545, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 862, §§ 2, 3; Ga. L. 2000, p. 136, § 44; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3; Ga. L. 2008, p. 352, § 1/HB 1093.)</p>
          <p>The 2000 amendments.
      The first 2000 amendment, effective March 16, 2000, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, in subsection (c.1), substituted a period for a semicolon at the end of subparagraph (c.1)(2)(A) and substituted a period for "; or" at the end of subparagraph (c.1)(2)(B). The second 2000 amendment, effective July 1, 2000, substituted "certified mail or statutory overnight delivery" for "certified mail" in the first sentence of the introductory language in subsection (c.1).</p>
          <p>The 2008 amendment,
      effective May 12, 2008, inserted "of the instrument" throughout subsections (b) and (c); in subsection (b), added paragraph (b)(1), redesignated former paragraphs (b)(1) through (b)(3) as present paragraphs (b)(2) through (b)(4), respectively, in paragraph (b)(2), inserted "or she" near the end of the last sentence, and, in paragraph (b)(3), substituted "paragraph (2)" for "paragraph (1)"; and rewrote subsection (c).
   See the Editor's note for applicability.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
