<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-165/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_2_165">
        <num>44-2-165</num>
        <content>
          <p>If the debt secured by a creditor's certificate or any part thereof becomes due and unpaid, the holder of the creditor's certificate may, after advertising the property for sale in the manner prescribed by law for advertising sheriff's sales of land, sell the property at auction before the courthouse door of the county and sell it to the highest and best bidder for cash. The sale need not be conducted by the creditor or holder of the creditor's certificate personally but may be conducted through any agent or attorney. The holder of the certificate, his agent, or his attorney shall thereupon make an oath to the facts and apply to the judge for an order of transfer to the purchaser. The application shall be accompanied by a certified copy of the certificate of title from the title register as of the date of the sale. The judge shall cause at least five days' notice to be given to the debtor and to any persons who, according to the title register, have acquired any interest in the property subsequent to the issuance of the creditor's certificate; and, if no objections are made or if objections are made after a hearing, the judge shall grant an order of transfer with such directions for cancellation of other certificates and entries and otherwise as shall be in accordance with the justice of the case and with the spirit of this article. The proceeds of the sale shall be applied first to the payment of the costs of advertising the sale and obtaining the judge's order of transfer, then to the payment of the debt, and any remainder shall be paid to the debtor or his order.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1917, p. 108, ยง 35; Code 1933, ยง 60-505.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
