<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-82/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_2_82">
        <num>44-2-82</num>
        <content>
          <p>After the record has been perfected and settled, the judge of the superior court shall proceed to decide the case; and if, upon consideration of such record, the title shall be found in the petitioner, the judge shall enter a decree to that effect ascertaining all limitations, liens, encumbrances, and the like and declaring the land entitled to registration according to his findings. Such decree shall be entered upon the minutes of the superior court and shall become a part of the records thereof. If, upon consideration of the record, the judge finds that the petitioner is not entitled to a decree declaring the land entitled to registration, he shall enter judgment accordingly. If any person shall have filed a cross-action praying for the title to be found in him, the judge may enter a decree to that effect in like manner ascertaining and declaring all limitations, liens, and the like and declaring the land entitled to registration according to his findings. If separate parcels shall be involved, the court shall render a separate decree as to each parcel; and the same shall be done where the petitioner has divided a tract into separately described parcels and has accurately described each parcel for separate registration.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1917, p. 108, ยง 26; Code 1933, ยง 60-222.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
