<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-173/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_2_173">
        <num>44-2-173</num>
        <content>
          <p>Whenever it is desired to have an involuntary transfer registered, petition therefor shall be made to the judge of the court. The judge may hear the facts or, in his discretion, may refer the petition to an examiner of titles to hear and report the facts. The judge shall see to it that all parties at interest are given reasonable notice before any order of transfer is made. Whenever, in his judgment, the interests of justice so require, the judge shall cause notice of the petition to be published in the newspaper in which the sheriff's sales of the county are advertised for not less than four times in four separate weeks. Before granting an order directing the transfer, the judge shall fully satisfy himself that all parties who have or may have an interest in the matter of the transfer have been notified; that, in the case of minors or other persons under disability, guardians ad litem have been appointed to represent their interests; and that there is no valid reason why the order directing involuntary transfer should not be made. Thereupon, he shall enter a decree or judgment upon the minutes of the court, reciting the facts and stating that an order of transfer has been issued, and shall issue the order of transfer in substantially the form and manner prescribed in this article.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1917, p. 108, ยง 50; Code 1933, ยง 60-514.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
