<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-67/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_2_67">
        <num>44-2-67</num>
        <content>
          <p>"To (here list the defendants shown in the petition):
   Please take notice that (here name the plaintiff or plaintiffs) has filed in said court a petition seeking to register, under the provisions of the Land Registration Law, the following described lands (describe them). You are notified to show cause to the contrary, if any you have, before said court on or before the ______ day of ________________________, ________.
   ______________
   Clerk"</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this Code section, if any defendant named in the original petition shall through his counsel request in writing a copy of the petition from the applicant, the applicant shall provide the defendant with a copy of the petition, with all exhibits attached, within five days of the request. The time within which a defendant must file an answer or cross-action to the application shall be suspended from the date of his request for a copy of the petition until the date he receives the copy of the petition, with all exhibits attached, from the applicant.</p>
          <p>Guardians ad litem shall be appointed for infants and other persons under disability in proceedings under this article, as provided for in Title 9.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1917, p. 108, § 10; Code 1933, § 60-209; Ga. L. 1943, p. 326, § 1; Ga. L. 1964, p. 170, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 44; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 44; Ga. L. 2000, p. 1589, § 3.)</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_44_2_67__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this Code section, instead of the clerk's issuing process and making copies of the petition and process and instead of service of the petition and process being made, it shall be sufficient for the clerk to prepare and cause to be issued and served as provided in subsection (a) of this Code section a summons substantially in the following language:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
