<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-2-164/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_2_164">
        <num>44-2-164</num>
        <content>
          <p>The creditor's certificate shall be assignable or negotiable to the same extent as the note or other evidence of indebtedness secured thereby may be, but assignments or transfers of the creditor's certificate need not be noted on the title register. A transfer or assignment of the indebtedness shall operate to transfer the creditor's certificate securing the same in like manner and to the same extent as is set forth in Code Section 10-3-1, relating to the case of transfer of indebtedness secured by mortgage, unless otherwise agreed between the parties. The creditor's certificate may be surrendered and canceled at any time by the owner thereof. It shall be the creditor's duty to surrender the certificate and give an order for cancellation of the same when the debt is paid. If he refuses, he may be compelled by the court to do so and in any proper case the judge may order a cancellation on the title register. Upon presentation of an order of cancellation with the surrendered creditor's certificate or upon presentation of the judge's order directing cancellation, the clerk shall enter a notation of the same in the register of titles and on the owner's certificate of title.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1917, p. 108, ยง 33; Code 1933, ยง 60-504.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
