<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-101/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_3_101">
        <num>44-3-101</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 609, ยง 33; Ga. L. 1990, p. 227, ยง 9; Ga. L. 2012, p. 1031, ยง 1/SB 136; Ga. L. 2017, p. 352, ยง 3/SB 46.)</p>
          <p>The 2012 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2012, added subsection (c) and redesignated former subsection (c) as present subsection (d).</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2017, substituted the present provisions of subsection (c) for the former provisions, which read: "Notwithstanding and prior to the usual expiration of the period of the declarant's right to control the association pursuant to subsection (a) of this Code section, the right to control also may pass to the unit owners as provided in this subsection if the declarant fails to do any of the following: (1) incorporate the association pursuant to subsection (a) of Code Section 44-3-100; (2) cause the board of directors to be duly appointed and the officers to be elected pursuant to subsection (b) of Code section 44-3-100; (3) maintain and make available to owners, upon written request, a list of the names and business or home addresses of the association's current directors and officers; (4) call meetings of the members of the association in accordance with the provisions of the association's bylaws at least annually pursuant to Code Section 44-3-102; or (5) prepare an annual operating budget and establish the annual assessment and distribute the budget and notice of assessment to the owners in accordance with the condominium instruments no later than 30 days after the beginning of the association's fiscal year. In the event that the declarant fails to meet one or more of the obligations of this subsection, then any owner, acting individually or jointly with other owners, may send the declarant written notice of the failure to comply with such requirements and provide the declarant a 30 day opportunity to cure the failure; and such notice shall be sent by certified mail or statutory overnight delivery to the declarant's principal office. If the declarant fails to cure any or all deficiencies identified in the notice within 30 days of such notice, then any owner, acting individually or jointly with other owners, may file a petition in the superior court of the county in which any portion of the condominium is located in order to obtain an order to grant the owners control of the association. The superior court shall have authority to hold a hearing and issue a summary ruling on said petition at any time designated by the court not earlier than 20 days after the service thereof, unless the parties consent in writing to an earlier trial. If the owners prevail in such action, then the superior court shall award to the owners all reasonable attorney's fees and costs incurred by the owners for the prosecution of such action."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
