<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-3-74/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_3_74">
        <num>44-3-74</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1975, p. 609, ยง 11; Ga. L. 2016, p. 193, ยง 9/HB 1004; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, ยง 44/HB 323.)</p>
          <p>The 2016 amendment,
      effective January 1, 2017, substituted the present provisions of subsection (b) for the former provisions, which read: "In addition to the records and indexes required to be maintained by the clerk of the superior court, such clerk shall maintain one or more separate plat books, entitled 'Condominium Plat Book," in which shall be recorded all plats required to be filed pursuant to this article. In addition to such plats, there shall also be entitled to be recorded in such plat books other plats, including site plans and plot plans, prepared by a registered land surveyor and affecting any condominium; but the same shall not constitute the recording of a plat pursuant to Code Section 44-3-83 unless they comply with all requirements thereof. The record of the declaration and of any amendment thereto shall contain a reference to the plat book and page number of the plat or plats recorded in connection therewith."; deleted former subsection (c), which read: "The plans required to be recorded pursuant to Code Section 44-3-83 shall be kept by the clerk of the superior court in a separate file for each condominium and shall be indexed in the same manner as a conveyance entitled to record, numbered serially in the order of receipt, each designated 'Condominium Plans,' with the name of the condominium, and each containing a reference to the deed book and page number where the first page of the declaration is recorded or the document number assigned to the declaration upon its recordation. The record of the declaration and of any amendment thereto shall contain a reference to the file number of the plans recorded in connection therewith."; redesignated former subsection (d) as present subsection (c); and, in present subsection (c), deleted "the" following "clerk of" in the middle.</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective May 9, 2017, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, revised language in subsection (b).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
