<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-5-167/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_5_167">
        <num>44-5-167</num>
        <content>
          <p>Possession under a duly recorded deed shall be construed to extend to all the contiguous property embraced in such deed. To the extent that any such property is bounded on one or more sides by a railroad, and the description of the property contained in such deed makes reference to the railroad or the railroad right of way as a boundary for such property, such reference shall be construed to mean that the boundary line is located at the edge of the tract depicted on the official map of the railroad filed with the Interstate Commerce Commission pursuant to the Railroad Valuation Act of March 1, 1913, Stat. 701, as amended, and such depictions contained on such official railroad map shall be conclusive as to the location of the boundary line between the property of the railroad and any adjoining property owner as of the date of such railroad map; provided, however, that each railroad corporation and railroad company shall file and record such official map of the railroad with the superior court for the county in which such land depicted on such official railroad map is situated. Any court of this state shall take judicial notice of the information set forth in any such official map properly filed and recorded by such railroad corporation or railroad company.</p>
          <p>(Civil Code 1895, ยง 3587; Civil Code 1910, ยง 4167; Code 1933, ยง 85-405; Ga. L. 2008, p. 210, ยง 6/HB 1283.)</p>
          <p>The 2008 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2008, in the first sentence substituted "shall" for "will", substituted "such" for "the", and added the last two sentences.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
