<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-21/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_7_21">
        <num>44-7-21</num>
        <content>
          <p>"
      NOTICE OF COMMISSION RIGHTS</p>
          <p>The undersigned licensed Georgia real estate broker does hereby publish this NOTICE OF COMMISSION RIGHTS pursuant to Code Section 44-7-21 of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated to establish that the lease set forth below contains a written brokerage commission agreement providing for the payment or promise of payment of compensation for brokerage services.
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Owner
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Landlord
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Tenant
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Lease date
   Lease term
   __________________________________________________________________________
   Project name or building
   Legal Description: All that tract or parcel of land lying and being in the State of Georgia, County of ________, being more particularly described on Exhibit 'A' attached hereto and made a part hereof. (A full and complete legal description is required for this form to be valid.)
   Given under hand and seal this ________ day of ________________________, ________.
   Signed, sealed, and
   delivered in the
   presence of:
   Broker:
   ______________________________
   __________________________ (Seal)
   Unofficial Witness
   Name:__________________
   ______________________________
   ______________________________
   Notary Public
   Georgia Real Estate
   (Notary Seal Attached)
   License No. ____________________________"
   (c)
   The real estate broker must file a release of commission rights within 30 days of receipt of the final payment of commissions due under the written brokerage commission agreement.
   (d)
   This Code section shall only apply to leaseholds of all or a portion of commercial real estate as that term is defined in Code Section 44-14-601 which are entered into on or after July 1, 1997.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding any provision of this Code section to the contrary, this Code section does not create an interest in the real property which is the subject of the lease.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_44_7_21__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A real estate broker shall be entitled to the protections afforded by this Code section only upon the broker's recording a notice of commission rights in the deed records in the office of the clerk of the superior court in the county in which the real property or leasehold interest is located within 30 days of the execution of the lease incorporating the written brokerage commission agreement. Said notice of commission rights must be filed before conveyance of the real property, must be signed by the broker or by a person expressly authorized to sign on behalf of the broker, and must follow substantially the following form:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
