<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/44-7-33/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_7_33">
        <num>44-7-33</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 61-604, enacted by Ga. L. 1976, p. 1372, ยง 6; Ga. L. 2018, p. 969, ยง 3/HB 834.)</p>
          <p>The 2018 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2018, in subsection (a), substituted "premises which shall" for "premises, which list shall" in the first sentence, substituted "such list" for "the list" in the second and fourth sentences, inserted a comma following "sign the list" in the third sentence, and inserted "or she" in the middle of the fourth sentence; substituted the present provisions of subsection (b) for the former provisions, which read: "Within three business days after the date of the termination of occupancy, the landlord or his agent shall inspect the premises and compile a comprehensive list of any damage done to the premises which is the basis for any charge against the security deposit and the estimated dollar value of such damage. The tenant shall have the right to inspect the premises within five business days after the termination of the occupancy in order to ascertain the accuracy of the list. The landlord and the tenant shall sign the list, and this shall be conclusive evidence of the accuracy of the list. If the tenant refuses to sign the list, he shall state specifically in writing the items on the list to which he dissents and shall sign such statement of dissent. If the tenant terminates occupancy without notifying the landlord, the landlord may make a final inspection within a reasonable time after discovering the termination of occupancy."; and, in subsection (c), in the middle of the first sentence, substituted "compiled" for "given" and inserted "and provided to the tenant pursuant to Code Section 44-7-34", substituted "tenant is present for the inspection of the premises after vacancy and signs the landlord's final damage list or fails" for "tenant fails to sign a list or" near the middle of the third sentence, and added the fourth sentence.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
