<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-1-1/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_1_1">
        <num>46-1-1</num>
        <content>
          <p>As used in this title, the term:</p>
          <p>(Orig. Code 1863, §§ 2038, 2039; Code 1868, §§ 2039, 2040; Code 1873, §§ 2065, 2066; Ga. L. 1878-79, p. 125, § 12; Code 1882, §§ 719l, 2065, 2066; Civil Code 1895, §§ 2199, 2263, 2264, 2267; Civil Code 1910, §§ 2642, 2711, 2712, 2715; Ga. L. 1931, Ex. Sess., p. 99, § 2; Ga. L. 1931, p. 199, §§ 2, 33; Ga. L. 1933, p. 198, § 1; Code 1933, §§ 18-101, 18-201, 68-502, 68-601, 93-101; Ga. L. 1939, p. 207, § 1; Ga. L. 1943, p. 179, § 1; Ga. L. 1960, p. 1129, § 1; Ga. L. 1962, p. 630, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 30, § 1; Ga. L. 1963, p. 365, § 1; Ga. L. 1964, p. 298, § 1; Ga. L. 1970, p. 224, § 1; Ga. L. 1975, p. 1190, § 1; Ga. L. 1976, p. 197, § 1; Ga. L. 1979, p. 651, § 1; Ga. L. 1980, p. 479, § 1; Code 1933, § 93-102, enacted by Ga. L. 1981, p. 121, § 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 46; Ga. L. 1982, p. 410, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 827, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 35; Ga. L. 1983, p. 735, § 1; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 46; Ga. L. 1984, p. 1394, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 1394, § 1; Ga. L. 1986, p. 1283, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 1090, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 709, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1993, p. 579, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 97, § 46; Ga. L. 1994, p. 661, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1238, § 1; Ga. L. 1995, p. 1302, § 14; Ga. L. 1996, p. 950, § 2; Ga. L. 1997, p. 798, § 1; Ga. L. 2000, p. 951, §§ 9-1, 9-2, 9-3; Ga. L. 2002, p. 415, § 46; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1378, § 8; Ga. L. 2005, p. 334, § 28-1/HB 501; Ga. L. 2007, p. 607, § 1/HB 317; Ga. L. 2007, p. 679, § 1/HB 389; Ga. L. 2009, p. 669, § 1/HB 440; Ga. L. 2011, p. 479, § 18/HB 112; Ga. L. 2012, p. 580, § 14/HB 865; Ga. L. 2012, p. 775, § 46/HB 942.)</p>
          <p>The 2002 amendments.
      The first 2002 amendment, effective April 18, 2002, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, deleted "by the Public Service Commission" preceding "pursuant to this title" in paragraph (2) and substituted "Department of Motor Vehicle Safety" for "Public Service Commission" in paragraph (18). The second 2002 amendment, effective July 1, 2002, rewrote paragraph (7); rewrote subparagraph (9)(C); and, in paragraph (11), substituted "United States Department of Transportation" for "interstate Commerce Commission" and inserted "passenger" near the middle.</p>
          <p>The 2005 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2005, substituted "commission" for "commissioner of motor vehicle safety" in paragraph (7); deleted ", provided that they do not operate to or from fixed termini outside of such limits and to any dray or truck which operates within the corporate limits of a city and is subject to regulation by the governing authority of such city or by the commissioner of motor vehicle safety and which goes beyond the corporate limits only for the purpose of hauling chattels which have been seized under any court process" at the end of
   division (9)(C)(ii); in division (9)(C)(x), substituted "commissioner of public safety" for "commissioner of motor vehicle safety" three times and inserted "and the Environment" following "Senate Natural Resources" in the next-to-last sentence; deleted division (9)(C)(xii), which read: "Motor vehicles engaged in compensated intercorporate hauling whereby transportation of property is provided by a person who is a member of a corporate family for other members of such corporate family, provided:</p>
          <p>"(I)
   The parent corporation notifies the commissioner of motor vehicle safety of its intent or the intent of one of the subsidiaries to provide the transportation;</p>
          <p>"(II)
   The notice contains a list of participating subsidiaries and an affidavit that the parent corporation owns directly or indirectly a 100 percent interest in each of the subsidiaries;</p>
          <p>"(III)
   A copy of the notice is carried in the cab of all vehicles conducting the transportation; and</p>
          <p>"(IV)
   The transportation entity of the corporate family registers the compensated intercorporate hauling operation with the commissioner of motor vehicle safety, registers and identifies any of its vehicles, and becomes subject to the commissioner's liability insurance and motor common carrier and motor contract carrier and hazardous materials transportation rules. For the purpose of this division, the term 'corporate family' means a group of corporations consisting of a parent corporation and all subsidiaries in which the parent corporation owns directly or indirectly a 100 percent interest;" substituted "state revenue commissioner" for "commissioner of motor vehicle safety" four times in division (9)(C)(xiii) and paragraphs (11) and (18), and
   added "state revenue" preceding "commissioner's" in division (9)(C)(xiii).</p>
          <p>The 2007 amendments.
      The first 2007 amendment, effective July 1, 2007, in division (9)(C)(ii), in the second sentence, substituted "such vehicles" for "taxicabs and buses" in the middle and added a period at the end, and added the last two sentences.
   The second 2007 amendment, effective July 1, 2007, added the last sentence in subparagraph (9)(B) and substituted the present provisions of division (9)(C)(xiii) for the former provisions which read: "Vehicles, except limousines, transporting not more than ten persons for hire, except that any operator of such a vehicle is required to register the exempt operation with the state revenue commissioner, register and identify any of its vehicles, and become subject to the state revenue commissioner's liability insurance and vehicle safety rules;".</p>
          <p>The 2009 amendment,
      effective May 4, 2009, added paragraphs (5.1), (6.2), and (6.3); in paragraph (6), near the beginning, inserted "'compensation' or 'for'" and inserted "payment or other", and added "or for hire, provided that no exempt rideshare shall be deemed to involve any element of transportation for compensation or for hire" at the end; and, in paragraph (13), deleted "or" at the end of subparagraph (13)(C), substituted "; or" for a period at the end of subparagraph (13)(D), and added subparagraph (13)(E).</p>
          <p>The 2011 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2011, substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of paragraph (8), which read: "'Motor carrier of property' means a motor common or contract carrier engaged in transporting property, except household goods, in intrastate commerce in this state."; in subparagraph (9)(A), substituted "persons or household goods or engaged in the activity of nonconsensual towing pursuant to Code Section 44-1-13 for hire over any public highway in this state" for "persons or property for hire over any public highway in this state and not operated exclusively within the corporate limits of any city", and added the last sentence; in subparagraph (9)(B), substituted "household goods" for "property", and inserted "or engaged in the activity of nonconsensual towing pursuant to Code Section 44-1-13," in the first sentence; in division (9)(C)(ii), deleted "drays, trucks, buses, and other motor vehicles" following "Taxicabs" in the first sentence and deleted the period following the first sentence, deleted the second through fourth sentences, relating to the exception of regulation by the governing authorities and tow trucks engaged in consensual towing, respectively, and added "the provisions of this division notwithstanding, vehicles and the drivers thereof operating within the corporate limits of any city shall be subject to the safety regulations adopted by the commissioner of public safety pursuant to Code Section 40-1-8" at the end of the present first sentence; substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of division (9)(C)(v), which read: "Granite trucks, where transportation from quarry to finishing plant involves not crossing more than two counties"; substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of division (9)(C)(vi), relating to RFD carriers and star-route carriers; substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of division (9)(C)(vii), relating to motor trucks of railway companies which perform pick-up and delivery; substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of division (9)(C)(ix), relating to single source leasing; substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of division (9)(C)(x), relating to motor vehicles engaged exclusively in the transportation of agricultural or dairy products; substituted "subparagraph" for "paragraph" at the end of division (9)(c)(xiii); substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of paragraph (11), relating to the definition of "permit"; and substituted "Reserved" for the former provisions of paragraph (13), relating to the definition of "private carrier"; and substituted "commission" for "state revenue commissioner" at the end of paragraph (18).</p>
          <p>The 2012 amendments.
      The first 2012 amendment, effective July 1, 2012, rewrote this Code section. The second 2012 amendment, effective May 1, 2012, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "renter's" for "rentor's" in subparagraph (5.1)(C). See Editor's notes regarding the effect of these amendments.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
