<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-3-322/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_3_322">
        <num>46-3-322</num>
        <content>
          <p>(name and address of the newspaper</p>
          <p>designated by the incorporator or</p>
          <p>incorporators or his or</p>
          <p>their representative)</p>
          <p>Dear Sirs:
   You are requested to publish, four times, a notice in the following form:
   "______________ (name of electric membership corporation) has been duly incorporated on ______________ (month, day, and year to be inserted by the Secretary of State), by the issuance of a certificate of incorporation by the Secretary of State in accordance with the applicable provisions of Article 4 of Chapter 3 of Title 46, the 'Georgia Electric Membership Corporation Act.' The initial registered office of the electric membership corporation is located at ______________ (address of registered office) and its initial registered agent at such address is (name of agent)."
   Enclosed is a (check, draft, or money order) in the amount of $60.00 in payment of the costs of publishing this notice.
   Very truly yours,
   (Name and address
   of incorporator or
   incorporators or his or
   their representative)</p>
          <p>A check, draft, or money order in the amount of $60.00, payable to the designated newspaper; and</p>
          <p>A consent to appointment as registered agent, as provided for in subsection (c) of Code Section 46-3-240.</p>
          <p>State of Georgia
   Office of the Secretary of State
   Ex Officio Corporation Commissioner
   This is to certify that ______________ (the name of the electric membership corporation) has been duly incorporated under the laws of the State of Georgia on the ______ day of ________________________, ________ (insert date articles of incorporation are delivered for filing), by the filing of articles of incorporation in the office of the Secretary of State and the fees therefor paid, as provided by law, and that attached hereto is a true copy of the said articles of incorporation.
   Witness my hand and official seal, this ______ day of ________________________, ________.
   __________________________
   Secretary of State
   Ex Officio Corporation
   Commissioner of the
   State of Georgia</p>
          <p>Return the certificate of incorporation with the conformed copy of the articles of incorporation attached thereto to the incorporator or incorporators or his or their representative. A copy of the certificate of incorporation shall be attached to the original articles of incorporation;</p>
          <p>Forward a conformed copy of the articles of incorporation with a copy of the certificate of incorporation attached thereto, along with the check, draft, or money order provided for in paragraph (3) of subsection (c) of this Code section, to the clerk of the superior court in the county where the initial registered office of the electric membership corporation is located, within four business days after the articles of incorporation have been delivered to the Secretary of State for filing;</p>
          <p>Mail the letter and the check, draft, or money order provided for in paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (c) of this Code section, with the date of incorporation inserted in the notice, to the designated newspaper within four business days after the articles of incorporation have been delivered to the Secretary of State for filing.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 644, § 8; Ga. L. 1980, p. 72, § 4; Code 1933, § 34C-703, enacted by Ga. L. 1981, p. 1587, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 6, § 46; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 46.)</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_46_3_322__subsec_4">
          <num>(4)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A letter addressed to the publisher of a newspaper which is the official organ of the county where the initial registered office of the electric membership corporation is to be located or which is a newspaper of general circulation published within that county whose most recently published annual statement of ownership and circulation reflects a minimum of 60 percent paid circulation. This letter shall contain a notice to be published four times in the newspaper and shall be in substantially the following form:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_46_3_322__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Issue a certificate of incorporation in substantially the following form and attach it to one conformed copy of the articles of incorporation:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
