<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-58/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_4_58">
        <num>46-4-58</num>
        <content>
          <p>All gas which has previously been reduced to possession and which is subsequently injected into an underground storage reservoir shall at all times be deemed the property of the injector, its heirs, successors, or assigns; and in no event shall such gas be subject to any right of the owner of the surface of the land under which such underground reservoir lies, or of the owner of any mineral interest therein, or of any person other than such injector, its heirs, successors, or assigns, to release, produce, take, reduce to possession, or otherwise interfere with or exercise any control thereof; provided, however, that the right of condemnation granted by Code Section 46-4-57 shall be without prejudice to the right of the owner of the condemned land or the owner of any other right or interest therein to drill or bore through the underground reservoir in such a manner as will protect the underground reservoir against pollution and against the escape of gas and as will comply with the order of the commission and the rules and regulations of the Department of Natural Resources issued for the purpose of protecting underground storage; provided, further, that the right of condemnation granted by Code Section 46-4-57 shall be without prejudice to the rights of the owner of such land or the owner of any other right or interest therein as to all other uses thereof.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 93-811, enacted by Ga. L. 1965, p. 463, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
