<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/46-4-56/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_4_56">
        <num>46-4-56</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any party appearing at the hearing who is directly affected by an order of the commission approving or disapproving a proposed underground storage project considered at such hearing shall have the right to judicial review of the order by filing a petition with the Superior Court of Fulton County within 30 days after the entry of the order by the commission. In the event no such petition is filed within such time, the order of the commission shall be final and conclusive. In such action the burden of proof shall be upon the party complaining of such order, and such order shall be deemed prima facie valid. Any person directly interested in the subject matter may, in the discretion of the court, be permitted to intervene in such action. Any party to such action may offer in evidence all or any part of the record of the hearing before the commission and any other relevant evidence. The practice, pleading, and proceedings in such action shall be equitable in nature. The court shall have jurisdiction to enter a decree affirming or setting aside such order or remanding the cause to the commission with directions to modify such order so that it shall conform to this article. Such action shall have precedence over other matters before the court. Appeals may be taken by any party to such action in the same manner and to the same extent as in other civil actions.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 93-808, enacted by Ga. L. 1965, p. 463, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
