<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-6-47/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_6_47">
        <num>2-6-47</num>
        <content>
          <p>The commission shall publish the result of the referendum. It shall consider and determine whether the continued operation of the district within the defined boundaries is administratively practicable and feasible. If the commission determines that the continued operation of such district is administratively practicable and feasible, it shall record such determination and deny the petition; provided, however, that the commission shall not have the authority to determine that the continued operation of the district is administratively practicable and feasible unless at least a majority of the votes cast in the referendum were cast in favor of the continuance of such district. If the commission determines that the continued operation of such district is not administratively practicable and feasible, it shall record such determination and shall certify such determination to the supervisors of the district. In making its determination, the commission shall give due regard and weight to the attitudes of the owners and occupiers of lands lying within the district, the number of landowners eligible to vote in such referendum who voted, the proportion of the votes cast in such referendum in favor of the discontinuance of the district to the total number of votes cast, the approximate wealth and income of the landowners and occupiers of land of the district, the probable expense of carrying on erosion control operations within such district, and such other economic and social factors as may be relevant to such determination, having due regard to the legislative findings set forth in Code Section 2-6-21.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 377, ยง 13; Ga. L. 1988, p. 269, ยง 16.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
