<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-7-99/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_7_99">
        <num>2-7-99</num>
        <content>
          <p>Required; competency. No individual shall purchase, use, or supervise the use of any pesticide as a private applicator unless he is licensed as a certified private applicator or is acting under the direct supervision of an individual who is licensed as a certified private applicator. The Commissioner shall require the applicant to demonstrate his competency to apply "restricted use pesticides" safely, effectively, and in such a manner as to prevent any unreasonable adverse effects on the environment. Such determination of competency shall be made on the basis of standards and procedures approved by the Environmental Protection Agency in the "Georgia Plan for Certification of Pesticide Applicators."</p>
          <p>Application for license; form; content. Application for a license shall be made in writing to the Commissioner on a designated form obtained from the Commissioner's office. Each application shall contain information regarding the applicant's qualifications and proposed operations and shall include the following:</p>
          <p>The name of the person applying for the license;</p>
          <p>The complete home address and mailing address of the applicant; and</p>
          <p>Any other information pertinent to the applicant's operation.</p>
          <p>Issuance. If the Commissioner finds the applicant qualified to use or supervise the use of "restricted use pesticides" as a private pesticide applicator, he shall issue such license, to be effective for a specified period which shall be determined by the Commissioner by regulation. There shall be no fee required for a certified private applicator's license.</p>
          <p>Required; competency. No individual shall purchase, use, or supervise the use of any pesticide as a commercial applicator unless he is licensed as a certified commercial applicator or is acting under the direct supervision of an individual who is licensed as a certified commercial applicator. No person shall commercially apply any pesticide by aerial equipment without a certified commercial pesticide applicator license. The Commissioner shall require the applicant to demonstrate his competency to apply pesticides safely, effectively, and without any unreasonable adverse effects on the environment. Such determination of competency shall be made on the basis of standards and procedures approved by the Environmental Protection Agency in the "Georgia Plan for Certification of Pesticide Applicators."</p>
          <p>Application for license; form; content. Application for a license shall be made in writing to the Commissioner on a designated form obtained from the Commissioner's office. Each application shall contain information regarding the applicant's qualifications and proposed operations and shall include the following:</p>
          <p>The full name of the person applying for the license;</p>
          <p>The principal business address of the applicant in this state and elsewhere;</p>
          <p>If applicable, the name and address of an attorney in fact pursuant to the requirements of Chapter 5 of this title, the "Department of Agriculture Registration, License, and Permit Act"; and</p>
          <p>Any other necessary information prescribed by the Commissioner.</p>
          <p>Issuance; fees; renewal. If the Commissioner finds the applicant qualified to apply pesticides in the classification or classifications he or she has applied for, the Commissioner shall issue a certified commercial pesticide applicator's license. Effective August 21, 1980, all new certified commercial pesticide applicator licenses shall be issued for a period of five years from the date of certification. The fee for the five-year license shall be $90.00. Licenses shall be subject to renewal on the day following expiration, based on such recertification requirements as the Commissioner may establish by regulation.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1972, p. 849, § 7; Ga. L. 1976, p. 369, § 7; Ga. L. 1980, p. 749, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 2; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1253, § 1; Ga. L. 2010, p. 9, § 1-5/HB 1055.)</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_7_99__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>C
      ERTIFIED PRIVATE APPLICATOR'S LICENSE.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_7_99__subsec_2">
          <num>(2)</num>
          <content>
            <p>C
      ERTIFIED COMMERCIAL PESTICIDE APPLICATOR'S LICENSE.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
