<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/2-8-14/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_8_14">
        <num>2-8-14</num>
        <content>
          <p>(c.1) (1)The Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes shall also be composed of:</p>
          <p>Two members, who shall be producers of wine, appointed by the ex officio members of the Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes. Said members shall serve initial terms of two years and subsequent terms of three years from the effective date of their appointment and until their successors are appointed and qualified;</p>
          <p>One member appointed by the ex officio members of the Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes who shall be a producer of wine and shall reside in one of the following counties of this state: Banks, Bartow, Catoosa, Chattooga, Cherokee, Dade, Dawson, Elbert, Fannin, Floyd, Forsyth, Franklin, Gilmer, Gordon, Habersham, Hall, Hart, Jackson, Lumpkin, Madison, Murray, Pickens, Rabun, Stephens, Towns, Union, Walker, White, or Whitfield. In appointing such member, the ex officio members shall consider any recommendations of the board of directors of Georgia Wine Producers, Inc. Such member shall serve a three-year term from the effective date of his or her appointment and until a successor is appointed and qualified;</p>
          <p>One member appointed by the ex officio members of the Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes who shall be a producer of wine and shall reside in one of the following counties of this state: Baldwin, Barrow, Bibb, Bleckley, Bulloch, Burke, Butts, Candler, Carroll, Chattahoochee, Clarke, Clayton, Cobb, Columbia, Coweta, Crawford, DeKalb, Douglas, Effingham, Emanuel, Fayette, Fulton, Glascock, Greene, Gwinnett, Hancock, Haralson, Harris, Heard, Henry, Houston, Jasper, Jefferson, Jenkins, Johnson, Jones, Lamar, Laurens, Lincoln, Macon, Marion, McDuffie, Meriwether, Monroe, Morgan, Muscogee, Newton, Oconee, Oglethorpe, Paulding, Peach, Pike, Polk, Putnam, Richmond, Rockdale, Schley, Screven, Spalding, Talbot, Taliaferro, Taylor, Treutlen, Troup, Twiggs, Upson, Walton, Warren, Washington, Wilkes, or Wilkinson. In appointing such member, the ex officio members shall consider any recommendations of the board of directors of Georgia Wine Producers, Inc. Such member shall serve a three-year term from the effective date of his or her appointment and until a successor is appointed and qualified; and</p>
          <p>One member appointed by the ex officio members of the Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes who shall be a producer of wine and shall reside in one of the following counties of this state: Appling, Atkinson, Bacon, Baker, Ben Hill, Berrien, Brantley, Brooks, Bryan, Calhoun, Camden, Charlton, Chatham, Clay, Clinch, Coffee, Colquitt, Cook, Crisp, Decatur, Dodge, Dooly, Dougherty, Early, Echols, Evans, Glynn, Grady, Irwin, Jeff Davis, Lanier, Lee, Liberty, Long, Lowndes, McIntosh, Miller, Mitchell, Montgomery, Pierce, Pulaski, Quitman, Randolph, Seminole, Stewart, Sumter, Tattnall, Telfair, Terrell, Thomas, Tift, Toombs, Turner, Ware, Wayne, Webster, Wheeler, Wilcox, or Worth. In appointing such member, the ex officio members shall consider any recommendations of the board of directors of Georgia Wine Producers, Inc. Such member shall serve a three-year term from the effective date of his or her appointment and until a successor is appointed and qualified.</p>
          <p>Vacancies shall be filled by appointment by the ex officio members of the Agricultural Commodity Commission for Wine and Grapes, in like manner, for the unexpired term, except that vacancies in the office of a member elected by a legislative committee shall be filled for the unexpired term by the legislative committee which made the previous appointment. Any appointed member shall be eligible for reappointment provided he or she is nominated as provided in this Code section.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
