<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/29-4-3/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_4_3">
        <num>29-4-3</num>
        <content>
          <p>(b.1)If no other person is available to serve as guardian of the ward, the judge may appoint a public guardian in accordance with Chapter 10 of this title. In the event the court determines that there is no public guardian registered in accordance with Chapter 10 of this title appropriately available to serve as guardian for a ward, the court may appoint the Department of Human Services as guardian. If so appointed, the department shall designate a representative of the department to provide guardian services who shall take the oath of guardianship. If, after having been so appointed, the department presents to the court a public guardian registered in accordance with Chapter 10 of this title or some other person suitable and appropriate to serve as guardian of a ward and willing to so serve, the court shall allow the department to resign and shall appoint such public guardian or such other person. If the department is appointed pursuant to this subsection, it shall be bound by all the requirements of this chapter, except that it shall not be required to post bond or pay any cost or fee of court associated with the guardianship proceeding. If the department is appointed pursuant to this subsection and enters into a contract with an independent contractor for the provision of guardianship services, the expense of providing such services may be paid for from state funds appropriated for public guardians under Chapter 10 of this title or, upon approval of the court, from the estate of the ward.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
