<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/6-4-10/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_4_10">
        <num>6-4-10</num>
        <content>
          <p>The implementation of new air transportation projects that are planned to accommodate 14 C.F.R. Part 121 aircraft operations within the State of Georgia develops and promotes for the public good and general welfare, trade, commerce, tourism, industry, and employment opportunities and promotes the general welfare of the state by creating a favorable climate for the location of new industry, trade, and commerce and the development of existing industry, trade, and commerce within the State of Georgia.It is therefore in the public interest and is vital to the public welfare of the people of Georgia and it is declared to be the public purpose of this chapter to so develop such air transportation projects within this state.No bonds, notes, or other obligations, except refunding bonds, shall be issued by the authority pursuant to this chapter unless its membership adopts a resolution finding that the project for which such bonds, notes, or other obligations are to be issued will promote the foregoing objectives.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
