<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/32-10-103/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_32_10_103">
        <num>32-10-103</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any holders of revenue bonds issued under this article or any of the coupons appertaining thereto, any duly appointed receiver of such bonds or coupons, and any indenture trustee for bondholders, except to the extent the rights given in this Code section may be restricted by resolution passed before the issuance of the bonds or by the trust indenture, may, either at law or in equity, by action, mandamus, or other proceedings, protect and enforce any and all rights under the laws of Georgia or granted in this Code section or under such resolution or trust indentures and may enforce and compel performance of all duties required by this article or by such resolution or trust indenture to be performed by the authority or any officer thereof, including the fixing, charging, and collection of revenues, tolls, and other charges for the use of the project or projects. No holder of any such bond or receiver or indenture trustee thereof shall have the right to compel any exercise of the taxing power of the state to pay any such bond or the interest thereon or to enforce the payment thereof against any property of the state; nor shall any such bond constitute a charge, lien, or encumbrance, legal or equitable, upon any property of the state.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1953, Jan.-Feb. Sess., p. 302, ยง 25; Code 1933, ยง 95A-1262, enacted by Ga. L. 1973, p. 947, ยง 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, ยง 32.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
