<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-3-524/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_3_524">
        <num>12-3-524</num>
        <content>
          <p>The authority, in order to make the Georgia Music Hall of Fame competitive with other nonprofit cultural institutions in securing gifts, grants, donations, and contributions and in the promotion and marketing of the Georgia Music Hall of Fame, is authorized to expend available funds for the meals, entertainment, and incidental expenses of bona fide prospects, contributors, and other persons who attend any function at the request of the authority or its staff to discuss the securing of, to provide services in the securing of, or to make gifts, grants, donations, and contributions to the Georgia Music Hall of Fame or to promote and market Georgia Music Hall of Fame programs and facilities. All such expenditures shall be verified by vouchers showing the date, place, purpose, and persons for whom such expenditures were made. The authority shall make available to the state auditor such vouchers or other collateral materials requested for the purposes of conducting an audit of the authority's books, accounts, and records as required by state law.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
