<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/12-8-122/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_8_122">
        <num>12-8-122</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Compact is substantially as follows:</p>
          <p>'ARTICLE I. POLICY AND PURPOSE</p>
          <p>There is hereby created the Southeast Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Compact. The party states recognize and declare that each state is responsible for providing for availability of capacity either within or outside the state for disposal of low-level radioactive waste generated within its borders, except for waste generated as a result of defense activities of the federal government or federal research and development activities. They also recognize that the management of low-level radioactive waste is handled most efficiently on a regional basis. The party states further recognize that the Congress of the United States, by enacting the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act (P.L. 96-573), has provided for and encouraged the development of low-level radioactive waste compacts as a tool for disposal of such waste. The party states recognize that the safe and efficient management of low-level radioactive waste generated within the region requires that sufficient capacity to dispose of such waste be properly provided.</p>
          <p>It is the policy of the party states to: enter into a regional low-level radioactive waste management compact for the purpose of providing the instrument and framework for a cooperative effort; provide sufficient facilities for the proper management of low-level radioactive waste generated in the region, promote the health and safety of the region; limit the number of facilities required to effectively and efficiently manage low-level radioactive waste generated in the region; encourage the reduction of the amounts of low-level waste generated in the region; distribute the costs, benefits, and obligations of successful low-level radioactive waste management equitably among the party states; and ensure the ecological and economical management of low-level radioactive wastes.</p>
          <p>Implicit in the Congressional consent to this Compact is the expectation by the Congress and the party states that the appropriate federal agencies will actively assist the Compact Commission and the individual party states to this Compact by:</p>
          <p>1. expeditious enforcement of federal rules, regulations, and laws; and</p>
          <p>2. imposing sanctions against those found to be in violation of federal rules, regulations, and laws; and</p>
          <p>3. timely inspection of their licensees to determine their capability to adhere to such rules, regulations, and laws; and</p>
          <p>4. timely provision of technical assistance to this Compact in carrying out their obligations under the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act as amended.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE II. DEFINITIONS</p>
          <p>As used in this Compact, unless the context clearly requires a different construction:</p>
          <p>a.'Commission' or 'Compact Commission' means the Southeast Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Commission.</p>
          <p>b.'facility' means a parcel of land, together with the structures, equipment, and improvements thereon or appurtenant thereto, which is used or is being developed for the treatment, storage, or disposal of low-level radioactive waste.</p>
          <p>c.'generator' means any person who produces or possesses low-level radioactive waste in the course of, or as an incident to, manufacturing, power generation, processing, medical diagnosis and treatment, research, or other industrial or commercial activity. This does not include persons who provide a service to generators by arranging for the collection, transportation, storage or disposal of wastes with respect to such waste generated outside the region.</p>
          <p>d.'high-level waste' means irradiated reactor fuel, liquid wastes from reprocessing irradiated reactor fuel, solids into which such liquid wastes have been converted, and other high-level radioactive waste as defined by the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</p>
          <p>e.'host state' means any state in which a regional facility is situated or is being developed.</p>
          <p>f.'low-level radioactive waste' or 'waste' means radioactive waste not classified as high-level radioactive waste, transuranic waste, spent nuclear fuel, or by-product material as defined in Section 11e.(2) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, or as may be further defined by federal law or regulation.</p>
          <p>g.'party state' means any state which is a signatory party to this Compact.</p>
          <p>h.'person' means any individual, corporation, business enterprise, or other legal entity (either public or private).</p>
          <p>i.'region' means the collective party states.</p>
          <p>j.'regional facility' means (1) a facility as defined in this Article which has been designated, authorized, accepted, or approved by the Commission to receive waste or (2) the disposal facility in Barnwell County, South Carolina, owned by the State of South Carolina and as licensed for the burial of low-level radioactive waste on July 1, 1982, but in no event shall this disposal facility serve as a regional facility beyond December 31, 1992.</p>
          <p>k.'state' means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands or any other territorial possession of the United States.</p>
          <p>l.'transuranic wastes' means waste material containing transuranic elements with contamination levels as determined by the regulations of (1) the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission or (2) any host state, if it is an agreement state under Section 274 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</p>
          <p>m.'waste management' means the storage, treatment, or disposal of waste.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE III. RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS</p>
          <p>The rights granted to the party states by this Compact are additional to the rights enjoyed by sovereign states, and nothing in this Compact shall be construed to infringe upon, limit, or abridge those rights.</p>
          <p>a.Subject to any license issued by the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission or a host state, each party state shall have the right to have all wastes generated within its borders stored, treated, or disposed of, as applicable, at regional facilities, and additionally shall have the right of access to facilities made available to the region through agreements entered into by the Commission pursuant to Article IV(e)(9). The right of access by a generator within a party state to any regional facility is limited by its adherence to applicable state and federal law and regulation.</p>
          <p>b.If no operating regional facility is located within the borders of a party state and the waste generated within its borders must therefore be stored, treated, or disposed of at a regional facility in another state, the party state without such facilities may be required by the host state or states to establish a mechanism which provides compensation for access to the regional facility according to terms and conditions established by the host state or states and approved by a two-thirds vote of the commission.</p>
          <p>c.Each party state must establish the capability to regulate, license, and ensure the maintenance and extended care of any facility within its borders. Host states are responsible for the availability, the subsequent post-closure observation and maintenance, and the extended institutional control of their regional facilities, in accordance with the provisions of Article V, Section b.</p>
          <p>d.Each party state must establish the capability to enforce any applicable federal or state laws and regulations pertaining to the packaging and transportation of waste generated within or passing through its borders.</p>
          <p>e.Each party state must provide to the Commission on an annual basis, any data and information necessary to the implementation of the Commission's responsibilities. Each party state shall establish the capability to obtain any data and information necessary to meet its obligation herein defined.</p>
          <p>f.Each party state must, to the extent authorized by federal law, require generators within its borders to use the best available waste management technologies and practices to minimize the volumes of wastes requiring disposal.</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE IV. THE COMMISSION</p>
          <p>a.There is hereby created the Southeast Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Commission ('Commission' or 'Compact Commission'). The Commission shall consist of two voting members from each party state to be appointed according to the laws of each state. The appointing authorities of each state must notify the Commission in writing of the identity of its members and any alternates. An alternate may act on behalf of the member only in the member's absence.</p>
          <p>b.Each Commission member is entitled to one vote. No action of the Commission shall be binding unless a majority of the total membership cast their vote in the affirmative, or unless a greater than majority vote is specifically required by any other provision of this Compact.</p>
          <p>c.The Commission must elect from among its members a presiding officer. The Commission shall adopt and publish, in convenient form, by-laws which are consistent with this Compact.</p>
          <p>d.The Commission must meet at least once a year and shall also meet upon the call of the presiding officer, by petition of a majority of the party states, or upon the call of a host state. All meetings of the Commission must be open to the public.</p>
          <p>e.The Commission has the following duties and powers:</p>
          <p>1. to receive and approve the application of a non-party state to become an eligible state in accordance with the provisions of Article VII(b); and,</p>
          <p>2. to receive and approve the application of an eligible state to become a party state in accordance with the provisions of Article VII(c); and</p>
          <p>3. to submit an annual report and other communications to the governors and to the presiding officer of each body of the legislature of the party states regarding the activities of the Commission; and</p>
          <p>4. to develop and use procedures for determining, consistent with considerations for public health and safety, the type and number of regional facilities which are presently necessary and which are projected to be necessary to manage waste generated within the region; and</p>
          <p>5. to provide the party states with reference guidelines for establishing the criteria and procedures for evaluating alternative locations for emergency or permanent regional facilities; and</p>
          <p>6. to develop and adopt, within one year after the Commission is constituted as provided in Article VII, Section d., procedures and criteria for identifying a party state as a host state for a regional facility as determined pursuant to the requirements of this Article. In accordance with these procedures and criteria, the Commission shall identify a host state for the development of a second regional disposal facility within three years after the Commission is constituted as provided for in Article VII, Section d. and shall seek to ensure that such facility is licensed and ready to operate as soon as required but in no event later than 1991.</p>
          <p>In developing criteria, the Commission must consider the following: the health, safety, and welfare of the citizens of the party states; the existence of regional facilities within each party state; the minimization of waste transportation; the volumes and types of wastes generated within each party state; and the environmental, economic, and ecological impacts on the air, land and water resources of the party states.</p>
          <p>The Commission shall conduct such hearings, require such reports, studies, evidence, and testimony, and do what is required by its approved procedures in order to identify a party state as a host state for a needed regional facility; and</p>
          <p>7. in accordance with the procedures and criteria developed pursuant to section (e)(6) of this Article, to designate, by a two-thirds vote, a host state for the establishment of a needed regional facility. The Commission shall not exercise this authority unless the party states have failed to voluntarily pursue the development of such facility. The Commission shall have the authority to revoke the membership of a party state that willfully creates barriers to the siting of a needed regional facility; and</p>
          <p>8. to require of and obtain from party states, eligible states seeking to become party states, and non-party states seeking to become eligible states, data and information necessary to the implementation of Commission responsibilities; and</p>
          <p>9. notwithstanding any other provision of this Compact, to enter into agreements with any person, state, or similar regional body or group of states for the importation of waste into the region and for the right of access to facilities outside the region for waste generated within the region. The authorization to import requires a two-thirds majority vote of the Commission, including an affirmative vote of both representatives of the host state in which any affected regional facility is located. This shall be done only after an assessment of the affected facilities' capability to handle such wastes; and</p>
          <p>10. to act or appear on behalf of any party state or states, only upon written request of both members of the Commission for such state or states, as an intervenor or party in interest before Congress, state legislatures, any court of law, or any federal, state, or local agency, board, or commission which has jurisdiction over the management of wastes. The authority to act, intervene, or otherwise appear shall be exercised by the Commission, only after approval by a majority vote of the Commission; and</p>
          <p>11. to revoke the membership of a party state in accordance with Article VII(f).</p>
          <p>f.The Commission may establish any advisory committees as it deems necessary for the purpose of advising the Commission on any matters pertaining to the management of low-level radioactive waste.</p>
          <p>g.The Commission may appoint or contract for and compensate a limited staff necessary to carry out its duties and functions. The staff shall serve at the Commission's pleasure irrespective of the civil service, personnel, or other merit laws of any of the party states or the federal government and shall be compensated from funds of the Commission. In selecting any staff, the Commission shall assure that the staff has adequate experience and formal training to carry out such functions as may be assigned to it by the Commission. If the Commission has a headquarters it shall be in a party state.</p>
          <p>h.Funding for the Commission shall be provided as follows:</p>
          <p>1. each eligible state, upon becoming a party state, shall pay $25,000 to the Commission which shall be used for costs of the Commission's services.</p>
          <p>2. each state hosting a regional disposal facility shall annually levy special fees or surcharges on all users of such facility, based upon the volume of wastes disposed of at such facilities, the total of which:</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE V. DEVELOPMENT AND OPERATION OF FACILITIES</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VI. OTHER LAWS AND REGULATIONS</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VII. ELIGIBLE PARTIES, WITHDRAWAL, REVOCATION, ENTRY INTO FORCE, TERMINATION</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE VIII. PENALTIES</p>
          <p>A
      RTICLE IX. SEVERABILITY AND CONSTRUCTION</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
