<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/37-4-63/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_37_4_63">
        <num>37-4-63</num>
        <content>
          <p>Upon application to the department by a parent, spouse, next of kin, or guardian or by an agency of another state in which a person is hospitalized, the person shall be eligible to be admitted to a facility in the State of Georgia if found by the department to be a legal resident of Georgia. The department shall designate a facility to which such person is to be transported at no expense to the State of Georgia. The regional state hospital administrator of such facility and the next of kin or guardian of the person shall be notified of this action. The regional state hospital administrator shall be authorized to accept the person for a period not to exceed five days, unless prior to the expiration of such period proceedings have been initiated under Code Section 37-4-42 for an order to receive services from the department. After a thorough physical and mental examination has been made by the medical staff of such facility, the regional state hospital administrator of the facility or his designee is authorized to initiate a petition under this chapter, if this is necessary. Such application shall be forwarded to the court of the county in which that facility is located for action pursuant to this chapter in relation thereto.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, ยง 88-2509.8, enacted by Ga. L. 1978, p. 1826, ยง 1; Ga. L. 2002, p. 1324, ยง 1-18.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
