<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-2-152/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_40_2_152">
        <num>40-2-152</num>
        <content>
          <p>For each apportionable motor bus or van-type vehicle, the fee shall be $3.75 for each 100 pounds or fractional part of 100 pounds factory weight. No motor bus license fee amount shall exceed $875.00.</p>
          <p>Trucks transporting logs, pulpwood, or other forest products shall be issued restricted license plates, and the fees shall be as enumerated in Code Section 40-2-151.</p>
          <p>Each school bus operated exclusively in the transportation of pupils and teachers to and from schools or school activities or in the transportation of the owner and his or her immediate family shall be issued a restricted license plate for the sum of $5.00.A bus owned by a church or owned in common with other churches and used and operated exclusively for the church in transporting members and patrons to and from church or church activities, when no part of the proceeds of the operation of the bus inures to the benefit of any private person, shall be issued a restricted license plate for the sum of $5.00 in the same manner as school buses when the bus complies with the laws applicable to school buses.</p>
          <p>A truck or a truck-tractor hauling fertilizer, milk, or crops as defined in paragraph (7.1) of Code Section 1-3-3 shall be issued a restricted license plate with the fee computed in accordance with Code Section 40-2-151.</p>
          <p>A farm vehicle shall be issued a restricted license plate with the fee computed in accordance with Code Section 40-2-151.</p>
          <p>Only for apportionable vehicles registered under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this Code section:</p>
          <p>For all trailers and semitrailers owned by fleets whose tractors are registered under the International Registration Plan, the apportioned value for ad valorem taxes shall be determined as provided in Code Section 48-5-442.1.</p>
          <p>For all trailers and semitrailers owned by fleets whose tractors are registered under the International Registration Plan, payment of ad valorem taxes shall be accepted by the department upon request of the taxpayer regardless of the county in which such trailer is domiciled.</p>
          <p>Each apportionable vehicle identified under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this Code section shall be subject to an alternative ad valorem tax which shall be determined by the value and rate assigned to each weight class. Each weight class shall be a separate subclass of motor vehicle, and the value of each vehicle shall remain the value for each tax year as follows:</p>
          <p>Less than 30,001 lbs. shall be valued at $15,000.00 and taxed at $50.00 per year;</p>
          <p>30,001 to 36,000 lbs. shall be valued at $25,000.00 and taxed at $75.00 per year;</p>
          <p>36,001 to 44,000 lbs. shall be valued at $40,000.00 and taxed at $125.00 per year;</p>
          <p>The commissioner shall add the alternative ad valorem tax in subsection (k) of this Code section to the vehicle registration fees in subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this Code section, prior to apportionment of those fees. The alternative ad valorem tax shall be apportioned on the same basis and in the same manner as the apportionable registration fees and collected at the same time.</p>
          <p>(A) One percent of the alternative ad valorem tax collected by the commissioner shall be paid into the general fund of the state treasury in order to defray costs of administration.</p>
          <p>The alternative ad valorem tax imposed by this Code section shall be collected by the commissioner and shall be distributed annually from the separate, segregated fund not later than April 1 of the calendar year immediately following the calendar year in which such taxes were paid to the commissioner, in the manner provided for in this subsection.</p>
          <p>Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, each year, the distributions of alternative ad valorem tax proceeds under this subsection shall be based upon the immediately preceding year's tax digest of each qualified tax authority submitted to and approved by the commissioner. If such digest has not been submitted and approved, the commissioner shall, for purposes of this subsection, utilize in its place the most recently submitted and approved tax digest of such qualified tax jurisdiction.</p>
          <p>(A) One percent of the alternative ad valorem tax collected by the commissioner shall be paid into the general fund of the state treasury in order to defray costs of administration.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_40_2_152__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided for in this Code section, the annual fee for all apportionable vehicles not operated as a common or contract carrier for hire in accordance with owner declared gross vehicle weight or combined vehicle gross weight shall be as follows:
   (1) Less than 30,001 lbs. ....................................$ 45.00
   (2) 30,001 to 36,000 lbs. ......................................70.00
   (3) 36,001 to 44,000 lbs. .....................................115.00
   (4) 44,001 to 54,999 lbs. .....................................190.00
   (5) 55,000 to 63,280 lbs. .....................................300.00
   (6) 63,281 lbs. to maximum permitted ..........................400.00</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_40_2_152__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided for in this Code section, the annual fee for all apportionable vehicles operated as a common or contract carrier for hire in accordance with owner declared gross vehicle weight or combined vehicle gross weight shall be as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_40_2_152__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Less than 30,001 lbs. ....................................$ 85.00
   (2) 30,001 to 36,000 lbs. .....................................130.00
   (3) 36,001 to 44,000 lbs. .....................................215.00
   (4) 44,001 to 54,999 lbs. .....................................365.00
   (5) 55,000 to 63,280 lbs. .....................................575.00
   (6) 63,281 lbs. to maximum permitted ..........................725.00</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_40_2_152__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The alternative ad valorem tax imposed by this Code section shall be collected by the commissioner and shall be distributed annually from the separate, segregated fund not later than August 1 of the calendar year immediately following the calendar year in which such taxes were paid to the commissioner, in the manner provided for in this subsection.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
