<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-24/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_40_5_24">
        <num>40-5-24</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 322, art. 4, § 3; Ga. L. 1943, p. 196, § 5; Ga. L. 1951, p. 598, § 2; Ga. L. 1957, p. 103, § 3; Ga. L. 1958, p. 268, § 1; Ga. L. 1959, p. 318, § 1; Code 1933, § 68B-205, enacted by Ga. L. 1975, p. 1008, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 149, § 40; Ga. L. 1989, p. 519, § 8; Ga. L. 1990, p. 1241, § 1; Ga. L. 1990, p. 2048, § 4; Ga. L. 1994, p. 514, § 2; Ga. L. 1997, p. 760, § 12; Ga. L. 1998, p. 3, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 184, § 1-2; Ga. L. 2005, p. 1461, § 4/SB 226; Ga. L. 2006, p. 343, § 3/SB 637; Ga. L. 2010, p. 199, § 2/HB 258; Ga. L. 2010, p. 932, § 6/HB 396; Ga. L. 2011, p. 355, § 3/HB 269; Ga. L. 2014, p. 409, § 5/SB 392; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 40/HB 323; Ga. L. 2021, p. 403, § 4/HB 466.)</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective May 9, 2017, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "instruction permit" for "instructional permit" in subparagraph (a)(1)(B).</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2021, deleted former paragraph (a)(2), which read: "A person who has been issued an instruction permit under this subsection and has never been issued a Class D driver's license under subsection (b) of this Code section will become eligible for a Class D driver's license under subsection (b) of this Code section only if such person is at least 17 years of age, has a valid instruction permit which is not under suspension, and, for a period of not less than 12 consecutive months prior to making application for a Class D driver's license, has not been convicted of a violation of Code Section 40-6-391, hit and run or leaving the scene of an accident in violation of Code Section 40-6-270, racing on highways or streets, using a motor vehicle in fleeing or attempting to elude an officer, reckless driving, or convicted of any offense for which four or more points are assessable under subsection (c) of Code Section 40-5-57; provided, however, that a person who is at least 16 years of age and meets all of the other qualifications of this paragraph except for age who has completed an approved driver education training course as provided in subsection (a.2) of Code Section 40-5-22 will be eligible for a Class D driver's license."; redesignated former paragraph (a)(3) as present paragraph (a)(2); rewrote paragraph (b)(1), which read: "Any resident of this state who is at least 17 years of age and who, for a period of at least 12 months, had a valid instruction permit issued under subsection (a) of this Code section may apply to the department for a Class D driver's license to operate a noncommercial Class C vehicle if such resident has otherwise complied with all prerequisites for the issuance of such Class D driver's license as provided in subsection (a) of this Code section, provided that a resident at least 17 years of age who has at any age surrendered to the department a valid instruction permit or driver's license issued by another state or the District of Columbia or who has submitted to the department proof, to the satisfaction of the department, of a valid instruction permit or driver's license issued by another state or the District of Columbia may apply his or her driving record under such previously issued permit or driver's license toward meeting the eligibility requirements for a Class D driver's license the same as if such previously issued permit or driver's license were an instruction permit issued under subsection (a) of this Code section; provided, however, that a person who is at least 16 years of age and meets all of the other qualifications of this paragraph except for age who has completed an approved driver education training course as provided in subsection (a.2) of Code Section 40-5-22 may apply for a Class D driver's license."; substituted "parents and stepparents, grandparents, siblings and stepsiblings" for "parents and step-parents, grandparents, siblings and step-siblings" in subparagraph (b)(2)(C); and, in paragraph (b)(3), in the middle, inserted "in violation of Code Section 40-6-186", "in violation of Code Section 40-6-395", and "in violation of Code Section 40-6-390", and added the proviso at the end; substituted "completed a driver education training course may apply" for "completed an approved driver education training course as provided in subsection (a.2) of Code Section 40-5-22 may apply" near the end of the second sentence of subsection (c); and deleted former subsection (f), which read: "For the purposes of this Code section, the term 'approved driver education training course' shall include those driver education training courses approved by the Department of Driver Services."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
