<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-5-27/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_40_5_27">
        <num>40-5-27</num>
        <content>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 322, art. 4, § 4; Ga. L. 1951, p. 598, § 3; Code 1933, § 68B-208, enacted by Ga. L. 1975, p. 1008, § 1; Ga. L. 1989, p. 519, § 10; Ga. L. 1990, p. 2048, § 4; Ga. L. 1992, p. 3311, § 2; Ga. L. 1996, p. 1250, § 3; Ga. L. 1997, p. 760, § 14; Ga. L. 2001, p. 184, § 1-3; Ga. L. 2004, p. 749, § 4; Ga. L. 2005, p. 334, § 17-7/HB 501; Ga. L. 2005, p. 525, § 1/HB 613; Ga. L. 2011, p. 752, § 40/HB 142; Ga. L. 2013, p. 281, § 2/HB 475; Ga. L. 2014, p. 710, § 1-7/SB 298; Ga. L. 2015, p. 60, § 4-11/SB 100; Ga. L. 2017, p. 774, § 40/HB 323; Ga. L. 2019, p. 461, § 1/SB 212; Ga. L. 2020, p. 199, § 2-4/HB 463; Ga. L. 2021, p. 403, § 6/HB 466.)</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective May 9, 2017, part of an Act to revise, modernize, and correct the Code, substituted "instruction permit" for "instructional permit" in the last sentence of paragraph (d)(1) and near the end of paragraph (d)(2).</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective January 1, 2020, added a colon at the end of paragraph (d)(1);
   added the division (d)(1)(A)(i) designation; substituted "A classroom or online driver training course licensed by the department and which includes a minimum of 30 class hours of instruction; and" for "a driver training course which includes a minimum of 30 class hours of instruction and six hours of private in-car training" in division (d)(1)(A)(i); added division (d)(1)(A)(ii) and subparagraph (d)(1)(B); designated the former last sentence of paragraph (d)(1) as paragraph (d)(2); and redesignated former paragraph (d)(2) as present paragraph (d)(3).</p>
          <p>The 2020 amendment,
      effective June 30, 2020, inserted "or political subdivision of a foreign country" in subparagraph (a)(3)(B).</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2021, rewrote subsection (d), which read: "(d)(1) The department shall authorize licensed driver training schools to conduct knowledge tests, on-the-road driving skills tests, and other tests required for issuance of a driver's license as provided in this subsection. The department shall, prior to approving a licensed driver training school to conduct tests as provided in this subsection, make a determination that the school has been licensed for a minimum of two years and has conducted driver education courses on a full-time basis for such two-year period and that such school meets all other standards which the department may establish as a condition for approval to conduct such tests. The department shall authorize a driver training school licensed pursuant to Chapter 13 of Title 43 and approved by the department to administer the on-the-road driving skills testing provided for in this Code section, provided that the applicant has successfully completed:</p>
          <p>"(A)(i) A classroom or online driver training course licensed by the department and which includes a minimum of 30 class hours of instruction; and</p>
          <p>"(ii) Six hours of private in-car instruction provided by a licensed instructor employed by the licensed driver training school administering such on-the-road driving skills test.</p>
          <p>"(B) For any applicant 18 years of age or older, a minimum of six hours of private in-car instruction provided by a licensed instructor employed by the licensed driver training school administering such on-the-road driving skills test.</p>
          <p>"(2) The department may establish by rules and regulations the type of tests or demonstrations to be made by applicants for any Class P instruction permit, Class C driver's license, or Class D driver's license under this Code section.</p>
          <p>"(3) The department may authorize public and private high schools to conduct knowledge tests required for issuance of a Class P instruction permit or Class D driver's license or both."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
