<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/40-6-374/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_40_6_374">
        <num>40-6-374</num>
        <content>
          <p>Local authorities shall use the following wording or similar wording in adopting by reference the provisions of this chapter or the definitions contained in Code Section 40-1-1:
   (Municipality or County) of ______________
   Ordinance ______________ number
   An ordinance adopting the Georgia Uniform Rules of the Road, Code Sections [ ________ to ________ (except for Code Sections __________ )] of Chapter 6 of Title 40 of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated, to regulate traffic upon the public streets of the (Municipality or County) of ________ and repealing ordinance number ________ and all other ordinances and sections of ordinances in conflict herewith.
   It is ordained by ________ as follows:
   Section 1. Adoption by reference. Pursuant to Chapter 6 of Title 40 of the Official Code of Georgia Annotated, Code Sections 40-6-372 through 40-6-376, Code Sections [ ________ to ________ (except for Code Sections ______________ )] of that chapter known as the Uniform Rules of the Road and the definitions contained in Code Section 40-1-1 are hereby adopted as and for the traffic regulations of this (Municipality or County) with like effect as if recited herein.
   Section 2. Penalties. Unless another penalty is expressly provided by law, every person convicted of a violation of any provision of this ordinance shall be punished by a fine of not more than ________ dollars or by imprisonment for not more than ________ days or by both such fine and imprisonment.
   Section 3. Repeal. The (existing ordinances covering the same matters as embraced in this ordinance) are hereby repealed and all ordinances or parts of ordinances inconsistent with the provisions of this ordinance are hereby repealed.
   Section 4. Effective date. This ordinance shall take effect from and after the ________ day of ______________, ________.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 68A-1505, enacted by Ga. L. 1974, p. 633, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 3, § 29; Ga. L. 1984, p. 22, § 40; Ga. L. 1990, p. 2048, § 5; Ga. L. 1999, p. 81, § 40.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
