<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-11-284/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_11_284">
        <num>15-11-284</num>
        <content>
          <p>The notice required to be given to the mother, the biological father, and legal father of the child shall state:
   "NOTICE OF EFFECT OF TERMINATION JUDGMENT
   Georgia law provides that you can permanently lose your rights as a parent. A petition to terminate parental rights has been filed requesting the court to terminate your parental rights to your child. A copy of the petition to terminate parental rights is attached to this notice. A court hearing of your case has been scheduled for the __________ day of ____________, __________, at
      (time of day)
      , at the ____________ Court of ____________ County.
   If you fail to appear, the court can terminate your rights in your absence.
   If the court at the trial finds that the facts set out in the petition to terminate parental rights are true and that termination of your rights will serve the best interests of your child, the court can enter a judgment ending your rights to your child.
   If the judgment terminates your parental rights, you will no longer have any rights to your child. This means that you will not have the right to visit, contact, or have custody of your child or make any decisions affecting your child or your child's earnings or property. Your child will be legally freed to be adopted by someone else.
   Even if your parental rights are terminated:
   (1) You will still be responsible for providing financial support (child support payments) for your child's care unless and until your child is adopted; and
   (2) Your child can still inherit from you unless and until your child is adopted.
   This is a very serious matter. You should contact an attorney immediately so that you can be prepared for the court hearing. You have the right to hire an attorney and to have him or her represent you. If you cannot afford to hire an attorney, the court will appoint an attorney if the court finds that you are an indigent person. Whether or not you decide to hire an attorney, you have the right to attend the hearing of your case, to call witnesses on your behalf, and to question those witnesses brought against you.
   If you have any questions concerning this notice, you may call the telephone number of the clerk's office which is ____________."</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
