<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-50/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_10_50">
        <num>15-10-50</num>
        <content>
          <p>Magistrate Court of _____________ County</p>
          <p>State of Georgia</p>
          <p>______________
   Plaintiff
   Current Civil Action
   ______________
   File No. ______________
   Address
   ______________
   v.
   Original Civil Action
   File No. ______________
   ______________
   Defendant
   Court where original
   judgment entered:
   ______________
   ______________
   Address
   ______________</p>
          <p>INTERROGATORIES</p>
          <p>TO: ______________, Defendant in the above-styled action:
   The Plaintiff in the above-styled action requests that you answer the following interrogatories separately, fully, and under oath and serve such answers on said plaintiff at plaintiff's address shown above by mail or hand delivery within 30 days after the service of these interrogatories.
   1. List your full name, home phone number, and address, including apartment number and ZIP Code.
   2. List the name, address, and phone number of your employer(s).
   3. Describe and state the location of each piece of real estate in which you own any interest.
   4. Give the name, address, phone number, and a description of the nature of any business venture in which you own any interest.
   5. List the names, addresses, and phone numbers of all persons who owe money to you and specify the amounts owed.
   6. List the names and addresses of all banks or savings institutions where you have any sums of money deposited and identify the accounts by number.
   7. List and give the present location of all items of personal property owned by you that have a value of more than $100.00.</p>
          <p>VERIFICATION</p>
          <p>STATE OF GEORGIA, COUNTY OF ________________________________________________
   ______________, being first duly sworn on oath, says the foregoing are true and complete answers to the interrogatories propounded by plaintiff to defendant.
   Sworn and subscribed
   before me, this ______
   day of ______, ________.
   ______________
   ______________
   Notary public
   Defendant
   or attesting
   official</p>
          <p>NOTICE</p>
          <p>YOU ARE REQUIRED TO PROVIDE COMPLETE ANSWERS TO THE ABOVE-STATED QUESTIONS TO THE PLAINTIFF WITHIN 30 DAYS AFTER SERVICE OF THESE INTERROGATORIES UPON YOU. IF YOU DO NOT ANSWER, OR DO NOT ANSWER COMPLETELY, YOU MAY BECOME SUBJECT TO THE SANCTIONS PROVIDED BY LAW FOR CONTEMPT OF COURT. IF YOU NEED FURTHER INSTRUCTION OR IF YOU NEED ASSISTANCE IN ANSWERING THE QUESTIONS CONTACT THE COURT AT ONCE.</p>
          <p>The court in its discretion may limit the number of times interrogatories may be propounded upon a judgment debtor, may relieve a judgment debtor of the obligation to answer one or more propounded interrogatories, and may for good cause shown enlarge the time for answering any interrogatory. The court may if necessary compel the answering of interrogatories, but the sanction of contempt shall be applied only after notice and an opportunity for hearing and a showing of willful failure to answer or willful failure to answer fully and truthfully.</p>
          <p>An evasive or incomplete answer to an interrogatory shall be treated as a failure to answer.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Code Section 15-10-42, the judgment creditor or a successor in interest when that interest appears of record may, in addition to any other process or remedy provided by law, utilize the discovery provisions set forth in Code Section 9-11-69.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_10_50__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The interrogatories, verification, and notice shall be in substantially the following form:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
