<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/15-10-48/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_10_48">
        <num>15-10-48</num>
        <content>
          <p>The statement of claim, verification, and notice shall be in substantially the following form:
   Magistrate Court of _____________ County
   State of Georgia
   ________________
   Plaintiff
   ________________
   Address
   v.
   ________________
   Defendant
   Statement of Claim
   (Here the plaintiff or, at his or her request, the court will insert a brief statement of the plaintiff's claim or claims giving the defendant reasonable notice of the basis for each claim and, if the action is on a contract, either express or implied, the original statement of the plaintiff's claim which is to be filed with the court may be verified by the plaintiff or his or her agent as follows:)
   STATE OF GEORGIA
   COUNTY OF ________________
   __________________, being first duly sworn on oath, says the foregoing is a just and true statement of the amount owing by defendant to plaintiff, exclusive of all setoffs and just grounds of defense.
   ________________
   Plaintiff or agent
   Sworn and subscribed
   before me this ________ day
   of __________, ______.
   ________________
   Notary public
   or attesting
   official
   Notice
   TO: ________________
   Defendant
   ________________
   Home Address
   or
   ________________
   Business Address
   You are hereby notified that ____________ has made a claim and is requesting judgment against you in the sum of ______________ dollars ($ __________), as shown by the foregoing statement. The court will hold a hearing upon this claim at (address of court) at a time to be set after your answer is filed.
   YOU ARE REQUIRED TO FILE OR PRESENT AN ANSWER TO THIS CLAIM WITHIN 30 DAYS AFTER SERVICE OF THIS CLAIM UPON YOU. IF YOU DO NOT ANSWER, JUDGMENT BY DEFAULT WILL BE ENTERED AGAINST YOU. YOUR ANSWER MAY BE FILED IN WRITING OR MAY BE GIVEN ORALLY TO THE JUDGE.
   If you have witnesses, books, receipts, or other writings bearing on this claim, you should bring them with you at the time of hearing.
   If you wish to have witnesses summoned, see the court at once for assistance.
   If you have any claim against the plaintiff, you should notify the court at once.
   If you admit the claim, but desire additional time to pay, you must come to the hearing in person and state the circumstances to the court.
   You may come with or without an attorney.
   ________________
   Magistrate of
   __________ County</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
