<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-430/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_430">
        <num>21-2-430</num>
        <content>
          <p>In precincts in which ballots are used, the poll officers shall, after taking the oath, publicly open the ballot boxes which have been furnished to them and shall, prior to opening of the polls, totally destroy any ballots and other papers which they may find therein which are not intended for use in such primary or election. When the polling place is opened, the ballot box shall be securely locked and shall not be opened until the close of the polls, as provided in Code Section 21-2-436. At the opening of the polls, the seals of the packages furnished by the superintendent shall be publicly broken and such packages shall be opened by the chief manager. The cards of instruction shall be immediately posted in each voting compartment. One card of instruction, one notice of penalties, and one voting rights poster shall be immediately posted in or about the voting room outside the enclosed space; and such card of instruction, notice of penalties, and voting rights poster shall be given to any elector at his or her request so long as there are any on hand.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 34-1315, enacted by Ga. L. 1969, p. 308, § 15; Ga. L. 1983, p. 140, § 1; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 253, § 61/HB 244.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
