<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-384/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_384">
        <num>21-2-384</num>
        <content>
          <p>I, the undersigned, do swear (or affirm) under penalty of false swearing that I am a citizen of the United States and of the State of Georgia; that I possess the qualifications of an elector required by the laws of the State of Georgia; that I am entitled to vote in the precinct containing my residence in the primary or election in which this ballot is to be cast; that I am eligible to vote by absentee ballot; that I have not marked or mailed any other absentee ballot, nor will I mark or mail another absentee ballot for voting in such primary or election; nor shall I vote therein in person; and that I have read and understand the instructions accompanying this ballot; that I have carefully complied with such instructions in completing this ballot; that I have marked and sealed this ballot in private and have not allowed any unauthorized person to observe the voting of this ballot or how this ballot was voted except those authorized under state and federal law; and that I will not give or transfer this ballot to any person not authorized by law to deliver or return absentee ballots. I understand that the offer or acceptance of money or any other object of value to vote for any particular candidate, list of candidates, issue, or list of issues included in this election constitutes an act of voter fraud and is a felony under Georgia law.
   ______________________________________________________________________
   Signature or Mark of Elector
   ______________________________________________________________________
   Printed Name of Elector
   Oath of Person Assisting Elector (if any):
   I, the undersigned, do swear (or affirm) that I assisted the above-named elector in marking such elector's absentee ballot as such elector personally communicated such elector's preference to me; and that such elector is entitled to receive assistance in voting under provisions of subsection (a) of Code Section 21-2-409.
   This, the ____________ day of ________,
   ________.
   ______________________________________________________________________
   Signature of Person Assisting
   Elector
   ______________________________________________________________________
   Printed Name of Person
   Assisting Elector
   Reason for assistance (Check appropriate square):
   [] Elector is unable to read the English language.
   [] Elector requires assistance due to physical disability.</p>
          <p>In the case of absent uniformed services or overseas voters, if the presidential designee under Section 705(b) of the federal Help America Vote Act promulgates a standard oath for use by such voters, the Secretary of State shall be required to use such oath on absentee ballot materials for such voters and such oath shall be accepted in lieu of the oath set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</p>
          <p>Each board of registrars or absentee ballot clerk shall maintain for public inspection a master list, arranged by precincts, setting forth the name and residence of every elector to whom an official absentee ballot has been sent. Absentee electors whose names appear on the master list may be challenged by any elector prior to 5:00 P.M. on the day before absentee ballots are to begin being scanned and tabulated.</p>
          <p>Such special absentee run-off ballots for the general primary shall list the titles of all offices being contested at the general primary and the candidates qualifying for such general primary for each office and shall permit the elector to vote in the general primary runoff by indicating his or her order of preference for each candidate for each office. A separate ballot shall be prepared for each political party, but a qualified elector under this subsection shall be mailed only the ballot of the political party in whose primary such elector requests to vote. The Secretary of State shall prepare instructions for use with such special absentee run-off ballots, including instructions for voting by mail using an electronically transmitted ballot. Such ballot shall be returned by the elector in the same manner as other absentee ballots by such electors who are entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq.</p>
          <p>Such special absentee run-off ballots for the general election shall list the titles of all offices being contested at the general election and the candidates qualifying for such general election for each office and shall permit the elector to vote in the general election runoff by indicating his or her order of preference for each candidate for each office.</p>
          <p>To indicate order of preference for each candidate for each office to be voted on, an elector shall put the numeral "1" next to the name of the candidate who is the elector's first choice for such office, the numeral "2" for the elector's second choice, and so forth, in consecutive numerical order, such that a numeral indicating the elector's preference is written by the elector next to each candidate's name on the ballot. An elector shall not be required to indicate preference for more than one candidate for an office if the elector so chooses.</p>
          <p>A special absentee run-off ballot shall be enclosed with each general primary absentee ballot sent to an elector who is entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq., along with instructions on how to cast the special absentee run-off ballot and the two envelopes to be used in returning such ballot as provided in subsection (b) of this Code section, provided that the envelopes bear the notation of "Official Overseas/Military General Primary Run-off Ballot." An elector shall be sent only the ballot containing the candidates of the political party in whose primary such elector desires to vote.</p>
          <p>A special absentee run-off ballot shall be enclosed with each general election absentee ballot sent to an elector entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq., along with instructions on how to cast the special absentee run-off ballot and the two envelopes to be used in returning such ballot as provided in subsection (b) of this Code section, provided that the envelopes bear the notation of "Official Overseas/Military General Election Run-off Ballot." The State Election Board shall by rule or regulation establish procedures for the transmission of blank absentee ballots by mail and by electronic transmission for all electors who are entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq., as amended, and by which such electors may designate whether the elector prefers the transmission of such ballots by mail or electronically, for use in county, state, and federal primaries, elections, and runoffs in this state and, if the Secretary of State finds it to be feasible, for use in municipal primaries, elections, and runoffs. If no preference is stated, the ballot shall be transmitted by mail. The State Election Board shall by rule or regulation establish procedures to ensure to the extent practicable that the procedures for transmitting such ballots shall protect the security and integrity of such ballots and shall ensure that the privacy of the identity and other personal data of such electors who are entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq., as amended, to whom a blank absentee ballot is transmitted under this Code section is protected throughout the process of such transmission.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, §§ 34-1404, 34-1405, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1970, p. 347, § 27; Ga. L. 1974, p. 71, §§ 4, 5; Ga. L. 1977, p. 684, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 725, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 21; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1512, § 5; Ga. L. 1985, p. 206, § 1; Ga. L. 1985, p. 496, § 13; Ga. L. 1985, p. 632, § 4; Ga. L. 1986, p. 32, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 34, § 1; Ga. L. 1987, p. 417, § 5; Ga. L. 1989, p. 643, § 9; Ga. L. 1990, p. 143, § 4; Ga. L. 1992, p. 1, § 2; Ga. L. 1992, p. 1815, § 3; Ga. L. 1995, p. 1027, § 9; Ga. L. 1997, p. 649, § 6; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 21, § 1; Ga. L. 1999, p. 52, § 12; Ga. L. 2001, p. 230, § 14; Ga. L. 2003, p. 517, § 38; Ga. L. 2005, p. 253, § 53/HB 244; Ga. L. 2006, p. 888, § 3/HB 1435; Ga. L. 2007, p. 536, § 1/SB 40; Ga. L. 2008, p. 261, § 1/SB 456; Ga. L. 2010, p. 569, §§ 4, 5/HB 1073; Ga. L. 2011, p. 683, § 12/SB 82; Ga. L. 2011, p. 697, § 2/HB 92; Ga. L. 2012, p. 995, § 26/SB 92; Ga. L. 2017, p. 697, § 17/HB 268; Ga. L. 2019, p. 7, § 30/HB 316; Ga. L. 2021, p. 14, § 27/SB 202.)</p>
          <p>The 2017 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2017, in paragraph (c)(1), in the form, inserted ", for voting purposes," near the beginning, and substituted "Year of Elector's Birth" for "Month and Day of Elector's Birth" near the middle.</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective April 2, 2019, in subsection (b), inserted "addressed to the elector" near the middle of the first sentence, added the fourth sentence, inserted "provisional absentee ballot information, if necessary," in the middle of the fifth sentence; rewrote paragraph (c)(1); and in subsection (e), substituted "52 U.S.C. Section 20302" for "42 U.S.C. Section 1973ff" in the first and third sentences, and added ", for use in county, state, and federal primaries, elections, and runoffs in this state and, if the Secretary of State finds it to be feasible, for use in municipal primaries, elections, and runoffs" at the end of the first sentence.</p>
          <p>The 2021 amendment,
      effective July 1, 2021, rewrote paragraphs (a)(2) and (a)(4) and subsection (b); in paragraph (c)(1), in the first undesignated paragraph, inserted "under penalty of false swearing" near the beginning, deleted "and" following "accompanying this ballot;" and inserted the language beginning with "; that I have marked and sealed this ballot in private" at the end of the first sentence; substituted "the day before absentee ballots are to be scanned and tabulated" for "the day before the primary or election" at the end of subsection (d); and rewrote subsection (e).</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_2_384__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>(1)
   The oaths referred to in subsection (b) of this Code section shall be in substantially the following form:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_2_384__subsec_1">
          <num>(1)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The election superintendent shall prepare special absentee run-off ballots for general primaries and general elections for use by qualified electors who are entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 52 U.S.C. Section 20301, et seq.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
