<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-72/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_72">
        <num>21-2-72</num>
        <content>
          <p>Except when otherwise provided by law or court order, the primary and election records of each superintendent, registrar, municipal governing authority, and committee of a political party or body, including registration statements, nomination petitions, affidavits, certificates, tally papers, returns, accounts, contracts, reports, and other documents in official custody, except the contents of voting machines, shall be open to public inspection and may be inspected and copied by any elector of the county or municipality during usual business hours at any time when they are not necessarily being used by the custodian or his or her employees having duties to perform in reference thereto; provided, however, that such public inspection shall only be in the presence of the custodian or his or her employee and shall be subject to proper regulation for the safekeeping of such documents and subject to the further provisions of this chapter. The custodian shall also, upon request, if photocopying equipment is available in the building in which the records are housed, make and furnish to any member of the public copies of any of such records upon payment of the actual cost of copying the records requested.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 34-403, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1970, p. 347, § 6; Ga. L. 1982, p. 437, §§ 1, 2; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 253, § 7/HB 244.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
