<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-90/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_90">
        <num>21-2-90</num>
        <content>
          <p>All elections and primaries shall be conducted in each polling place by a board consisting of a chief manager, who shall be chairperson of such board, and two assistant managers assisted by clerks. The managers of each polling place shall be appointed by the superintendent. If the political parties involved elect to do so, they may submit to the superintendent, for consideration in making such appointment, a list of qualified persons. When such lists are submitted to the appropriate office, the superintendent, insofar as practicable, shall make appointments so that there shall be equal representation on such boards for the political parties involved in such elections or primaries. The superintendent shall make each appointment by entering an order which shall remain of record in the appropriate office and shall make such order available for public inspection upon request. The order shall include the name and address of the appointee, his or her title, and a designation of the precinct and primary or election in which he or she is to serve.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 34-501, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1969, p. 329, § 4; Ga. L. 1970, p. 347, § 9; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1512, § 5; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 253, § 9/HB 244; Ga. L. 2010, p. 914, § 2/HB 540; Ga. L. 2011, p. 683, § 2/SB 82; Ga. L. 2012, p. 995, § 4/SB 92.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
