<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_8">
        <num>21-2-8</num>
        <content>
          <p>No person shall be eligible for party nomination for or election to public office, nor shall he or she perform any official acts or duties as a superintendent, registrar, deputy registrar, poll officer, or party officer, as set forth in this chapter, in connection with any election or primary held under this chapter, if under the laws of this state, any other state, or the United States he or she has been convicted and sentenced, in any court of competent jurisdiction, for fraudulent violation of primary or election laws, malfeasance in office, or felony involving moral turpitude, unless such person's civil rights have been restored and at least ten years have elapsed from the date of the completion of the sentence without a subsequent conviction of another felony involving moral turpitude. Additionally, the person shall not be holding illegally any public funds. In the event of the disqualification of the superintendent as described in this Code section, the clerk of the superior court shall act in his or her stead. Notwithstanding the above, the governing authority of a municipality shall appoint an individual to serve as superintendent for municipal elections or municipal primaries in the event of the disqualification of the municipal superintendent, unless the municipality has contracted with a county government for the provision of election services, in which event the clerk of the superior court shall act in place of a disqualified superintendent.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 34-107, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1983, p. 930, § 2; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 2001, p. 240, § 1; Ga. L. 2005, p. 253, § 3/HB 244.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
