<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/21-2-262/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_2_262">
        <num>21-2-262</num>
        <content>
          <p>(a.1)Upon the petition of 20 electors or of the county executive committee of a political party to the superintendent of the county, praying for the division or redivision of a precinct into two or more precincts, or for the alteration of the bounds of any precinct, or for the formation of one or more precincts out of two or more existing precincts or parts thereof, or for the consolidation of adjoining precincts, the superintendent shall refer such petition to the board of registrars, which shall make a full investigation of the facts and shall promptly report to the superintendent its findings and recommendations as to the division, redivision, alteration, formation, or consolidation of the precincts prayed for. If the board of registrars shall find that a division, redivision, alteration, formation, or consolidation of precincts will promote the convenience of the electors and the public interests, it shall recommend a proper division, redivision, alteration, formation, or consolidation of precincts which conforms to the requirements of subsection (a) of Code Section 21-2-261.1 and shall accompany its report with a map, plat, or draft of the new election precinct or precincts proposed by it. Such petitions may specify the boundaries desired by the petitioners and may be accompanied by a map setting forth such boundaries.</p>
          <p>(Code 1933, § 34-703, enacted by Ga. L. 1964, Ex. Sess., p. 26, § 1; Ga. L. 1977, p. 1199, § 1; Ga. L. 1982, p. 3, § 21; Ga. L. 1982, p. 1512, § 2; Ga. L. 1987, p. 34, § 1; Ga. L. 1992, p. 56, § 1; Ga. L. 1994, p. 1406, § 20; Ga. L. 1996, p. 145, § 13; Ga. L. 1998, p. 295, § 1; Ga. L. 2019, p. 7, § 13/HB 316.)</p>
          <p>The 2019 amendment,
      effective April 2, 2019, in subsection (c), substituted "30 days" for "ten days" near the end of the first sentence and added the second sentence.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
