<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-75/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_82_75">
        <num>36-82-75</num>
        <content>
          <p>Within 20 days from the date of service of the notice provided for in Code Section 36-82-74, the district attorney or the Attorney General shall prepare and file, in the office of the clerk of the superior court of the county issuing the bonds or of the county in which the governmental body is located, a petition directed to the superior court of such county in the name of the state and against the governmental body desiring to issue the revenue bonds. The petition shall set forth service of the notice, the name of the governmental body seeking to issue the bonds, the amount of bonds to be issued, for what purpose the bonds are to be issued, what interest they are to bear, how much principal and interest is to be paid annually, when the bonds are to be paid in full, and the security to be pledged to the payment of the bonds; provided, however, the petition may provide for a maximum interest rate and a maximum annual principal and interest payment. The district attorney or the Attorney General shall obtain from the judge of the court an order requiring the governmental body by its proper officers to show cause, at such time and place, either in term or chambers, within 20 days from the filing of the petition, as the judge may direct, why the bonds and the security for the payment thereof should not be confirmed and validated. The petition and order shall be served in the manner now provided by law for the service of petitions upon counties, governmental bodies, or political subdivisions. The officers of the governmental body shall make sworn answers to the petition within the time prescribed.</p>
          <p>(Ga. L. 1937, p. 761, ยง 11; Ga. L. 1991, p. 1103, ยง 1.)</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
