<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ga-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ga"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ga/act/ocga/36-82-196/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ga-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ga/legislature" showAs="Georgia General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_82_196">
        <num>36-82-196</num>
        <content>
          <p>When the department is required to apply the policy guidelines it may consider such factors, known as evaluation factors, in deciding which applications should receive a notice of allocation. The evaluation factors to be considered shall include, but are not limited to, the number of permanent jobs created or retained; the commitment of the borrower to hire individuals eligible for training under the Job Training Partnership Act or its successor program; the unemployment rate of the territorial area of the issuer compared to the state as a whole; the ratio of private investment to bond financing; evidence of HoDAG or UDAG approval; the amount of benefit to low-income to moderate-income individuals; the cost per qualified residential rental unit; the housing vacancy rate of the territory of the issuer compared to the state as a whole, as determined by the department; and the degree to which the combination of income and price limits serve to target the single-family housing bonds to low-income to moderate-income households.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
